<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-2538</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Greater U Street Performance Parking Zone.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Greater U Street Performance Parking Zone ("zone") is designated as the area bounded by: S Street, NW, from the intersection of Florida Avenue, NW and 4th Street, NW, to 14th Street, NW; 14th Street, NW, from S Street, NW, to U Street, NW; U Street, NW, from 14th Street, NW, to 17th Street, NW; 17th Street, NW, from U Street, NW, to Florida Avenue, NW; Florida Avenue, NW, from 17th Street, NW, to W Street, NW; W Street, NW, from the intersection of Florida Avenue, NW and 16th Street, NW, to the intersection of Florida Avenue, NW and 15th Street, NW; Florida Avenue, NW, from 15th Street, NW, to Barry Place, NW; Barry Place, NW, from Florida Avenue, NW, to Georgia Avenue, NW; Georgia Avenue, NW, from Barry Place, NW, to Florida Avenue, NW; Florida Avenue, NW, from Georgia Avenue, NW, to S Street, NW.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The zone includes both sides of all boundary streets.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Mayor may alter the boundaries of the zone; provided, that the Council and the affected Advisory Neighborhood Commissions ("ANC") are provided with 30 days' written notice, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays, of the Mayor's intent to do so, and any ANC recommendation, if provided, is given great weight pursuant to <cite path="§1-309.10">§ 1-309.10</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Pursuant to <cite path="§50-2531">§ 50-2531</cite>, the Mayor shall adjust fees to manage curbside availability, dissuade repeat parking violations, and manage congestion during peak nightlife hours.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may establish metered or pay-by-phone parking for residential parking permit spaces within the zone.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Within the first 30 days of the implementation of the zone, the Mayor may issue warning citations for curbside parking violations related to the program in the zone.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-279" type="History" path="§8a">Nov. 25, 2008, D.C. Law 17-279, § 8a</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-09-06" doc="D.C. Law 25-50" eff="2023-09-06" path="§6112|(b)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-506" path="§8002|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2024-07-15" eff="2024-07-15">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-506" path="§8002|(a)">§ 8002(a) of Fiscal Year 2025 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-506, July 15, 2024, 71 DCR 8406)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-07-15" doc="D.C. Act 25-506" eff="2024-07-15" path="§8002|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Law 25-217" eff="2024-09-18" path="§8002|(a)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Law 25-217" eff="2024-09-18" path="§8002|(a)|(2)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
