<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-921.88</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Bus Service Enhancement Fund established.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Bus Service Enhancement Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by DDOT in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Provided that the Chief Financial Officer certifies that sufficient revenue exists pursuant to <cite path="§50-921.89">§ 50-921.89</cite>, there shall be deposited into the Fund general retail sales tax revenue collected pursuant to <cite path="47|20">Chapter 20 of Title 47</cite> as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In Fiscal Year 2023, $2.5 million; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For each succeeding fiscal year after Fiscal Year 2023, $10 million.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Money in the Fund shall be used to improve transit access or service in areas identified in DDOT's Multimodal Long-Range Transportation Plan as areas of high transportation need or historically underserved communities or to serve residents of those areas as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Making payments to WMATA to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Create new bus routes not in operation before July 1, 2023; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Extend service hours, shorten headways, or make other service improvements for an existing bus route;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Used by DDOT to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Operate new DC Circulator or DC Streetcar routes not in operation before July 1, 2023;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Extend service hours, shorten headways, or make other service improvements for an existing DC Circulator or DC Streetcar line; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Install, lease, maintain, or operate infrastructure that DDOT determines will increase ridership or improve transit service, including dedicated transit lanes, signal priority, bus shelters, payment kiosks, or other amenities; or</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Funding studies to support increased ridership or improved transit service.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the Fund but not expended in a fiscal year shall not revert to the unassigned fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-137" type="History" path="§11aa">May 21, 2002, D.C. Law 14-137, § 11aa</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-137" type="History" path="§11aa" display="false">May 21, 2002, D.C. Law 14-137, § 11aa</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-699" path="§2|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2023-03-22" eff="2022-12-08">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-699" path="§2|(b)|includes|11aa">§ 11aa of Fare-Free Bus Funding Emergency Amendment Act of 2022 (D.C. Act 24-699, Dec. 8, 2022, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-03-22" doc="D.C. Act 24-699" eff="2022-12-08" path="§2|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-35" path="§2|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2023-03-22" eff="2023-02-27">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-35" path="§2|(b)|includes|11aa">§ 11aa of Fare-Free Bus Funding Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2023 (D.C. Act 25-35, Feb. 27, 2023, 70 DCR 2976)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-03-22" doc="D.C. Act 25-35" eff="2023-02-27" path="§2|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-22" doc="D.C. Law 24-335" eff="2023-03-22" path="§2|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-22" doc="D.C. Law 24-335" eff="2023-03-22" path="§2|(b)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 24-340" path="§2|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2023-03-22" eff="2023-03-22">For temporary (225 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-340" path="§2|(b)|includes|11aa">§ 11aa of Fare-Free Bus Funding Temporary Amendment Act of 2022 (D.C. Law 24-340, Mar. 22, 2023, 70 DCR 1578)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-03-22" doc="D.C. Law 24-340" eff="2023-03-22" path="§2|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
