<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>21-2061</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Death, resignation, or removal of conservator.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The court may, upon notice and hearing, remove a conservator for abuse, neglect, or financial exploitation of an individual for whom the conservator has been appointed or for any other good cause.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The court may accept the resignation of a conservator.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Upon the conservator's death, resignation, or removal, the court may appoint another conservator, who shall succeed to the title and powers of the previous conservator.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A conservator removed for abuse, neglect, or financial exploitation of an individual for whom the conservator has been appointed shall not be subsequently appointed as a conservator for another person for a minimum of 5 years after last removal and until satisfactorily proving their rehabilitation and fitness as determined by the court.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>In the event that a removed conservator holds a professional license, the court may report the misconduct to the appropriate licensing authority.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-204" type="History">Feb. 28, 1987, D.C. Law 6-204, § 2(a), 34 DCR 632</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based upon <cite path="§2-314" proof="true">§ 2-314</cite> of the Uniform Guardianship and Protective Proceedings Act (1982 Act).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 21-2061.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-296" eff="2023-03-10" path="§3|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
