<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>ยง</prefix>
  <num>21-2601.16</num>
  <heading>Judicial relief.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The following persons may petition a court to construe a power of attorney or review the agent's conduct, and grant appropriate relief:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The principal or the agent;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A guardian, conservator, or other fiduciary acting for the principal;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A person authorized to make health care decisions for the principal;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The principal's spouse, parent, or descendant;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>An individual who would qualify as a presumptive heir of the principal;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A person named as a beneficiary to receive any property, benefit, or contractual right on the principal's death or as a beneficiary of a trust created by or for the principal that has a financial interest in the principal's estate;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>A governmental agency having regulatory authority to protect the welfare of the principal;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The principal's caregiver or another person that demonstrates sufficient interest in the principal's welfare; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>A person asked to accept the power of attorney.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Upon motion by the principal, the court shall dismiss a petition filed under this section, unless the court finds that the principal lacks capacity to revoke the agent's authority or the power of attorney.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-236" eff="2023-02-23" path="ยง2|(d)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-236" eff="2023-02-23" path="ยง2|(d)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
