<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>21-2602.15</num>
  <heading>Retirement plans.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "retirement plan" means a plan or account created by an employer, the principal, or another individual to provide retirement benefits or deferred compensation of which the principal is a participant, beneficiary, or owner, including the following plans or accounts:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An individual retirement account under 26 U.S.C. § 408;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A Roth individual retirement account under 26 U.S.C. § 408A;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A deemed individual retirement account under 26 U.S.C. § 408(q);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>An annuity or mutual fund custodial account under 26 U.S.C. § 403(b);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A pension, profit-sharing, stock bonus, or other retirement plan qualified under 26 U.S.C. [§] 401(a);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A plan under 26 U.S.C. § 457(b); and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>A nonqualified deferred compensation plan under 26 U.S.C. § 409A.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Unless the power of attorney otherwise provides, language in a power of attorney granting general authority with respect to retirement plans authorizes the agent to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Select the form and timing of payments under a retirement plan and withdraw benefits from a plan;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Make a rollover, including a direct trustee-to-trustee rollover, of benefits from one retirement plan to another;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Establish a retirement plan in the principal's name;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Make contributions to a retirement plan;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Exercise investment powers available under a retirement plan; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Borrow from, sell assets to, or purchase assets from a retirement plan.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-236" eff="2023-02-23" path="§2|(d)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-236" eff="2023-02-23" path="§2|(d)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
