<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>3-1205.08a</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Temporary license, registration, or certification.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A board may, in situations established by the Mayor through rulemaking, issue a temporary license, registration, or certification for a health care profession to an applicant if the applicant is licensed, registered, or certified and in good standing in another jurisdiction to practice the same profession.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A temporary license, registration, or certification issued pursuant to this section shall be valid for a fixed period of time established by the issuing board, subject to any limits as may be established by the Mayor by rule.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "in good standing" means that the applicant has an active license and is not subject to any current public or private discipline, including probation, suspension, revocation, or any other public or private practice restriction.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>An applicant who previously held a license, registration or certification in the District that was revoked or suspended shall be not eligible for a temporary license, registration, or certification under this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-99" type="History" path="§508a">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, § 508a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-26" type="History">as added July 18, 2009, D.C. Law 18-26, § 2(e)(9), 56 DCR 4043</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2(e)(9) of Health Occupations Revision General Amendment Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-146, July 28, 2009,  56 DCR 6308).</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-191" eff="2024-07-19" path="§101|(aa)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-191" eff="2024-07-19" path="§101|(hh)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
