<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>3-1205.11a</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Emeritus status.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may issue rules permitting emeritus status for a licensee, registrant, or certificate holder who meets the following requirements:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The person has at least 10 years of relevant licensed, registered, or certified practice in the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The person provides a declaration of retirement from active practice in all jurisdictions in which the person is licensed, registered, or certified;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The person is not the subject of disciplinary action in any jurisdiction; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The person has had no prior revocation or suspension of their license, registration, or certification in any jurisdiction.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An individual holding emeritus status permits the holder to refer to themself by the title of their license, registration, or certification but may not:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Engage in active practice of that health profession in the District or any other jurisdiction; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Either explicitly or implicitly hold themself out to others as a person permitted to engage in active practice of that health profession.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The board may cancel an emeritus license, registration, or certificate for failure to meet the requirements of subsections (a) or (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The board may take disciplinary action against an emeritus status holder for violations of  <cite path="§3-1205.01">§ 3-1205.01</cite> or <cite path="§3-1205.14">§ 3-1205.14</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>An emeritus status holder may apply to change to active license, registration, or certification status within 5 years after the date emeritus status was granted by:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Paying the fee established by the Mayor;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Complying with the continuing education requirements in effect when the emeritus holder seeks to return to active license, registration, or certification status;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Complying with any other current requirements for the reactivation of a license, registration, or certification; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Establishing to the board's satisfaction that they possess the current competency to practice their health profession.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>An emeritus status holder may not return to active license, registration, or certification status more than 5 years after the grant of the emeritus status except by submitting an application for a new license, registration, or certification and establishing to the satisfaction of the board that they qualify for the license, registration, or certification and possess current competency to practice that profession.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-99" type="History" path="§511a">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, § 511a</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-191" eff="2024-07-19" path="§101|(aa)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-191" eff="2024-07-19" path="§101|(mm)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
