<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>3-1207.10</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Qualifications for licensure.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Board of Professional Counseling shall license as a professional counselor a person who, in addition to meeting the requirements of <cite path="3|12|V">subchapter V of this chapter</cite> and any requirements the Mayor may establish by rule, has satisfactorily passed the national examination adopted by the Board, possesses a master's degree in counseling or a related subject from an accredited college or university consisting of at least 60 hours of postgraduate education, and has completed 2 years of supervised counseling experience.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Board of Professional Counseling shall license as a graduate professional counselor a person who, in addition to meeting the requirements of <cite path="3|12|V">subchapter V of this chapter</cite> and any requirements the Mayor may establish by rule, has satisfactorily completed the national examination adopted by the Board and possesses a master's degree in counseling or a related subject from an accredited college or university, consisting of at least 48 hours of graduate education.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Board of Professional Counseling may license, by endorsement, a professional counselor who, in addition to meeting the requirements of <cite path="3|12|V">subchapter V of this chapter</cite> and any requirements the Mayor may establish by rule, is currently licensed in another state in good standing and has:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Engaged in independent professional counseling practice providing clinical counseling for at least 5 years pursuant to such license; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Held an independent professional counseling license for at least 3 years and possesses the National Certified Counseling credential issued by the National Board of Certified Counselors.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-99" type="History" path="§710">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, § 710</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-126" type="History">as added July 22, 1992, D.C. Law 9-126, § 2(g), 39 DCR 3824</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-13" type="History">July 7, 2009, D.C. Law 18-13, § 2(d), 56 DCR 3608</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-13">D.C. Law 18-13</cite> designated subsec. (a); and added subsecs. (b) and (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 2-3307.10.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-191" eff="2024-07-19" path="§101|(eee)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
