<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>3-1209.05</num>
  <heading>Dental assistant.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Dental assistant” means a person who is registered by the Board of Dentistry and is authorized to assist a licensed dentist or a licensed dental hygienist in the performance of duties related to oral care under the supervision of a dentist.</text>
    </para>
    <para placeholder="Repealed">
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A person who is engaged as a dental assistant to assist a dentist in the performance of dental procedures, or to assist a dental hygienist in the performance of dental hygiene procedures, in any area of or specialty area of dentistry, including oral and maxillofacial surgery, or who performs the duties of a dental assistant in any area of or specialty area of dentistry, including oral and maxillofacial surgery, in the District shall be registered with the Board, renew the registration as required by rule, and pay the required registration fee established by the Board.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A dental assistant shall wear a name tag bearing the title “dental assistant” while acting in a professional capacity and display his or her current registration in a conspicuous place in the dental office in which he or she is employed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A person shall not engage in the practice of dental assisting or use the title of dental assistant unless he or she is registered to practice as a dental assistant under this chapter and practices under the supervision of a dentist licensed under this chapter. Unless authorized by the Board to perform duties related to oral care in the District, an individual shall not be permitted to perform any clinical duties or engage in any physical patient contact.</text>
  </para>
  <para placeholder="Repealed">
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>A dentist may delegate duties to a dental assistant that are appropriate to the training and experience of the dental assistant and within the scope of practice of the supervising dentist; provided, that the dentist shall not delegate to a dental assistant any task or function identified, through rulemaking, as a task or function that shall not be delegated.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall issue rules necessary to implement the provisions of this section, including the standards of education and experience required to qualify as a registered dental assistant , the duties that may be performed by a dental assistant, and the required level of supervision.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall create a Level III dental assistant designation to authorize dental assistants with appropriate training and experience, as determined by the Board, to conduct the application pit and fissure sealants, coronal polishing to remove stain and biofilm, and glucose testing, as well as all functions authorized by this section and any other services authorized by rule.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-99" type="History" path="§905">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, § 905</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-15" type="History">as added July 7, 2009, D.C. Law 18-15, § 2(e), 56 DCR 3616</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-191" eff="2024-07-19" path="§101|(sss)|(1)|(A)|(i)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-191" eff="2024-07-19" path="§101|(sss)|(1)|(A)|(ii)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-191" eff="2024-07-19" path="§101|(sss)|(1)|(B)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-191" eff="2024-07-19" path="§101|(sss)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-191" eff="2024-07-19" path="§101|(sss)|(3)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-191" eff="2024-07-19" path="§101|(sss)|(3)|(B)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-191" eff="2024-07-19" path="§101|(sss)|(4)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-191" eff="2024-07-19" path="§101|(sss)|(5)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-191" eff="2024-07-19" path="§101|(sss)|(6)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
