<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>3-1202.13</num>
  <heading>Board of Professional Counseling.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a Board of Professional Counseling to consist of 5 members appointed by the Mayor; except, that from July 19, 2024, the Board shall consist of 7 members appointed by the Mayor with the advice and consent of the Council.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Board shall regulate the practices of professional counseling, professional art therapy, addiction counseling, dance therapy, and marriage and family therapy.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Members of the Board shall serve a 3-year term. Of the members first appointed to the Board, one member shall be appointed to a one-year term, 2 members shall be appointed to a 2-year term, and 2 members shall be appointed to a 3-year term.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Of the members of the Board, 2 shall be professional counselors licensed in the District, one shall be an educator engaged in teaching counseling, one shall be a professional art therapist, one shall be a consumer member, and one shall have at least 5 years of experience in the field of addiction counseling; except, that from July 19, 2024, of the members of the Board:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Three shall be professional counselors licensed in the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>One shall be a professional art therapist licensed in the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>One shall be a marriage and family therapist licensed in the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>One shall be a professional counselor, a professional art therapist, a marriage and family therapist, or an addiction counselor licensed or certified in the District; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>One shall be a consumer member; provided further, that of the members who are licensed professional counselors, one shall be an educator engaged in teaching counseling and one shall have at least 3 years of experience in the field of addiction counseling.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-99" type="History" path="§213">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, § 213</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-126" type="History">as added July 22, 1992, D.C. Law 9-126, § 2(d), 39 DCR 3824</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-13" type="History">July 7, 2009, D.C. Law 18-13, § 2(c), 56 DCR 3608</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-13">D.C. Law 18-13</cite> rewrote subsec. (b); and, in subsec. (d), substituted “one shall be a consumer member, and one shall have at least 5 years of experience in the field of addiction counseling” for “and 1 shall be a consumer member”. Prior to amendment, subsec. (b) read as follows: “(b) The Board shall regulate the practice of professional counseling.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 2-3302.13.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§1-523.01">§ 1-523.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-06-24" doc="D.C. Law 23-115" eff="2020-06-24" path="§2|(c)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-06-24" doc="D.C. Law 23-115" eff="2020-06-24" path="§2|(c)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-06-24" doc="D.C. Law 23-115" eff="2020-06-24" path="§2|(c)|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 23-115" path="§2|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2020-06-24" eff="2020-06-24">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-115" path="">D.C. Law 23-115</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-115" path="§3">§ 3 of D.C. Law 23-115</cite> provided that the change made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-115" path="§2|(c)">§ 2(c) of D.C. Law 23-115</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-06-24" doc="D.C. Law 23-115" eff="2020-06-24" path="§2|(c)" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-149" path="§7081" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2020-12-03" eff="2020-12-03"><cite doc="D.C. Law 23-149" path="§7081">Section 7081 of D.C. Law 23-149</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-115" path="§3">section 3 of D.C. Law 23-115</cite> removing the applicability provision impacting this section.  Therefore, the amendment of this section by Law 23-115 has been implemented.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-12-03" doc="D.C. Law 23-149" eff="2020-12-03" path="§7081" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-191" eff="2024-07-19" path="§101|(o)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-191" eff="2024-07-19" path="§101|(o)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-191" eff="2024-07-19" path="§101|(o)|(3)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
