<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>3-1208.04a</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Exceptions for non-clinical practice.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Nothing in <cite path="3|12">this chapter</cite> shall be construed as preventing or restricting an individual who has successfully completed a bachelor's degree in social work, a master's degree in social work, or a doctorate degree in social work through a program accredited by the Council on Social Work Education from engaging in non-clinical practice; provided, that no such persons shall represent by title or description of services that they are social workers.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "non-clinical practice" means competencies and activities commonly included in a social work education program that do not involve clinical assessment, diagnosis, or treatment of mental health conditions, including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Non-clinical case management, including coordinating social services, conducting non-clinical assessments of service needs, and facilitating client access to resources;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Community organization, including public education campaigns, information dissemination, and connecting individuals with social services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Advocacy, including advocating for clients and communities, advocating for policy changes, and representing clients' policy interests; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Administrative tasks, including handling client documentation, record-keeping, and program coordination.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-99" type="History" path="ยง804a">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, ยง 804a</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-191" eff="2024-07-19" path="ยง101|(iii)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
