<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>3-1208.81</num>
  <heading proof="needed">License and registration requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No person may practice psychology in the District without one of the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A health services psychology license, which is required for the practice of psychology as defined in <cite path="§3-1201.02|(16)|(A)">§ 3-1201.02(16)(A)</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A general applied psychology license, which is required for the practice of psychology within the scope of <cite path="§3-1201.02|(16)|(A)|(ii)">§ 3-1201.02(16)(A)(ii)</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A school psychology registration, which is required for the practice of psychology within the scope of <cite path="§3-1201.02|(16)|(A)|(iii)">§ 3-1201.02(16)(A)(iii)</cite>; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A psychology associate registration, which is required for the practice of psychology within the scope of [<cite path="§3-1201.02|(16)|(B)|(iv)">§ 3-1201.02(16)(B)(iv)</cite>].</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All active psychology licenses issued before July 19, 2024, shall, upon renewal, be issued as health services psychology licenses.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, for 2 years after July 19, 2024, or such longer period of time which may be established by the Mayor through rulemaking, a person who has been practicing general applied psychology or school psychology before July 19, 2024, may continue to practice without the licensure or registration required pursuant to <cite path="§3-1205.01|(a)|(1)">§ 3-1205.01(a)(1)</cite> or <cite path="§3-1205.01|(a)|(2)">(2)</cite>; provided, that the person applies for the relevant license or registration within 2 years after July 19, 2024.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-99" type="History" path="§881">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, § 881</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-191" eff="2024-07-19" path="§101|(ppp)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-191" eff="2024-07-19" path="§101|(ppp)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
