<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>3-1208.82</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Qualifications.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In addition to the general qualifications for licensure set forth in <cite path="3|12|V">subchapter V of this chapter</cite>, and any requirements the Mayor may establish by rule, an individual applying for a license to practice health services psychology or general applied psychology shall establish to the satisfaction of the Board of Psychology that the individual has:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Earned a doctoral degree in psychology from an accredited college or university; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Completed at least 2 years of experience in such areas of practice as shall be required by the Mayor through rulemaking, at least one year of which shall be postdoctoral experience.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An individual applying for a registration to practice school psychology shall meet such education and training requirements as may be established by the Mayor through rulemaking.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An individual applying for registration as a psychology associate shall have graduated from an accredited college or university with at least a master's degree based on a program of studies focusing on psychology, or a program judged by the Board to be substantially equivalent in subject matter and extent of training to a master's or doctoral degree in psychology.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b) of this section, individuals currently practicing as general applied psychologists or school psychologists who do not meet the qualifications of this section shall be eligible for licensure or registration if they apply for a license or registration within 24 months after July 19, 2024.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-99" type="History" path="ยง888">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, ยง 882</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-191" eff="2024-07-19" path="ยง101|(ppp)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-191" eff="2024-07-19" path="ยง101|(ppp)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
