<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>3-1206.07b</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Certified clinical nurse specialist.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In addition to the functions authorized under <cite path="§3-1206.04">§ 3-1206.04</cite>, a certified clinical nurse specialist may provide the services described in subsection (b) of this section related to specific specialties, including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Populations, such as pediatrics, geriatrics, or women's health;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Settings, such as critical care or the emergency room;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Diseases or medical subspecialties, such as diabetes or oncology;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Types of care, such as psychiatric or rehabilitation; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Types of problem, such as pain, wounds, and stress.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A clinical nurse specialist may provide diagnosis, treatment, and ongoing management of patients or clients, through:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Providing for the continuous improvement of patient or client outcomes and nursing care;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Practicing within the core competencies and behaviors specified by the National Association of Clinical Nurse Specialists or other national certifying body recognized by the Board;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Creating therapeutic environments through mentoring and system changes;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Practicing with individual clients, families, groups, and populations of clients; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Any other functions and roles prescribed by rules.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-99" type="History" path="§607b">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, § 607b</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-191" eff="2024-07-19" path="§101|(aaa)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
