<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>3-1206.09</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Qualifications, certification.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In addition to the general qualifications for licensure set forth in <cite path="3|12|V">subchapter V of this chapter</cite>, and any requirements the Mayor may establish by rule, a certified registered nurse anesthetist shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be a registered nurse holding a current, valid license pursuant to <cite path="3|12">this chapter</cite> and be in good standing with no action pending or in effect against their license;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Possess at least a master's degree from a program accredited by the Council on Accreditation of Nurse Anesthesia Educational Programs; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Successfully complete the National Certification Examination administered by the National Board of Certification and Recertification for Nurse-Anesthetists ("NBCRNA") and hold current NBCRNA certification.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In addition to the general qualifications for licensure set forth in <cite path="3|12|V">subchapter V of this chapter</cite>, and any requirements the Mayor may establish by rule, a certified nurse-midwife shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be a registered nurse holding a current, valid license pursuant to <cite path="3|12">this chapter</cite> and be in good standing with no action pending or in effect against their license;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Possess at least a master's degree from a program accredited by the Accreditation Commission for Midwifery Education; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Successfully complete the certification examination administered by the American Midwifery Certification Board ("AMBC") and hold current AMBC certification as a certified nurse-midwife.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In addition to the general qualifications for licensure set forth in <cite path="3|12|V">subchapter V of this chapter</cite>, and any requirements the Mayor may establish by rule, a certified nurse practitioner shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be a registered nurse holding a current, valid license pursuant to <cite path="3|12">this chapter</cite> and be in good standing with no action pending or in effect against his or her license;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Possess at least a Master of Science in Nursing from a program accredited by a national nursing organization recognized by the Board of Nursing; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Successfully complete a national certification examination administered by a national nurse practitioner certifying organization recognized by the Board of Nursing and hold a current certification in the relevant population focus.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>In addition to the general qualifications for licensure set forth in <cite path="3|12|V">subchapter V of this chapter</cite>, and any requirements the Mayor may establish by rule, a clinical nurse specialist shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be a registered nurse holding a current, valid license pursuant to <cite path="3|12">this chapter</cite> and be in good standing with no action pending or in effect against his or her license;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Possess at least a Master of Science in Nursing from a program accredited by a national nursing organization recognized by the Board of Nursing; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Successfully complete a national certification examination administered by a national nurse practitioner certifying organization recognized by the Board of Nursing and hold current certification in the relevant population focus.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-99" type="History" path="ยง608a">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, ยง 608a [609]</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-191" eff="2024-07-19" path="ยง101|(bbb)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
