<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>3-703</num>
  <heading>Powers of the Commission.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall conduct studies, review progress, develop, recommend and undertake action and initiate and conduct programs in areas including, but not limited to, the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Elimination of discrimination based on sex and elimination of gender stereotyping and bias;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Public and private employment practices, including matters pertaining to hours, wages and working conditions;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Education;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Equality of rights and responsibilities of men and women under the law; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>New and expanded services for women to facilitate their optimal functioning as homemakers, wage earners, and citizens, including mental and physical health care, and the improvement of facilities for child care and youth development.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-1)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Each District agency shall conduct a gender analysis, pursuant to guidelines developed by the Commission, and provide a report including the results of the analysis to the Mayor, the Council, and the Commission, not later than 6 months after October 1, 2023, and every 2 years thereafter, that shall include:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Data on gender disparities, including data on salaries, job titles, and promotional timelines, disaggregated by sex, race, ethnicity, age, familial status, marital status, sexual orientation, gender identity, immigration status, and disability; provided, that data shall be collected, stored, aggregated, and presented in a way that protects any PII from disclosure;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>An evaluation of gender equity in the agency's operations including its budget allocations, delivery of direct and indirect services, staff salaries and benefits, and employment practices; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>A review of the agency's efforts to integrate the human rights principles identified in the CEDAW into its policies and practices.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Commission shall review each agency's gender analysis and provide recommendations to the Mayor and the Council for corrective action where efforts to attain gender equity are found to be lacking by the Commission not later than 3 months after receipt of each agency's gender analysis pursuant to subparagraph (A) of this paragraph and shall publish its recommendations online.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Each District agency shall designate a liaison to the Commission to coordinate the completion of the gender analysis to receive training, and the Commission shall publicly post a list of current liaisons online not later than 3 months after October 1, 2023, and annually thereafter.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The Commission shall provide guidelines to the liaisons designated pursuant to subparagraph (C) of this paragraph on how to conduct gender analyses and provide technical assistance throughout the gender analysis process.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Commission shall develop and publish online a citywide action plan to address and correct any deficiencies identified in the gender analyses conducted pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection and integrate the CEDAW principles of equality of rights and respect for human dignity to further local implementation not later than one year after October 1, 2023, and every 5 years thereafter. The Commission shall submit each citywide action plan to the Mayor and the Council.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Commission shall make training available to all District government employees not later than 4 months after October 1, 2023, and annually thereafter. District government employees shall complete training at least once during employment, in the following areas:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The principles of equality of rights and respect for human dignity as described in CEDAW;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Gender bias and stereotyping and how they can lead to inequities in the workplace;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The right to promotion, job security, and all benefits and conditions of employment, regardless of gender identity or expression or familial status;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Content regarding violence against women and girls, where appropriate, with a perspective sensitive to gender diversity;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>The intersectionality of gender and race to create unique dynamics and effects;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Opportunities for participants to practice the gender-inclusive skills that will be expected of them; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>How to report incidents of discrimination.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Commission is authorized to apply for and receive grants to fund its program activities in accordance with procedures relating to grants management.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Commission may accept private gifts and donations to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall stimulate and encourage study and review of the status of women and may act as a clearinghouse for activities in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-109" type="History" path="§4">Sept. 22, 1978, D.C. Law 2-109, § 4, 25 DCR 1456</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 2-2603.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 2-803.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-303" eff="2023-03-10" path="§2|(b)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-303" eff="2023-03-10" path="§2|(b)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 24-303" path="§2|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2023-03-10" eff="2023-03-10">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-303" path="">D.C. Law 24-303</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-303" path="§4">§ 4 of D.C. Law 24-303</cite> provided that the change made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-303" path="§2|(b)">§ 2(b) of D.C. Law 24-303</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-303" eff="2023-03-10" path="§2|(b)" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-50" path="§7089" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2023-09-06" eff="2023-09-06"><cite doc="D.C.Law 25-50" path="§7089">Section 7089 of D.C. Law 25-50</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-303" path="§3">section 3 of D.C. Law 24-303</cite> removing the applicability provision impacting this section.  Therefore the amendment of this section by section 2(b) of Law 24-303 has been implemented.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-09-06" doc="D.C. Law 25-50" eff="2023-09-06" path="§7089" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
