<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-1631.06</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Required disclosures.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A college athlete shall provide or disclose to the individual or office designated under subsection (b) of this section:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A copy of a name, image, or likeness agreement that provides name, image, or likeness compensation to the athlete or the athlete's designee in an amount of more than $300 or, if a record of the agreement does not exist, the amount of name, image, or likeness compensation provided or to be provided, if the amount is more than $300;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The amount of name, image, or likeness compensation provided to the athlete or the athlete's designee if the aggregate amount is more than $2,000 in a calendar year and a copy of each name, image, or likeness agreement under which the compensation was received, if a record of the agreement exists;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>For each agreement or amount that must be provided:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The arrangement for providing compensation;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The amount of compensation;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The identity of and a description of the relationship with the third party;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The activity required or authorized; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>If the athlete is represented by a name, image, or likeness agent, the name of and a description of the agreement with the agent;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A copy of each agreement entered into by the athlete with a name, image, or likeness agent; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Other information required by the Department.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An institution shall designate an individual or office to receive the information required by subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A college athlete shall provide:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The information required by subsection (a) of this section before the earlier of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Receiving name, image, or likeness compensation required to be disclosed pursuant to this section; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Engaging in a name, image, or likeness activity required to be disclosed pursuant to this section; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An update after a change in any of the information required by subsection (a) of this section, not later than 10 days after the earlier of the change or the next scheduled athletic event in which the college athlete may participate.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If an institution, conference, or athletic association voluntarily, or as required by <cite path="38|16A">this chapter</cite>, adopts a limitation affecting a college athlete's ability to engage in name, image, or likeness activity, the institution shall provide, in a record, a copy of the limitation on its website that is accessible by the public and electronically searchable and to each college athlete the institution expects to participate in an intercollegiate sport:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>At or before the time an offer of admission or financial aid is made, whichever is earlier; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the limitation is adopted after the college athlete is a student at the institution, as soon as practicable after adoption.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A name, image, or likeness agreement must contain a statement that the agreement is the sole, complete, and final agreement between the parties.  The statement must be made by:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The college athlete or, if the athlete is a minor, the parent or guardian of the athlete;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The third party; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If a name, image, or likeness agent provided service in connection with the agreement, the agent.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-245" eff="2023-02-23" path="ยง216" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
