<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-1209.03</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Program participant eligibility.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>To be eligible for financial assistance provided through the Program, an individual shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Meet the relevant enrollment requirements for the accredited master's degree program at UDC in which the individual enrolls;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Be a resident of the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Be enrolled in a UDC accredited master's degree program necessary to obtain licensure in a behavioral health and human services occupation in the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Have a stated interest in pursuing a license in a behavioral health and human services occupation and to work in a behavioral health and human services occupation in the District; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Meet other criteria as specified by UDC.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>To maintain eligibility for financial assistance through the Program, an individual shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Maintain satisfactory academic progress, as determined by UDC;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Be consecutively enrolled as a full-time or part-time student in an accredited master's degree program at UDC; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Meet any other requirement determined by UDC to be necessary or appropriate for Program participation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In exchange for accepting Program financial assistance, a Program participant shall commit to working for a District government agency, an LEA in the District, or a health care provider organization operating in the District for 3 years after receiving an accredited master's degree and earning the appropriate licensure or certification needed to practice in a behavioral health and human services occupation in the District.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If an individual successfully passes the licensure exam for a degree program authorized for licensure by the Board of Professional Counseling or Board of Social Work but does not complete 3 years working for a District government agency, an LEA in the District, or a health care provider organization operating in the District, the individual shall be obligated to return all financial assistance provided to the individual under the Program, regardless of any partial completion of the 3-year minimum; except, that in extraordinary circumstances beyond the individual's control, UDC may waive or pro-rate the obligation to return all of the financial assistance.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>UDC may impose additional requirements which, if not met by a Program participant, require the individual to return some or all of the financial assistance.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2024-01-23" doc="D.C. Law 25-104" eff="2024-01-23" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-01-23" doc="D.C. Law 25-104" eff="2024-01-23" path="ยง4" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
