<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-197.01</num>
  <heading>School Connect Pilot Program</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Deputy Mayor for Education shall convene a working group to establish a plan for transition of the School Connect pilot program ("Pilot Program"), as operated by the Department of For-Hire Vehicles, and to provide recommendations for the repositioning of positions, vehicles, software, and any other assets to a District agency within the Education or Public Safety cluster.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The working group shall include representation from:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Department of For-Hire Vehicles;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Office of the Deputy Mayor for Education;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Office of the Deputy Mayor for Public Safety and Justice;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Office of the Deputy Mayor for Operations and Infrastructure; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Agencies under the purview of each Deputy Mayor as each Deputy Mayor deems appropriate for participation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In establishing a Pilot Program transition plan, the working group shall consider:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An analysis of program performance, based on available data, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Pilot Program participation rate;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Pilot Program costs and identification of significant cost drivers;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Driver and transportation assistant satisfaction regarding program performance, job safety, work environment, and other factors deemed relevant; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Parent and student satisfaction regarding performance, safety, reliability, and any other factors deemed relevant;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Alignment with recommendations of the School Safety Enhancement Committee, as applicable, as established in <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-50" path="§4192">section 4192 of the School Safety Coordination Act of 2023, effective September 6, 2023 (D.C. Law 25-50; 70 DCR 10366)</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The potential for use of Pilot Program vehicles and assets to enhance operations of school transportation or other transportation programs operated by the District; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>If the Pilot Program is intended to continue beyond the 2024-2025 school year, the recommended agency within the Education or Public Safety cluster under which it will be housed and operated.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Deputy Mayor for Education shall incorporate feedback from students and families currently served by the Pilot Program in working group deliberations and shall permit Pilot Program participants to attend working group meetings.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>No later than 30 days prior to the Mayor's submission of the Fiscal Year 2026 budget and financial plan, the Deputy Mayor for Education shall provide, in writing, an update on the recommendations of the working group to the Council committees with jurisdiction over the Education cluster and the Department of For-Hire Vehicles.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2015-10-22" doc="D.C. Law 21-36" eff="2015-10-22" path="IV" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-506" path="§4132" codified:display="Note" app="2024-09-18" eff="2024-07-15">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-506" path="§4132">§ 4132 of Fiscal Year 2025 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-506, July 15, 2024, 71 DCR 8406)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Act 25-506" eff="2024-07-15" path="§4132" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Law 25-217" eff="2024-09-18" path="IV|N" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Law 25-217" eff="2024-09-18" path="§4132" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
