<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-1631.03</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Name, image, or likeness activity and compensation; limits on institutions, conferences, and athletic associations.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in <cite path="§38-1631.04">§ 38-1631.04</cite>, <cite path="38|16A">this chapter</cite> does not limit the ability of a college athlete to engage in name, image, or likeness activity to the extent permitted under other District law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in <cite path="§38-1631.04">§ 38-1631.04</cite>:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An institution, conference, or athletic association may not:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Prevent or restrict a college athlete from:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Receiving name, image, or likeness compensation;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Entering into a name, image, or likeness agreement;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Engaging in name, image, or likeness activity;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>Obtaining the services of a name, image, or likeness agent; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>Creating or participating in a group license; or</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Interfere with the formation or recognition of a collective representative to facilitate or provide representation to negotiate a group license.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An athletic association may not prevent or restrict an institution or college athlete from participating in an intercollegiate sport because the college athlete:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Receives name, image, or likeness compensation;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Enters into a name, image, or likeness agreement;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Engages in name, image, or likeness activity; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Obtains the services of a name, image, or likeness agent.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Receipt of name, image, or likeness compensation may not affect eligibility of a college athlete or the duration, amount, or renewal of an athletic scholarship.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-245" eff="2023-02-23" path="§213" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
