<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-1209.02</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Program establishment.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a Behavioral Health and Human Services Scholarship Program at the University of the District of Columbia to provide financial assistance to individuals who seek to obtain an accredited master's degree from UDC and become licensed in a behavioral health and human services occupation to work for a District government agency, an LEA located in the District, or for a health care provider organization operating in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Program shall provide financial assistance to UDC students for:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The successful completion of an accredited master's degree program at UDC; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Passage of licensure exams to become licensed in a behavioral health and human services occupation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The financial assistance to Program participants shall include some or all of the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Tuition at UDC, to the extent charged;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Academic costs, including the cost of books and supplies;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Stipends to be used toward living expenses and transportation; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Fees associated with obtaining a license for a behavioral health and human services occupation in the District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>UDC shall select individuals to participate in the Program, consistent with the eligibility criteria established pursuant to <cite path="ยง38-1209.03">ยง 38-1209.03</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Program marketing and public education shall be provided by UDC to attract District residents and employees to the Program.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Among other authorized uses, UDC may use local funds appropriated to the Program to provide:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Salaries and fringe benefits for faculty and staff directly engaged in providing courses necessary to obtain an accredited master's degree;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Instructional materials used in courses necessary to obtain an accredited master's degree; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Marketing and recruitment activities to attract individuals to the Program.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2024-01-23" doc="D.C. Law 25-104" eff="2024-01-23" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-01-23" doc="D.C. Law 25-104" eff="2024-01-23" path="ยง3" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
