<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-1209.01</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Definitions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of <cite path="38|12|IX">this subchapter</cite>, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Accredited master's degree" means an accredited master's degree under the Middle States Commission on Higher Education in counseling, school counseling, clinical mental health counseling, social work or other master's degree programs accepted by the Board of Professional Counseling or Board of Social Work for the purposes of licensure in a behavioral health and human services occupation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Behavioral health and human services occupation" means an occupation that requires a worker to be licensed by the District's Board of Professional Counseling or Board of Social Work.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Health care provider organization" means an entity that is licensed under federal, state, or District law to provide health care services and provides those services in the District. The term  includes provider organizations certified by the Department of Behavioral Health, including group practice provider organizations enrolled in the District's Medicaid program.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"LEA" means local education agency, which is the District of Columbia Public Schools system or any individual or group of public charter schools operating under a single charter.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Program" means the Behavioral Health and Suman Services Program established by <cite path="ยง38-1209.02">ยง 38-1209.02</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"UDC" means the University of the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2024-01-23" doc="D.C. Law 25-104" eff="2024-01-23" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-01-23" doc="D.C. Law 25-104" eff="2024-01-23" path="ยง2" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
