<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-174.02</num>
  <heading proof="needed">District of Columbia Public Schools Flexible Schedule Pilot.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In Fiscal Year 2024, DCPS shall provide up to $400,000 per school to 6 or more schools for the purpose of continuing, creating, or planning scheduling arrangements that allow for variation in instructional calendars and formats on a daily or weekly basis for the schools' educators while continuing to provide academic instruction to students.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>By February 15, 2024, DCPS shall provide a report to Council that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Accounts for Fiscal Year 2024 funds spent and anticipated to be spent pursuant to subsection (a) of this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Explains whether DCPS anticipates exhausting appropriated funds by the end of the school year; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Identifies schools that requested to receive funds pursuant to subsection (a) of this section but were not selected and provides a justification for each school's exclusion.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "educator" includes a principal, assistant principal, teacher, assistant teacher, paraprofessional, school psychologist or counselor, all school service providers, or any person who provides professional educational services or education psychological services at a school.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-9" type="History" path="ยง105b">June 12, 2007, D.C. Law 17-9, ยง 105b</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-09-06" doc="D.C. Law 25-50" eff="2023-09-06" path="ยง4182" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
