<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-2612.01</num>
  <heading proof="needed">CTE and dual enrollment reporting.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Beginning with School Year 2024-2025 and annually by March 1 thereafter, OSSE shall publish on its website the following information concerning CTE programs for the previous school year:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The total number of students enrolled in CTE courses;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The total number of CTE students who participated in OSSE-funded work-based learning opportunities;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The total number of CTE concentrators who obtained an industry certification or credential disaggregated by the specific types of industry certifications or credentials obtained;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The number of CTE concentrators who earned college credit prior to high-school graduation and the number of credits earned;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The 4-year high-school graduation rate of CTE concentrators; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The total number of CTE concentrators who enrolled in a postsecondary educational institution within 12 months after graduation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>By December 1, 2024, OSSE shall publish on its website the following information concerning dual enrollment programs for the previous school year:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The amount of money spent on dual enrollment through the OSSE Dual Enrollment Consortium Program ("DECP");</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A list of institutions of higher education that received payments to operate dual enrollment programs through the DECP and the total amount of funding received by each institution of higher education;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The number of students, by individual student count per semester and by seat count, participating in locally funded dual enrollment courses and the DECP, which shall be disaggregated by the LEA and school the students attend, and shall include:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The number of economically disadvantaged students who participate in dual enrollment courses;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The number of students with disabilities who participate in dual enrollment courses;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The number of students by ward of school who participate in dual enrollment courses; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The number of students by race or ethnicity, if known, who participate in dual enrollment courses.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>LEAs shall provide all data requested by OSSE to meet the reporting requirements under this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Advanced Technical Center" means an OSSE-operated open-enrollment education center where students enrolled in DCPS or public charter high schools can participate in CTE programming while remaining enrolled in their high school.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"CTE" means career and technical education programming funded by a grant received pursuant to the Strengthening Career and Technical Education for the 21st Century Act, approved July 31, 2018 (Pub. L. No. 115-224; 132 Stat. 1563), or through OSSE's Advanced Technical Center.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"CTE concentrator" means a student who has completed at least 3 courses in a CTE pathway.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"CTE pathway" means an OSSE-approved sequence of at least 4 nonduplicative career education courses or content at the secondary level that incorporates technical, academic, and employability knowledge and skills.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Educational institution" shall have the same meaning as provided in <cite path="§38-1302|(4)">§ 38-1302(4)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"Industry certification or credential" means industry-endorsed assessments that are designed to indicate an individual's ability and competence in a field of work and signify satisfactory completion of education and experience requirements.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>"Postsecondary" means the level of education beyond high school.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>"Work-based learning" shall have the same meaning as provided in section 3(55) of the Carl D. Perkins Vocational and Technical Education Act of 2006, approved August 12, 2006 (120 Stat.685; 20 U.S.C. § 2302(55)).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-176" type="History" path="§7f-1">Oct. 21, 2000, D.C. Law 13-176, § 7f-1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-176" type="History" path="§7f-1" display="false">Oct. 21, 2000, D.C. Law 13-176, § 7f-1</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-506" path="§4162" codified:display="Note" app="2024-09-18" eff="2024-07-15">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-506" path="§4162|includes|7f-1">§ 7f-1 of Fiscal Year 2025 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-506, July 15, 2024, 71 DCR 8406)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Act 25-506" eff="2024-07-15" path="§4162" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Law 25-217" eff="2024-09-18" path="§4162" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
