<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-2851.05</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Reports.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Beginning in fiscal year 2011, the Mayor shall submit to the Council quarterly financial reports for DCPS setting forth by organization Level 4 approved budget, revised budget, actual expenditures and funds obligated to date, and projected expenditures for the full fiscal year.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>By March 31, 2024, and annually thereafter, the Mayor shall transmit a report of the previous school year's actual expenditures, for each school, to the Office of the State Superintendent of Education. The report shall conform to the common financial reporting standards established by the Department of Education pursuant to <cite path="§38-191|(b)|(10)">§ 38-191(b)(10)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>By no later than November 30th of each year, the Chancellor shall provide a written report to the Council describing programmatically how at-risk allocations provided to DCPS pursuant to <cite path="§38-2905.01">§ 38-2905.01</cite> were used in the previous school year to improve student achievement among at-risk students. The report also shall explain the allocation of at-risk funds sorted by individual school.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-722" path="§106" codified:display="Note" app="2023-03-10" eff="2023-01-10">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-722" path="§106">§ 106 of Schools First in Budgeting Emergency Amendment Act of 2022 (D.C. Act 24-722, Jan. 10, 2023, 70 DCR 516)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Act 24-722" eff="2023-01-10" path="§106" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-300" eff="2023-03-10" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-300" eff="2023-03-10" path="§106" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
