<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-2851.01</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Definitions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of <cite path="38|28A">this chapter</cite>, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Advance Expenditures" means all amounts expended by DCPS during a fiscal year that are charged against the local fund appropriations for DCPS for the next fiscal year, as authorized in an act making appropriations for DCPS.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(1A)</num>
      <text>"Central Administration" means the programs, services, and employees that support the functions necessary for the governance of the DCPS school district as a whole, including general oversight and management of support services, such as procurement, human resources, and financial administration, whose costs are not attributable to School Support, School-Wide, or Local Schools.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"DCPS" means the District of Columbia Public Schools system.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"ELL" means English language learner.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3A)</num>
      <text>"Lapsed Appropriations" means the aggregate balance of local fund appropriations for DCPS that is unspent at the end of the fiscal year for which the appropriations were made.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Local Schools" means the individual schools comprising the DCPS system and whose programs, services, and employees are paid with funds under the control and direction of the individual school principals.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Projected enrollment" is the number of students projected to be enrolled at a specific DCPS school at the time the Mayor's budget is proposed to the Council.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"School Support" means the programs, services, and employees that provide system-wide support to DCPS schools, such as curriculum development, instructional superintendents, teacher evaluations, and professional development, whose costs are not attributable to Central Administration, School-Wide, or Local Schools.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>"School-Wide" means the programs, services, and employees that directly support schools and are budgeted centrally but provided directly to individual schools, such as food service, security, fixed costs, speech therapists, itinerant ELL services, and substitute teachers, whose costs are not attributable to Central Administration, School Support, or Local Schools.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>"Uniform Per Student Funding Formula" means the formula for funding DCPS and the District's public charter schools established pursuant to the UPSFF Act.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>"UPSFF Act" means <cite path="38|29|I">subchapter I of Chapter 29 of this title</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-722" path="§102" codified:display="Note" app="2023-03-10" eff="2023-01-10">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-722" path="§102">§ 102 of Schools First in Budgeting Emergency Amendment Act of 2022 (D.C. Act 24-722, Jan. 10, 2023, 70 DCR 516)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Act 24-722" eff="2023-01-10" path="§102" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-300" eff="2023-03-10" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-300" eff="2023-03-10" path="§102" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Act 25-172" path="§4202|(a)" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2023-07-14" eff="2023-07-14">
            Section 4203 of D.C. Act 25-172 provided that the changes made to this section by section 4202(a) D.C. Act 25-172 shall apply as of July 1, 2023.
          </annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-07-14" doc="D.C. Act 25-172" eff="2023-07-14" path="§4202|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-172" path="§4202|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2023-07-14" eff="2023-07-14">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-172" path="§4202|(a)">§ 4202(a) of Fiscal Year 2024 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2023 (D.C. Act 25-172, July 14, 2023, 70 DCR 9933)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-09-06" doc="D.C. Law 25-50" eff="2023-09-06" path="§4202|(a)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-09-06" doc="D.C. Law 25-50" eff="2023-09-06" path="§4202|(a)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-09-06" doc="D.C. Law 25-50" eff="2023-09-06" path="§4202|(a)|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-50" path="§4202|(a)" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2023-09-06" eff="2023-09-06">
            Section 4203 of D.C. Law 25-50 provided that the changes made to this section by section 4202(a) D.C. Law 25-50 shall apply as of July 1, 2023.
          </annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-09-06" doc="D.C. Law 25-50" eff="2023-09-06" path="§4202|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
