<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-2992</num>
  <heading>Proposed new funding and organizational model for the Duke Ellington School of the Arts.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Chancellor or the Chancellor's DCPS designee shall meet with the DESAP Board of Directors at least once every 4 weeks to discuss a proposed new funding and organizational model for the Duke Ellington School of the Arts ("DESA") until a memorandum of agreement ("MOA") is signed by both parties.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The proposed new funding and organizational model shall address and resolve the following matters:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The conversion of DESAP faculty and staff, other than the DESAP Principal, to DCPS employee status with levels of pay for all such individuals comparable to those of DCPS employees;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The absorption of all of DESA's human resources for DESA employees, staff payroll for DESA employees, and student support functions into the budget of DCPS;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The preservation of, and due regard for, the dual-curriculum nature of DESA, including its arts faculty and staff;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The continuation of DESA's pre-professional arts program at the same or higher level of quality as the current pre-professional arts program; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The continued role of the DESAP Board of Directors in providing guidance and support for the DESA arts program, including partnerships with third-party organizations and the Ellington Fund.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>DCPS shall submit the MOA to the Council no later than 2 weeks after it is signed by DCPS and the DESAP Board of Directors.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>DCPS and the DESAP Board of Directors shall independently and promptly present to the Council a report detailing their proposed new DESA funding and organizational model together with a recommendation for Council action should an MOA not be attained by December 31, 2022.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Chairman of the Council may appoint up to 2 observers to attend the meetings between DCPS and the DESAP Board of Directors.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§4253" codified:display="Note" app="2021-11-13" eff="2021-08-23">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§4253">§ 4253 of Fiscal Year 2022 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-159, Aug. 23, 2021, 68 DCR 008602)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-11-13" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§4253" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-11-13" doc="D.C. Law 24-45" eff="2021-11-13" path="§4251" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-11-13" doc="D.C. Law 24-45" eff="2021-11-13" path="§4253" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-470" path="§4142" codified:display="Note" app="2022-07-13" eff="2022-07-13">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-470" path="§4142">§ 4142 of Fiscal Year 2023 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2022 (D.C. Act 24-470, July 13, 2022, 69 DCR 008707)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2022-07-13" doc="D.C. Act 24-470" eff="2022-07-13" path="§4142" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2022-09-21" doc="D.C. Law 24-167" eff="2022-09-21" path="§4142" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
