<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-3101</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Definitions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this act, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Action Plan" means a written assessment, posted on the DDOT website prior to implementation of the Action Plan, that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Summarizes the actions taken by DDOT, including any data produced, to complete a comprehensive assessment of traffic safety needs for a school, including the school zone;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Details the types of traffic safety infrastructure and the location, scope, and timing of installation of traffic safety infrastructure, by infrastructure element, to be installed, pursuant to an assessment of traffic safety needs undertaken by DDOT, as well as barriers or restrictions to implementation of traffic safety infrastructure identified by DDOT; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Describes the nature and timing of community engagement on implementation of the recommendations in the Action Plan.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Community-based organization" and "CBO" mean an organization operated by a nonprofit entity or faith-based organization that provides services, including violence interruption and deterrence and youth development.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"DCPS" means the District of Columbia Public Schools.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"DDOT" means the District Department of Transportation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"DME" means the Deputy Mayor for Education.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"Local education agency" and "LEA" mean DCPS or any individual public charter school or group of public charter schools operating under a single charter.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>"New school" means:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A school located in a never-before-occupied structure, except for a structure erected in an existing school zone; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A school located in a preexisting structure that has not been used as a DCPS school or public charter school within the last 5 years.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>"Priority area" means an area of the District, designated by the School Safety and Safe Passage Working Group, for receipt of safe passage services and whose bounds include at least the full school zone for at least one public school.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>"Safe passage" means programs and services administered or otherwise overseen by the DME, in collaboration with other relevant District and federal agencies, targeted at ensuring DCPS and public charter school students can travel to and from their schools safe from the threat of physical violence, intimidation, and other public safety concerns.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>"School zone" includes any street, block, or intersection within 350 feet of a given school's building or school grounds and includes crossing points closest to that boundary; however, areas within school zones that are unused for crossings, such as along a highway without marked crossing points, may be excluded from the school zone.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>"Shared fleet device" shall have the same meaning as provided in <cite path="§50-2201.02|(14D)">§ 50-2201.02(14D)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>"Spot safety assessment" means a determination of whether traffic safety infrastructure should be installed to increase traffic safety at a specific location.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>"Traffic safety infrastructure"  includes speed humps, bumps, cushions, tables, rumble strips, pavement markings, signs that warn of the presence of children, traffic signals and signage, raised crosswalks, raised intersections, continuous sidewalks, high-visibility crosswalks, curb extensions, pedestrian islands, bicycle lanes, bus islands and shelters, stop signs, including all way stops, automated traffic enforcement cameras and signage, and flashing signals and beacons.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-111" type="History" path="§2">May 23, 2000, D.C. Law 13-111, § 2, 47 DCR 2206</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-20" type="History">Sept. 18, 2007, D.C. Law 17-20, § 6023, 54 DCR 7052</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-320" type="History">Mar. 21, 2009, D.C. Law 17-320, § 3, 56 DCR 219</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of School Proximity Traffic Calming Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-169, October 25, 2007,  54 DCR 10980).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 6023 of Fiscal Year 2008 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-74, July 25, 2007,  54 DCR 7549).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-94">D.C. Law 17-94</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(D) Public park.”; in subsec. (h), substituted “school zone or on streets directly bordering recreation centers, libraries, and public parks” for “school zone”; and in subsec. (i), substituted “school zones, recreation centers, libraries, and public parks within 60 days from October 15, 2007” for “school zones within 60 days from the effective date of this act”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(C) Library; or</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) Recreation center;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(A) School building within a school zone;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) The Mayor shall place the traffic control device, deemed necessary under subsection (a) of this section, on every street within 100 yards of a:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-94">D.C. Law 17-94</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “school zones and streets directly bordering recreation centers, libraries, and public parks” for “school zones”; in subsec. (b), substituted “school zone or on streets directly bordering recreation centers, libraries, and public parks” for “school zone”; in subsec. (c)(1), substituted “schools zones and on streets directly bordering recreation centers, libraries, and public parks” for “school zones”; in subsec. (e), in par. (1), substituted “School zones and streets directly bordering recreation centers, libraries, and public parks” for “School zones” and “school zones and streets directly bordering recreation centers, libraries, and public parks” for “School zones”, and amended par. (2) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-320">D.C. Law 17-320</cite> added subsec. (f-1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-20">D.C. Law 17-20</cite> rewrote subsec. (f), which had read as follows: “(f) At least one crossing guard shall be placed at elementary schools. Crossing guards shall be placed at middle or junior high schools, and high schools where deemed necessary by the Metropolitan Police Department.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§5-132.02">§ 5-132.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§4112|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§4112|(b)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§4112|(c)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§4112|(d)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§4112|(e)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§4112|(f)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-285" eff="2023-03-10" path="§2|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 24-285" path="§2|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2023-03-10" eff="2023-03-10">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-285" path="">D.C. Law 24-285</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-285" path="§4">§ 4 of D.C. Law 24-285</cite> provided that the change made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-285" path="§2|(a)">§ 2(a) of D.C. Law 24-285</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-09-06" doc="D.C. Law 25-50" eff="2023-09-06" path="§6122|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-50" path="§6123|(a)" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2023-09-06" eff="2023-09-06"><cite doc="D.C.Law 25-50" path="§6123">Section 6123 of D.C. Law 25-50</cite> amended <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-285" path="§4">section 4 of D.C. Law 24-285</cite> removing the applicability provision impacting this section.  Therefore the amendment of this section by section 2(a) of Law 24-285 has been implemented.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-09-06" doc="D.C. Law 25-50" eff="2023-09-06" path="§6123|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
