<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-785.02</num>
  <heading>Establishment of District of Columbia Education Research Practice Partnership.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Education Research Practice Partnership shall consist of an independent, non-governmental entity selected through the competitive process as established in <cite path="§38-785.03">§ 38-785.03</cite> and subject to a master research services agreement entered into with the District pursuant to subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Partnership shall conduct independent education-related research that will support improvement in the District's public schools, and shall publicly report the findings of the research, and will also benefit the Council's legislative and oversight responsibilities.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Within 60 days of the independent, non-governmental entity being chosen pursuant to <cite path="§38-785.03">§ 38-785.03</cite>, the District shall enter into a master research services agreement ("Agreement"), encompassing data collection, sharing, ownership, and confidentiality, with the chosen independent, non-governmental entity for the purpose of enabling the Partnership to carry out its purposes.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Agreement also shall set forth in broad terms the general scope of services and the process for developing research projects.  The Agreement shall not direct the research agenda or any specific research projects.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Agreement shall be updated at least once every 5 years or as needed.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding <cite path="§1-328.13">§ 1-328.13</cite>, in Fiscal Year 2023 no later than November 15, 2022, the Deputy Mayor for Education shall issue a grant to the Partnership in the amount of $400,000.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2019-03-28" doc="D.C. Law 22-268" eff="2019-03-28" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-03-28" doc="D.C. Law 22-268" eff="2019-03-28" path="§103" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-470" path="§4122|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2022-07-13" eff="2022-07-13">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-470" path="§4122|(a)">§ 4122(a) of Fiscal Year 2023 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2022 (D.C. Act 24-470, July 13, 2022, 69 DCR 008707)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2022-07-13" doc="D.C. Act 24-470" eff="2022-07-13" path="§4122|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2022-09-21" doc="D.C. Law 24-167" eff="2022-09-21" path="§4122|(a)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
