<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-973.01</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on April 24, 2022.*
      </text>
  <heading>Classroom notification and COVID surge reporting requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>After a confirmed COVID-19 case of a student attending in-person learning or a school employee assigned to a classroom, a school shall send notice to all parents or guardians of students in the affected classroom and to all school personnel known to have spent at least one 15-minute period in the prior 3 days in the same classroom as the student or school employee. The notice shall disclose the fact of a positive test in the classroom and provide information on COVID-19 testing locations.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The notice required pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be sent within 24 hours, or one business day if the case is confirmed on a day when schools are closed, of a confirmed COVID-19 case to school staff assigned to the affected classroom and to parents or guardians of students in the affected classroom electronically or through the preferred method of contact asserted by a student's parent or guardian, if one has been asserted.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Within 2 business days after February 8, 2022, and monthly thereafter, DCPS shall transmit to the Council and post on the DCPS website the names of schools that have not been assigned a COVID Strategy and Logistics Coordinator and the names of schools that have not been assigned a full-time substitute teacher as of that date.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Office of the State Superintendent shall post on its website every week the percentage of randomized asymptomatic testing completed in each school during the preceding week.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"DCPS" means District of Columbia Public Schools.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"School" means a school in the DCPS system or an individual public charter school.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-973.01" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§38-973.01" codified:display="Note"/>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-973.01" before="heading" history="false" display-template="" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§38-973.01">
    <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on April 24, 2022.*
      </text>
  </codify:insert>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2022-02-08" doc="D.C. Act 24-322" eff="2022-02-08" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2022-02-08" doc="D.C. Act 24-322" eff="2022-02-08" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2022-02-08" doc="D.C. Act 24-322" eff="2022-02-08" path="§2" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-322" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2022-02-08" eff="2022-02-08">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-322" path="§2">§ 2 of Returning to School Safely Emergency Amendment Act of 2022 (D.C. Act 24-322, Feb. 8, 2022, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
