<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-971.02</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on January 24, 2022.*
      </text>
  <heading>Expansion of virtual education.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>During School Year 2021‐2022, an LEA shall provide distance learning to a student who is enrolled in the LEA and who is ineligible for a vaccine that is approved and authorized in the United States to prevent COVID‐19 if a licensed physician, nurse practitioner, or physician assistant has recommended that the student participate in distance learning and not in‐person school because:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The student has a documented medical condition that puts the student at high risk of severe illness from COVID‐19, consistent with the guidance of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The student's in‐person attendance would endanger an individual in the student's household because the individual has a documented medical condition, as defined by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, that places the individual at high risk of severe illness from COVID‐19.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>DCPS may limit the total number of students who receive distance learning pursuant to paragraph (1) of and this subsection to 200 elementary school students and 150 secondary school students in addition to those students already enrolled in its virtual learning academy as of October 5, 2021.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A public charter school LEA may limit the total number of students who receive distance learning instruction pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection; provided, that the limit shall be no less than 3% of the total number of students enrolled in the public charter school LEA.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Distance learning provided pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall comply with the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, approved April 13, 1970 (118 Stat. 2647; 20 U.S.C. § 1400 <em>et seq</em>.), section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (87 Stat. 394, 29 U.S.C. § 701 <em>et seq</em>), and ​their implementing regulations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of District law, during School Year 2021-2022, a student who receives distance learning instruction pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall be considered to be enrolled in the LEA for the purposes of the enrollment audit, school payment process, and other reasons determined by the Office of the State Superintendent of Education, even if the student has not physically attended or is not physically attending the LEA during any portion of the school year; provided, that the student otherwise complies with the attendance policies of the LEA.</text>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-952.02" expire="2021-10-26" codified:display="Note">For temporary (90 days) creation of § 38-971.02, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-190" path="§102">§ 102 of Protecting Our Children Emergency Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-190, Oct. 26, 2021, 68 DCR 011348)</cite>.</codify:annotation>
  <codify:annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-971.02" applicability="2021-10-26" delay="50" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§38-971.02">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-190" path="§102">§ 102 of Protecting Our Children Emergency Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-190, Oct. 26, 2021, 68 DCR 011348)</cite>.</codify:annotation>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-971.02" before="heading" history="false" display-template="" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§38-971.02">
    <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on January 24, 2022.*
      </text>
  </codify:insert>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-10-26" doc="D.C. Act 24-190" eff="2021-10-26" path="§102" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-10-26" doc="D.C. Act 24-190" eff="2021-10-26" path="§102" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-190" path="§102" codified:display="Note" app="2021-10-26" eff="2021-10-26">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-190" path="§102">§ 102 of Protecting Our Children Emergency Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-190, Oct. 26, 2021, 68 DCR 011348)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
