<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>24-403.01b</num>
  <heading proof="needed">First Step Act parity in earned time credits.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any person who has been convicted of a felony offense under District law and successfully completes evidence-based recidivism reduction programming or productive activities, except for those persons determined to be ineligible by the Department of Corrections or Bureau of Prisons because of their conviction for a District offense analogous to an ineligible federal offense, shall earn time credits as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A person shall earn 10 days of time credits for every 30 days of successful participation in evidence-based recidivism reduction programming or productive activities, as defined in 18 U.S.C. ยง 3635, while in the custody of the Department of Corrections or Bureau of Prisons; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A person determined by the Department of Corrections or Bureau of Prisons to be at a minimum or low risk for recidivating, who, over 2 consecutive assessments, has not increased their risk of recidivism, shall earn an additional 5 days of time credits for every 30 days of successful participation in evidence-based recidivism reduction programming or productive activities.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, time credits earned under this section shall be applied to a person's minimum term of imprisonment to determine the date of eligibility for release on parole and to the person's maximum term of imprisonment to determine the date when release on parole becomes mandatory.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>This section shall apply as of December 21, 2018.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 72-1-ch492" path="ยง3a-2">July 15, 1932, 47 Stat. 697, ch. 492, ยง 3a-2</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-04-21" doc="D.C. Law 24-344" eff="2023-04-21" path="ยง22" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
