<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-1141.06b</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Problem-gambling report and program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>By October 31, 2024, the Department shall award a contract of $300,000 to a non-governmental organization for the purpose of conducting a needs assessment aimed at better understanding how problem gambling is impacting the District's residents and developing strategies for establishing an evidence-based or evidence-informed problem-gambling prevention, harm reduction, and treatment program.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The non-governmental organization awarded the contract pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall submit a report of its fundings by November 1, 2025, to the Department, which the Department shall submit to the Council by December 31, 2025.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The report shall, at a minimum, include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Surveys and interviews with community members to gather information about their experiences with gambling, including issues related to problem gambling;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Analysis of existing data sources, including hospital admissions, emergency room visits, treatment records, and Medicaid billing reports, to identify trends and patterns related to problem gambling;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Community meetings and focus groups to facilitate discussions about problem gambling and its effects on individuals, families, and communities;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Collaborations with stakeholders such as advocacy groups and treatment providers that specialize in gambling addiction;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Mapping of local gambling resources to create an inventory or map of gambling-related services, including gambling addiction helplines, support groups, and treatment centers; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Evaluations of existing policies and programs aimed at addressing problem gambling, including public awareness campaigns, responsible gambling initiatives, and treatment services, to identify areas for improvement and opportunities for innovation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Beginning in Fiscal Year 2026, the Department shall establish:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A pilot problem-gambling program for up to 200 individuals, based on the findings from the report outlined in subsection (a) of this section; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A pilot training program for up to 50 certified mental health and substance use disorder providers on best practices for screening, assessing, and providing treatment to individuals with problem-gambling disorder.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, "problem gambling" means a condition characterized by persistent and recurrent problematic gambling behavior that adversely affects individuals or their families, often disrupting their daily lives and careers, resulting in significant distress or impairment.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History" path="§5117b">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 5117b</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History" path="§5117b" display="false">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 5117b</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-506" path="§5102" codified:display="Note" app="2024-09-18" eff="2024-07-15">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-506" path="§5102">§ 5102 of Fiscal Year 2025 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-506, July 15, 2024, 71 DCR 8406)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Act 25-506" eff="2024-07-15" path="§5102" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Law 25-217" eff="2024-09-18" path="§5102" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
