<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-2341.02a</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on March 24, 2022. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite path="§7-2341.02a(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
  <heading>Exemption from licensure or certification.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other law, an individual may provide emergency medical services without a District license or certification until August 10, 2022, if the individual:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Is licensed or certified in good standing in their home jurisdiction to provide emergency medical services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Has been fully vaccinated against COVID-19 or has been granted a medical or religious exemption from vaccination by the Department of Health ("Department"); and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Has not been issued an order limiting or restricting the individual's ability to provide emergency medical services in any state or jurisdiction.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An emergency medical services agency utilizing the services of an individual providing emergency medical services pursuant to this section shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Verify the credentials and license or certification status of the individual in order to ensure compliance with this section, including by confirming that the individual has not been issued a suspension or revocation order by the District and verifying that the individual has been fully vaccinated for COVID-19 or has received an exemption from vaccination by the Department;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Implement a process by which the credentials and home jurisdiction license or certification status of the individual is routinely verified; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Ensure proper supervision of any services being provided by such individual.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall not require an individual providing emergency medical services pursuant to this section to apply for a District license or certification prior to March 31, 2022<s>.".</s>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any temporary license or certification, including a limited reciprocity certification, issued by the Mayor shall not expire before August 10, 2022.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-189" path="§3" codified:display="Note" app="2021-12-24" eff="2021-09-22">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-189" path="§3">§ 3 of Preserve Our Healthcare Workforce Emergency Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-189, Sept. 22, 2021, 68 DCR 011343)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-12-24" doc="D.C. Act 24-189" eff="2021-09-22" path="§3" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-12-24" doc="D.C. Act 24-245" eff="2021-12-24" path="§3" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-12-24" doc="D.C. Act 24-245" eff="2021-12-24" path="§3" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-245" path="§3" codified:display="Note" app="2021-12-24" eff="2021-12-24">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-245" path="§3">§ 3 of Preserve Our Healthcare Workforce Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-245, Dec. 24, 2021, 68 DCR 013514)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
