<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-2510.15</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Implementation of strategic gun violence reduction strategies.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Metropolitan Police Department ("MPD") shall facilitate a Law Enforcement Shooting Review no less than twice per month to review each shooting in the District that occurred since the last Law Enforcement Shooting Review, including non-fatal shootings.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The purpose of the Law Enforcement Shooting Reviews shall be to identify the potential for retaliation and law enforcement or other government agency contacts or interventions with persons involved in the reviewed shootings that may help to prevent retaliatory criminal conduct, and then assign responsibilities for immediate contacts or interventions.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The purpose of the Law Enforcement Shooting Review shall not be to discuss information outside the investigative file. To the extent that there is any information discussed during the Law Enforcement Shooting Review that is not already included in the investigative file, MPD shall document that information in the investigative file.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Deputy Mayor for Public Safety and Justice shall coordinate a Coordination Meeting/Intervention Services Shooting Review no less than twice per month to review each shooting in the District that occurred since the last Coordination Meeting/Intervention Services Shooting Review from a services and response perspective, in order to identify and assign government and community partners to outreach and engage those high-risk individuals implicated by the shootings.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="D.C. Law 1-85" path="§1015">Sept. 24, 1976, D.C. Law 1-85, § 1015</annotation>
    <annotation type="History" doc="D.C. Law 1-85" path="§1015" display="false">Sept. 24, 1976, D.C. Law 1-85, § 1015</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-05-10" doc="D.C. Law 22-314" eff="2019-05-10" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-410" path="§11|(k)" codified:display="Note" app="2024-06-08" eff="2024-03-11">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-410" path="§11|(k)|includes|1015">§ 1015 of Secure DC Omnibus Emergency Amendment Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-410, Mar. 11, 2024, 71 DCR 2693)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-06-08" doc="D.C. Act 25-410" eff="2024-03-11" path="§11|(k)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-490" path="§11|(k)" codified:display="Note" app="2024-06-08" eff="2024-06-07">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-490" path="§11|(k)|includes|1015">§ 1015 of Secure DC Omnibus Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-490, June 7, 2024, 71 DCR 7006)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-06-08" doc="D.C. Act 25-490" eff="2024-06-07" path="§11|(k)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-06-08" doc="D.C. Law 25-175" eff="2024-06-08" path="§15|(k)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
