<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-3213</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Office of Opioid Abatement.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>There is established within the Department of Behavioral Health the Office of Opioid Abatement.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Office shall be led by a Director with at least 10 years' professional experience and education in prevention, recovery, treatment, and harm reduction efforts for opioid use disorder and co-occurring substance use and mental health disorders.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Office shall have the power and duty to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Conduct a District-wide needs assessment to identify structural gaps and needs related to opioid use disorder and co-occurring substance use and mental health disorders;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Support the Commission's activities by providing staffing, research and policy expertise, facilities, technical assistance, and other resources;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Assist the Commission in preparing its recommendations regarding goals, objectives, and performance indicators pursuant to <cite path="§7-3212|(h)|(2)|(A)">§ 7-3212(h)(2)(A)</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Integrate the work of the Office and Commission and Fund expenditures with existing District strategic planning related to opioid use disorder and co-occurring substance use and mental health disorders;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Develop governing principles, policies, and procedures for the application and awarding of monies and grants from the Fund;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Oversee expenditures from the Fund, including by preparing a quarterly accounting of expenditures from the Fund and the Fund balance;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Issue, manage, and oversee awards and grants from the Fund, including collecting and publicly reporting data from awardees and grantees concerning the effectiveness of infrastructure, activities, practices, programs, services, supports, and strategies funded;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Prepare the annual report required by <cite path="§7-3221|(f)">§ 7-3221(f)</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Create and maintain a public website that includes:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Commission meeting attendance, agendas, and minutes;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The governing principles, policies, and procedures developed pursuant to paragraph (5) of this subsection;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The quarterly accountings of Fund expenditures and Fund balance prepared pursuant to paragraph (6) of this subsection;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>A listing of awards and grants from the Fund and awardee and grantee data collected pursuant to paragraph (7) of this subsection; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>The annual reports prepared pursuant to<cite path="§7-3221|(f)">§ 7-3221(f)</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If the Office decides not to follow a Commission recommendation in whole or in part, the Office shall provide the Commission with a written explanation for its decision within 14 days after the decision is made.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Commission shall have at least 7 days after receipt of the Office's written explanation provided pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection to provide a written response before the Office proceeds with its decision.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation applicability="effective" type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-3213" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§7-3213">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-315" path="">D.C. Law 24-315</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-315" path="§301">§ 301 of D.C. Law 24-315</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-315" path="§103">§ 103 of D.C. Law 24-315</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</codify:annotation>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-315" eff="2023-03-10" path="I" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-315" eff="2023-03-10" path="§103" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 24-315" path="§103" codified:display="Note" app="2023-03-10" eff="2023-03-10">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-315" path="">D.C. Law 24-315</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-315" path="§301">§ 301 of D.C. Law 24-315</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-315" path="§103">§ 103 of D.C. Law 24-315</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-48" path="§8|(a)" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2023-08-29" eff="2023-08-29"><cite doc="D.C. Law 25-48" path="§8|(a)">Section 8(a) of D.C. Law 25-48</cite> repealed, on a temporary basis, <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-315" path="§301">section 301 of D.C. Law 24-315</cite> removing the applicability provision impacting this section.  Therefore the creation of this section by section 101 of Law 24-315 has been implemented.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-08-29" doc="D.C. Law 25-48" eff="2023-08-29" path="§8|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-109" path="§3" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2024-01-23" eff="2024-01-23"><cite doc="D.C. Law 25-109" path="§3">Section 3 of D.C. Law 25-109</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-315" path="§301">section 301 of D.C. Law 24-315</cite> removing the applicability provision impacting this section.  Therefore the creation of this section by section 101 of Law 24-315 has been implemented.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-01-23" doc="D.C. Law 25-109" eff="2024-01-23" path="§3" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
