<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-503.10</num>
  <heading>Wards 2 and 3 Senior Wellness Center Feasibility and Planning Task Force.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a Senior Wellness Center Feasibility and Planning Task Force ("Task Force"), that shall evaluate and comment on the feasibility study and planning of a Wards 2 and 3 senior wellness center. The Task Force shall advise and guide the Mayor, the Council, and the Department on the development of a new wellness center to serve residents of Wards 2 and 3 and review programs and services to address senior needs in those communities.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Task Force shall be composed of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>One member representing the Department on Aging, appointed by the Mayor;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>One member representing the Department of Health, appointed by the Mayor;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>One member representing the Department of Parks and Recreation, appointed by the Mayor;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Two current ANC members representing Ward 2, appointed by the Ward 2 Councilmember;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Two current ANC members representing Ward 3, appointed by the Ward 3 Councilmember;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>One member of the community residing in Ward 2, appointed by the Ward 2 Councilmember;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>One member of the community residing in Ward 3, appointed by the Ward 3 Councilmember;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Two members of the community residing in Ward 2, appointed by the Council committee with oversight over matters concerned with services to the senior community ("Committee"); and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Two members of the community residing in Ward 3, appointed by the Committee.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Chairperson of the Committee shall appoint:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A Chairperson of the Task Force with design and planning experience, preferably an architect;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>One member representing the University of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Two members representing Wards 2 and 3 Senior Villages;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>One member who is a current participant of social services in Ward 2; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>One member who is a current participant of senior programming sponsored by the Department of Parks and Recreation;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The members of the Task Force shall serve without compensation and shall either reside or work within the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The members of the Task Force shall serve 2-year terms.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Task Force shall, at a minimum:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Conduct bi-monthly meetings to evaluate and be engaged in the planning and stages of development of a wellness center to serve residents of Wards 2 and 3;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Provide quarterly reports to the Committee, Mayor, and Department on the progress, findings, and recommendations from the meetings;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>By December 31, 2024, the Task Force shall prepare a plan that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Describes the state of the needs for the Wards 2 and 3 senior population, including a description of the food insecure, homebound, and isolated individuals by neighborhoods and demographics, root causes of the issues, and specific identifiable risks for the senior population, as well as descriptions of any subcategories and the unique needs of such subcategories;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Provides the Task Force's recommendations on the necessary space and facilities within the wellness center;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Identifies the Task Force's findings and recommendations on programming to serve the Wards 2 and 3 communities; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Provides non-binding advisory approval of the design and planning of the project.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-24" type="History" path="ยง310">Oct. 29, 1975, D.C. Law 1-24, title III, ยง 310</annotation>
    <annotation app="2022-07-13" doc="D.C. Act 24-470" eff="2022-07-13" path="ยง5132" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
