<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-743.10</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Advisory Committee on Medical Radiation Technologists.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established an Advisory Committee on Medical Radiation Technologists ("Committee"), which shall consist of the following 5 members:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A physician licensed in the District whose practice consists mostly of the type of medicine that requires significant interaction with medical radiation technologists;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Three individuals who work as medical radiation technologists; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A consumer member with no direct affiliation with medical radiation technology or a member of another health profession.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>To remain qualified to serve as a member of the Committee, the medical radiation technologist members who serve as initial appointees shall become licensed or registered in their profession within 180 days of the Department of Health's implementation of the licensure or registration requirements.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Committee shall develop and submit to the Board of Medicine guidelines and proposed regulations for the licensure and regulation of cardiovascular-interventional technologists, computed tomography technologists, magnetic resonance technologists, mammographers, nuclear medicine technologists, radiation therapists, radiographers, ultrasound technologists, and radiologist assistants.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-28" type="History" path="ยง4949a">Oct. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-28, ยง 4949a</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-191" eff="2024-07-19" path="ยง202|(d)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
