<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-742.12</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Microenterprise Home Kitchen Businesses.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>This section shall not:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Apply to a food establishment that is required to have a license under Department regulations; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Exempt a microenterprise home kitchen business from any applicable District or federal tax laws.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Department shall develop a microenterprise home kitchen permit and develop standards and regulations relating to the requirements of this permit.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A microenterprise home kitchen business shall register with the Department before beginning operation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Department may perform a pre-operational inspection of the microenterprise home kitchen business before that business begins operation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Department may enter the premises of a microenterprise home kitchen business with a permit issued by the Department during the operating hours of the microenterprise home kitchen to conduct:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Scheduled pre-operational and compliance inspections with reasonable advance notice of the inspection; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Unannounced inspections when the Department has a valid reason, which could include a consumer complaint, to suspect that a microenterprise home kitchen poses an imminent health hazard or is the source of an adulterated food or of an outbreak of illness caused by a contaminated food.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Department shall document the reason for any inspection after an initial inspection, keep a copy of the documentation on file with the microenterprise home kitchen's permit, and provide a copy of that documentation to the operator.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>An operator may qualify for a microenterprise home kitchen permit; provided, that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Food that is prepared at the microenterprise home kitchen is handled, stored, and prepared in compliance with Department regulations;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The kitchen facility used to prepare food for the microenterprise home kitchen meets the requirements established by the Department;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The operator provides written standard operating procedures to the Department that include:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Proposed procedures and methods for how all food will be stored, handled, and prepared;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Proposed procedures and methods of food preparation and handling;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Procedures, methods, and schedules for cleaning utensils and equipment;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Procedures and methods for the disposal of refuse; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>A plan for maintaining time or temperature control food at the appropriate temperatures for each time or temperature control food.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The operator operates only during the hours and only prepares the food items approved in the microenterprise home kitchen permit;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The operator provides notification to the consumer that, while a permit has been issued by the Department, the kitchen does not meet all of the requirements of a commercial retail food establishment; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The operator successfully passes a nationally accredited Certified Food Protection Manager Course approved by the Department and obtains a District-issued Certified Food Protection Manager Certificate.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>An operator can apply to amend their permit by submitting a written proposal in a format determined in rules developed by the Department;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>The Department shall not require, as a condition of obtaining a microenterprise home kitchen permit, that an operator:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Rent or lease space at a commercial kitchen outside of their home;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Rent or purchase equipment, utensils, or display containers or equipment, other than what is required for safe storage, handling, and preparation of the food offered for sale;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Have additional hand-washing facilities in their home, except to require that a hand washing station supplied with warm water and soap be conveniently located in food preparation, food dispensing, and warewashing areas;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Have additional kitchen sinks, except to require that the kitchen sink has hot and cold water and is fully operational;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Limit the individuals permitted in food preparation areas, food storage areas, and washing areas, except during food preparation;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Limit the presence of animals in the home, except to require that all animals are kept outside of food preparation areas;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Use specific materials for food-contact and non-food contact surfaces; provided, that the food-contact surfaces are smooth, easily cleanable, and in good repair; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Install significant equipment or make significant renovations to the home, beyond what would be required to ensure food and human safety in the food preparation areas.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>The Department has the authority to issue citations and summarily suspend or revoke a permit if an operator is not complying with any provisions set forth in this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(j)</num>
    <text>A person whose license or permit is revoked may, within 15 days after the notice of revocation by the Department, appeal the decision to the Office of Administrative Hearings.</text>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation applicability="effective" type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-742.12" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§7-742.12">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-21" path="">D.C. Law 25-21</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-21" path="§5">§ 5 of D.C. Law 25-21</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-21" path="§2">§ 2 of D.C. Law 25-21</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</codify:annotation>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-28" type="History" path="§4936">Oct. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-28, § 4936</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-07-01" doc="D.C. Law 25-21" eff="2023-07-01" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-07-01" doc="D.C. Law 25-21" eff="2023-07-01" path="§2" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 25-21" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2023-07-01" eff="2023-07-01">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-21" path="">D.C. Law 25-21</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-21" path="§5">§ 5 of D.C. Law 25-21</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-21" path="§2">§ 2 of D.C. Law 25-21</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-07-01" doc="D.C. Law 25-21" eff="2023-07-01" path="§2" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-50" path="§7098" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2023-09-06" eff="2023-09-06"><cite doc="D.C.Law 25-50" path="§7098">Section 7098 of D.C. Law 25-50</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-21" path="§5">section 5 of D.C. Law 25-21</cite> removing the applicability provision impacting this section.  Therefore the creation of this section by section 2 of Law 25-21 has been implemented.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-09-06" doc="D.C. Law 25-50" eff="2023-09-06" path="§7098" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
