<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-791.02</num>
  <heading proof="needed">High-Need Healthcare Career Scholarships and Supports Program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall establish the High-Need Healthcare Career Scholarships and Supports Program for the purpose of increasing the number of healthcare workers in high-need healthcare careers in the District by providing supports and services to individuals who agree to serve as such workers in the District.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Program may pay for expenses incurred by:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Program participants to obtain credentials to serve as healthcare workers in high-need healthcare careers, including the costs of education, training, transportation, and examinations; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Approved schools and training programs for providing education and training to Program participants.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>To participate in the Program, an applicant must:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be a citizen or permanent resident of the United States;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Submit a completed application, in such form and with such information and documentation as may be required by the Mayor; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Be selected for participation by the Mayor based upon:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The individual's relevant experience;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The individual's ability to successfully complete the necessary education, training, examination, and licensing, certification, or registration requirements to serve as a healthcare worker in a high-need healthcare career in the District;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The individual's ability to serve successfully as a healthcare worker in a high-need healthcare career;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The individual's commitment to serve as a healthcare worker in a high-need healthcare career in the District for at least 2 years following their licensure, certification, or registration as a healthcare worker; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Such other factors as the Mayor may establish, which may include preferential consideration for:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Residents of the District;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Applicants committed to enrolling in a school or training program located in the District;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Residents of a Health Professional Shortage Area or Medically Underserved Area, as those terms are defined in <cite path="§7-751.01|(4)">§ 7-751.01(4)</cite> and <cite path="§7-751.01|(5)">(5)</cite>);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>Applicants who are immediately eligible and available for education or training;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>Applicants who commit to serving as a healthcare worker in a high-need healthcare career in the District for more than 2 years;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vi)</num>
          <text>Applicants who are fluent in Spanish, Chinese, Vietnamese, Korean, French, or Amharic; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vii)</num>
          <text>Applicants demonstrating a desire to reside within the District.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Each applicant selected for participation in the Program shall enter into a contract with the District agreeing to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Complete the necessary education, training, and examinations to become a healthcare worker in a high-need healthcare career in the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Serve a minimum of 2 years as a healthcare worker in a high-need healthcare career in the District; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Provide such information and reports on the individual's participation in the Program as may be required by the District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The contract required by subsection (c) of this section may provide the District with specific remedies for a Program participant's breach of the contract, and the District shall have the general right to enforce the contract in law or equity.</text>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation applicability="effective" type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-791.02" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§7-791.02">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-313" path="">D.C. Law 24-313</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-313" path="§301">§ 301 of D.C. Law 24-313</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-313" path="§102">§ 102 of D.C. Law 24-313</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</codify:annotation>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-468" path="§102" codified:display="Note" app="2023-03-10" eff="2022-07-06">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-468" path="§102">§ 102 of High Need Healthcare Career Scholarship and Health Professional Loan Repayment Program Emergency Amendment Act of 2022 (D.C. Act 24-468, July 6, 2022, 69 DCR 008390)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Act 24-468" eff="2022-07-06" path="§102" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 24-184" path="§102" codified:display="Note" app="2023-03-10" eff="2022-09-21">For temporary (225 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-184" path="§102">§ 102 of High Need Healthcare Career Scholarship and Health Professional Loan Repayment Program Temporary Amendment Act of 2022 (D.C. Law 24-184, Sept. 21, 2022, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-184" eff="2022-09-21" path="§102" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-313" eff="2023-03-10" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-313" eff="2023-03-10" path="§102" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 24-313" path="§102" codified:display="Note" app="2023-03-10" eff="2023-03-10">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-313" path="">D.C. Law 24-313</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-313" path="§301">§ 301 of D.C. Law 24-313</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-313" path="§102">§ 102 of D.C. Law 24-313</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-50" path="§7093" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2023-09-06" eff="2023-09-06"><cite doc="D.C.Law 25-50" path="§7093">Section 7093 of D.C. Law 25-50</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-313" path="§301">section 301 of D.C. Law 24-313</cite> removing the applicability provision impacting this section.  Therefore the creation of this section by section 102 of Law 24-313 has been implemented.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-09-06" doc="D.C. Law 25-50" eff="2023-09-06" path="§7093" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
