<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-3875.06</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Review personnel qualifications.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A utilization review entity shall ensure that an adverse determination is made by a physician who:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Possesses a current and valid non-restricted license to practice medicine in the District, Maryland, or Virginia; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Is of the same or similar specialty as a physician who typically manages the medical condition or disease or provides the health care service involved in the request; provided, that a physician making an adverse determination for pediatric care shall have a pediatric specialty.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The reviewing physician shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Be under the clinical direction of one of the utilization review entity's medical directors licensed in the District who is responsible for providing health care services to enrollees in the District; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Not receive any financial incentive based on the number of adverse determinations made; except, that the utilization review entity may establish medically appropriate performance standards.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A utilization entity shall ensure that all appeals are reviewed by a physician who:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Possesses a current and valid non-restricted license to practice medicine in the District, Maryland, or Virginia;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Is of the same or similar specialty as a physician who typically manages the medical condition or disease or provides the health care service involved in the request; provided, that the physician reviewing an appeal for pediatric care shall have a pediatric specialty and practiced that specialty for at least 5 years; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Is knowledgeable of, and have experience providing, the health care service on appeal.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A physician reviewing an appeal shall not:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Receive any financial incentive based on the number of adverse determinations made or upheld on appeal; provided, that the utilization review entity may establish medically appropriate performance standards;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Have been directly involved in making the adverse determination; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Be subordinate of the physician who made the adverse determination.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2020-10-20" doc="D.C. Law 23-135" eff="2020-10-20" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-01-17" doc="D.C. Law 25-100" eff="2024-01-17" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-01-17" doc="D.C. Law 25-100" eff="2024-01-17" path="ยง106" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
