<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>32-1452</num>
  <heading>Prohibited actions of employer.</heading>
  <text>An employer shall not:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Require, as a condition of employment, that an employee refrain from inquiring about, disclosing, comparing, or otherwise discussing the employees compensation or the compensation of another employee;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Discharge, discipline, interfere with, negatively affect the terms and conditions of employment, or otherwise retaliate against an employee who inquires about, discloses, compares, or otherwise discusses the employee’s compensation or the compensation of another employee or is believed by the employer to have done so;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Prohibit or attempt to prohibit an employee from lodging a complaint, or testifying, assisting, or participating in an investigation or proceeding, related to a violation of this chapter;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Screen prospective employees based on their wage history, including by requiring that a prospective employee's wage history satisfy minimum or maximum criteria or by requesting or requiring as a condition of being interviewed or as a condition of continuing to be considered for an offer of employment that a prospective employee disclose the prospective employee's wage history; or</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Seek the wage history of a prospective employee from a person who previously employed the individual.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-219" type="History" path="§3">Mar. 11, 2015, D.C. Law 20-219, § 3, 62 DCR 9</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-03-05" doc="D.C. Law 25-138" eff="2024-03-05" path="§2|(b)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2024-03-05" doc="D.C. Law 25-138" eff="2024-03-05" path="§2|(b)|(2)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2024-03-05" doc="D.C. Law 25-138" eff="2024-03-05" path="§2|(b)|(2)|(B)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2024-03-05" doc="D.C. Law 25-138" eff="2024-03-05" path="§2|(b)|(2)|(C)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2024-03-05" doc="D.C. Law 25-138" eff="2024-03-05" path="§2|(b)|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2024-03-05" doc="D.C. Law 25-138" eff="2024-03-05" path="§2|(b)|(4)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
