<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-1071.03</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Outreach and public guidance.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall create template services contracts that hiring entities may use to comply with the requirements of <cite path="§32-1071.02">§ 32-1071.02</cite>. The Mayor shall publish the templates as specified in subsection (c) of this section in English, Spanish, and at least 5 other languages that are the most commonly spoken languages in the District.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall make the template services contracts electronically available within 90 days after the applicability date of this section, which a member of the public should be able to download, enter information electronically, print, and save the templates using a desktop computer, tablet, or smartphone.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No later than 180 calendar days after the applicability date of this section, the Office of the Attorney General shall award grants, pursuant to the requirements set forth in <cite path="1|3|XII-A|B">part B of subchapter XII-A of Chapter 3 of Title 1</cite>, to provide guidance to domestic workers and hiring entities about domestic workers' rights under <cite path="32|10B">this chapter</cite>. A grantee shall be a community-based organization with at least 2 years' experience working on behalf of domestic workers. Grantees shall use grants awarded under this subsection to do any combination of the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Based on the input of an expert or experts in the field of health and safety, develop guidance for domestic workers and hiring entities to address the most common hazards domestic workers encounter in their workplaces and how to mitigate them; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Conduct education and outreach to domestic workers, hiring entities, and the public about the rights of domestic workers.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>No later than 90 calendar days after the applicability date of this section, the Mayor shall publish on a website information in a plain, easy-to-read format for use by domestic workers, hiring entities, and the general public, which shall include:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The template services contracts created pursuant to subsection (a) of this section;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Instructions for how to use the templates;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Answers to commonly asked questions about <cite path="32|10B">this chapter</cite>'s requirements, which the Mayor shall create in consultation with domestic workers and hiring entities;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Information about the rights of domestic workers under:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The Human Rights Act of 1977 (<cite path="2|14">Chapter 14 of Title 2</cite>);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The Minimum Wage Revision Act of 1992 (<cite path="32|10">Chapter 10 of this title</cite>);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>The Accrued Sick and Safe Leave Act of 2008 (<cite path="32|5|III">subchapter III of Chapter 5 of this title</cite>);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>The Universal Paid Leave Amendment Act of 2016 (<cite path="32|5|IV">subchapter IV of Chapter 5 of this title</cite>);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>The Protecting Pregnant Workers Fairness Act of 2014 (<cite path="32|12A">Chapter 12A of this title</cite>);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vi)</num>
          <text>The Wage Payment Act (<cite path="32|13">Chapter 13 of this title</cite>);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vii)</num>
          <text>The District of Columbia Workers' Compensation Act of 1979 (<cite path="32|15">Chapter 15 of this title</cite>); and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(viii)</num>
          <text>The District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Act (<cite path="51|1">Chapter 1 of Title 51</cite>);</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Instructions about how to file a complaint and how to respond to a complaint under <cite path="32|10B">this chapter</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Links to resources provided by the United States Department of Labor regarding the rights of domestic workers;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>A list of resources detailing the federal and District obligations of hiring entities, including IRS Publication 926, Household Employer's Tax Guide or revisions or successor publications of this guide; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>When made available by the Office of the Attorney General, the safety guidance created pursuant to subsection (b) of this section.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The website shall provide the information required under paragraph (1) of this subsection in English, Spanish, and at least 5 other languages that are the most commonly spoken languages in the District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation applicability="effective" type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Code" path="§32-1071.03" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§32-1071.03">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-305" path="">D.C. Law 24-305</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-305" path="§401">§ 401 of D.C. Law 24-305</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-305" path="§103">§ 103 of D.C. Law 24-305</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</codify:annotation>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-305" eff="2023-03-10" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-305" eff="2023-03-10" path="§401|(a)|(1)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-305" eff="2023-03-10" path="§103" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 24-305" path="§103" codified:display="Note" app="2023-03-10" eff="2023-03-10">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-305" path="">D.C. Law 24-305</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-305" path="§401">§ 401 of D.C. Law 24-305</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-305" path="§103">§ 103 of D.C. Law 24-305</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-09-06" doc="D.C. Law 25-50" eff="2023-09-06" path="§7090|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-50" path="§7090|(a)" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2023-09-06" eff="2023-09-06"><cite doc="D.C.Law 25-50" path="§7090">Section 7090(a) of D.C. Law 25-50</cite> amended <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-305" path="§401">section 401 of D.C. Law 24-305</cite> changing the applicability provision impacting this section to October 1, 2023.  Therefore the creation of this section by Law 24-305 has been implemented.
        </annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
