<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-1071.02</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Services contracts and other requirements for hiring entities and referral agencies.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A hiring entity shall execute a services contract with a domestic worker no later than the first day a domestic worker is expected to perform work for a hiring entity, or, if the hiring entity employs or engages a domestic worker as of January 29, 2024, within 30 calendar days after January 29, 2024.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An executed services contract shall include:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The domestic worker's start date;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>If known, the end date of contract;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The address where work will usually be performed or the business address that the hiring entity registered with the Department of Licensing and Consumer Protection;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The primary contact information for the hiring entity, including a telephone number;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>The duties to be performed by the domestic worker;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>The rate of pay per hour, week, or other unit of time, specifying for domestic workers who are employees the rate per hour and overtime rate;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>The form, place, and frequency of payment;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>The date first payment will be provided;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(I)</num>
        <text>The weekly schedule, including days of the week, start time, end time, and number of hours of work per week;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(J)</num>
        <text>If the domestic worker will be provided with rest breaks or meal breaks, the customary practice or time;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(K)</num>
        <text>Types of leave from work provided and whether paid or unpaid;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(L)</num>
        <text>Any other compensation or reimbursement provided by the hiring entity, such as health insurance premiums, transportation allowance, or separation pay;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(M)</num>
        <text>Whether the domestic worker must provide their own vehicle for the fulfillment of work duties; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(N)</num>
        <text>For live-in domestic workers, a description of the type and value of lodging provided, time of sleeping period, and personal time allotment.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If any of the provisions required pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection do not apply to the relationship between a hiring entity and domestic worker, the hiring entity shall specify in the services contract the provisions that do not apply.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A hiring entity and domestic worker may execute a services contract in identical documents; which identical documents shall have the same force and effect as a single document bearing the signatures of all parties.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>When one or more of the terms of a services contract permanently changes, the parties shall modify the existing services contract or execute a new services contract.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Recipients of shared services shall jointly execute a services contract with the domestic worker that complies with this subsection.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A services contract shall not:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Require the domestic worker to waive any provision of <cite path="32|10B">this chapter</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Prohibit, punish, interfere with, or have the effect of deterring the domestic worker from filing a complaint or cooperating with an investigation under <cite path="32|10B">this chapter</cite>; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Contain a non-compete provision to the extent prohibited in <cite path="32|5B">Chapter 5B of this title</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A provision in an executed services contract that paragraph (1) of this subsection prohibits shall be void as a matter of law.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A hiring entity shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Make reasonable efforts to provide a domestic worker with a translation of a services contract in the domestic worker's preferred language; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Retain a true and accurate copy of an executed services contract with a domestic worker and other records made or kept in relation to <cite path="32|10B">this chapter</cite> pursuant to rules promulgated pursuant to <cite path="§32-1071.05">§ 32-1071.05</cite> for no less than 3 years and as long as may be required by other applicable District law.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In determining whether a hiring entity made reasonable efforts to provide the translated services contract pursuant to paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection, a factfinder shall consider whether the Mayor has made template agreements available in the domestic worker's preferred language, the other resources available to the hiring entity to obtain a translation, the time the hiring entity spent attempting to obtain translation services, the complexity of the information in need of translation, and other relevant factors.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A hiring entity may not discharge, threaten, penalize, or in any other manner retaliate against a domestic worker because the hiring entity believes or because the domestic worker in fact:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Alleged a violation of <cite path="32|10B">this chapter</cite> that the domestic worker reasonably believes to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A hiring entity;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Mayor;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The Attorney General; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Another person that the hiring entity has employed or engaged.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Participated in or cooperated with an action by the Mayor or Attorney General under <cite path="32|10B">this chapter</cite>; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Otherwise exercised a right pursuant to <cite path="32|10B">this chapter</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>A referral agency shall notify domestic workers and hiring entities about the requirements of this section whenever the referral agency provides services to a hiring entity or a domestic worker.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Hiring entities that receive services under the same services contract are jointly and severally liable for violations of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>Unless otherwise specified in an executed services contract, no provision of the contract may be interpreted to limit or prohibit either party from terminating the employment or engagement at-will.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>A services contract that complies with this section shall be deemed to satisfy an employer's obligations pursuant to the requirements of <cite path="§32-1008|(c)">§ 32-1008(c)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(j)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to mean that a hiring entity or a domestic worker may not include other lawful terms in a services contract.</text>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation applicability="effective" type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Code" path="§32-1071.02" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§32-1071.02">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-305" path="">D.C. Law 24-305</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-305" path="§401">§ 401 of D.C. Law 24-305</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-305" path="§102">§ 102 of D.C. Law 24-305</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</codify:annotation>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-305" eff="2023-03-10" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-305" eff="2023-03-10" path="§401|(a)|(2)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-305" eff="2023-03-10" path="§102" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 24-305" path="§102" codified:display="Note" app="2023-03-10" eff="2023-03-10">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-305" path="">D.C. Law 24-305</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-305" path="§401">§ 401 of D.C. Law 24-305</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-305" path="§102">§ 102 of D.C. Law 24-305</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-09-06" doc="D.C. Law 25-50" eff="2023-09-06" path="§7090|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-50" path="§7090|(b)" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2023-09-06" eff="2023-09-06"><cite doc="D.C.Law 25-50" path="§7090">Section 7090(b) of D.C. Law 25-50</cite> amended <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-305" path="§401">section 401 of D.C. Law 24-305</cite> changing the applicability provision impacting this section to January 29, 2024.  Therefore the creation of this section by Law 24-305 shall be applicable January 29, 2024.
        </annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
