<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-246</num>
  <heading>DC Infrastructure Academy.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In addition to duties the Mayor prescribes, the DCIA shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Provide occupational skills training ("skills training") annually in industries for which there is significant demand regionally or by a major employer, including construction, infrastructure, and information technology;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Provide occupational skills training designed to meet the needs of employers by:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Aligning skills training, where appropriate, with the annual recommendations the committees submit to the DCIA pursuant to <cite path="§32-247|(c)">§ 32-247(c)</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Submitting a proposed curriculum, at least 30 calendar days prior to the start of any skills training taught by DCIA staff, to the relevant committee for its feedback; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Taking into consideration any feedback from a committee when implementing any skills trainings taught by DCIA staff;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Submitting to the relevant committee, at least 30 calendar days before soliciting applications or bids on a grant or contract to provide skills training, a request that the committee review a grant or contract solicitation's proposed scope of work; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Considering any feedback received from a committee when preparing statements of work for grants and contracts to provide skills training; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>For any customized skills training provided specifically for a particular employer, seeking input from the employer consistent with the requirements outlined in subparagraphs (B) and (C) of this paragraph;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Provide test preparation sessions and practice exams to ready participants to obtain the occupational credentials the committees identify in their annual reports pursuant to <cite path="§32-247|(c)">§ 32-247(c)</cite>(4) [§ 32-247(b)]; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Provide job referrals, as defined in 20 C.F.R. § 651.10, to employers in the industry sectors in which training is offered pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection for all qualified graduates of DCIA training programs.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>DCIA skills training may include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Training services enumerated in section 134(c)(3)(D) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act, approved July 22, 2014 (128 Stat. 1529; 29 U.S.C. § 3174(c)(3)(D));</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Supportive services, as defined in 20 C.F.R. § 651.10;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Integrated education and training, as defined in 34 C.F.R. § 463.35;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Workforce preparation activities, as defined in 34 C.F.R. § 463.34; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Job development, as defined in 20 C.F.R. § 651.10.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>At least 66% of the participants receiving skills training through the DCIA each fiscal year shall be trained in occupations that pay an average wage that is at least 150% of the minimum wage specified in <cite path="§32-1003">§ 32-1003</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>At least 25% of the value of each grant or contract with a skills training provider shall be contingent on the provider achieving at least one of the following results:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>At least 75% of the provider's participants receive an industry-recognized credential; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>At least 80% of the provider's participants enter permanent, unsubsidized employment in the occupation of training.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In Fiscal Year 2023, the DCIA shall administer a Commercial Driver's License ("CDL") mass transportation pipeline pilot program ("pilot program") that will train and support District residents to work toward employment with local mass transportation agencies such as the Washington Metropolitan Area Transportation Authority ("WMATA").</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To implement the pilot program, DCIA shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Screen candidates for their suitability to receive a CDL and be hired as bus drivers with mass transportation agencies;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Train candidates to receive a CDL or refer candidates to external training based on candidates' suitability;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Provide candidates with assistance completing CDL applications and applying for employment with local mass transportation agencies, including through:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Resume development;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Employment-readiness skills development; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Interview preparation; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Recruit candidates for the pilot program.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>DCIA shall select candidates to participate in the pilot program through suitability screening that will ensure participants have a high likelihood of being hired by local mass transportation agencies. Screening may include a criminal background check, screening for use of drugs and alcohol, or a review of participants' driving, employment, or medical records.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>DCIA shall train or refer participants to external training with local mass transportation agencies based on participants' suitability and qualifications.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>DCIA's CDL training program may be facilitated by DCIA staff or through contracts with training providers. DCIA may coordinate with mass transportation agencies to obtain vehicles or other training materials to create new or expand existing CDL training.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>DCIA shall provide CDL test preparation assistance for all participants who receive DCIA-administered CDL training. This assistance may include:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Working with the Department of Motor Vehicles to schedule tests;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Leading and facilitating test preparation sessions;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Educating participants on test-taking strategies; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Providing support to participants with test performance anxiety.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>DCIA shall launch a Districtwide campaign to recruit participants for the pilot program. Recruitment shall include outreach to American Job Center visitors and current and past participants of DOES programs including the DCIA, Project Empowerment, DC Career Connections, Pathways for Young Adults, and the Marion Barry Summer Youth Employment Program. Recruitment may also include outreach to adult education programs and District residents who are drivers with ridesharing companies.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>DCIA may accept a candidate who is deemed unsuitable for employment with a mass transportation agency due to a candidate's failure to pass drug or alcohol screening into the pilot program to receive DCIA-administered CDL training if DCIA determines that the candidate would likely be able to pass drug and alcohol screening in the future. DCIA may provide such participants with support or referrals to community services to address substance abuse concerns.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>"CDL" means a commercial driver's license issued by the District of Columbia or other jurisdiction, in accordance with the federal regulations, 49 CFR Part 383, to an individual that authorizes the individual to operate a class of commercial vehicle.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>"Mass transportation agency" means a government, quasi-government, or privately owned agency that transports the public by bus, train, trolly, streetcar, shuttle, or other means; which agencies may include WMATA, the DC Circulator, or the DC Streetcar.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Department of Employment Services funds may be used to purchase food and non-alcoholic beverages for participants receiving DCIA skills training, when the purchase is reasonably necessary to assist in the effective achievement of a statutorily authorized goal, objective, or responsibility.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-46" type="History" path="§2e">Jan. 5, 1980, D.C. Law 3-46, § 2e</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-12-03" doc="D.C. Law 23-149" eff="2020-12-03" path="§2082|(c)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-470" path="§4082" codified:display="Note" app="2022-07-13" eff="2022-07-13">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-470" path="§4082">§ 4082 of Fiscal Year 2023 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2022 (D.C. Act 24-470, July 13, 2022, 69 DCR 008707)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2022-07-13" doc="D.C. Act 24-470" eff="2022-07-13" path="§4082" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2022-09-21" doc="D.C. Law 24-167" eff="2022-09-21" path="§4082" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-09-06" doc="D.C. Law 25-50" eff="2023-09-06" path="§4173|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
