<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>44-665.11</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Definitions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of <cite path="44|6A|X">this subchapter</cite>, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Department" means the Department of Health Care Finance.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"District retention" means an amount equal to 13.125% of the fees collected pursuant to <cite path="§44-665.13|(a)|(1)">§ 44-665.13(a)(1)</cite>, plus the salary and fringe benefits for one full-time equivalent staff position at the Department.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Fund" means the Outpatient Hospital Directed Payment Provider Fee Fund established by <cite path="44|6A|X">this subchapter</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Hospital" shall have the same meaning as provided in <cite path="§44-501|(a)|(9)">§ 44-501(a)(9)</cite>; except, that the term "hospital" shall not include a hospital operated by the federal government.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Hospital system" means a group of hospitals licensed separately, but operated, owned, or maintained by a common entity.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"Medicaid" means the medical assistance programs authorized by Title XIX of the Social Security Act, approved July 30, 1965 (79 Stat. 343; 42 U.S.C. § 1396 <em>et seq.</em>), and by <cite path="§1-307.02">§ 1-307.02</cite>, and administered by the Department.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>"Outpatient gross patient revenue" means the amount that is reported in column 2 of line 28 of Worksheet G-2 of the hospital's most recently available Hospital and Hospital Health Care Complex Cost Report ("Form CMS 2552-10").</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, for a hospital that has not yet filed its first Form CMS-2552-10, the term "outpatient gross patient revenue" shall mean a dollar value determined by the Department, based on projected utilization volume and projected utilization migration from other area hospitals, that approximates the hospital's expected outpatient gross patient revenue.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>"State directed payment" means a Medicaid managed care delivery system and provider payment initiative authorized under 42 C.F.R § 438.6(c).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-506" path="§5032" codified:display="Note" app="2024-09-18" eff="2024-07-15">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-506" path="§5032">§ 5032 of Fiscal Year 2025 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-506, July 15, 2024, 71 DCR 8406)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Act 25-506" eff="2024-07-15" path="§5032" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Law 25-217" eff="2024-09-18" path="V|D" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Law 25-217" eff="2024-09-18" path="§5032" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
