<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>44-665.06</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Quarterly notice and collection.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The fee imposed under <cite path="§44-665.03">§ 44-665.03</cite> shall be calculated on a quarterly basis and shall be due and payable by the 15th day after the last month of each quarter; provided, that the fee shall not be due and payable until:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The District issues written notice that the payment methodologies for payments to hospitals required under <cite path="§44-665.05">§ 44-665.05</cite> have been approved by the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The District issues written notice to the hospital informing the hospital of its fee rate, inpatient net patient revenue subject to the fee, and the fee amount owed on a quarterly basis, including, in the initial written notice from the District to the hospital, all fee amounts owed beginning with the period commencing on October 1, 2024.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If a hospital fails to pay the full amount of the fee in accordance with <cite path="44|6A|IX">this subchapter</cite>, the unpaid balance shall accrue interest at the rate of 1.5% per month or any fraction thereof, which shall be added to the unpaid balance.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Chief Financial Officer may arrange a payment plan for the amount of the fee and interest in arrears.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-506" path="§5027" codified:display="Note" app="2024-09-18" eff="2024-07-15">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-506" path="§5027">§ 5027 of Fiscal Year 2025 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-506, July 15, 2024, 71 DCR 8406)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Act 25-506" eff="2024-07-15" path="§5027" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Law 25-217" eff="2024-09-18" path="V|C" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Law 25-217" eff="2024-09-18" path="§5027" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
