<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>44-665.12</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Outpatient Hospital Directed Payment Provider Fee Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Outpatient Hospital Directed Payment Provider Fee Fund, which shall be administered by the Department in accordance with subsections (c) and (d) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Revenue from the following sources shall be deposited in the Fund:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Fees collected under <cite path="44|6A|X">this subchapter</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Interest and penalties collected under <cite path="44|6A|X">this subchapter</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Money in the Fund shall be used only for the following purposes:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Making separate payments to Medicaid managed care organizations to fund Medicaid outpatient hospital directed payments to hospitals as required under <cite path="§44-665.15">§ 44-665.15</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Providing refunds to hospitals pursuant to <cite path="§44-665.14">§ 44-665.14</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Through the District retention:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Paying the salary and fringe benefits of one full-time equivalent staff position at the Department;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Funding the local match for Medicaid fee-for-service hospital reimbursements;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Funding <cite path="31|38F">Chapter 38F of Title 31</cite>, using an amount from the District retention equal to 1.125% of the fees collected under <cite path="44|6A|X">this subchapter</cite>; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Making a transfer to Local Funds in an amount not to exceed 13.125% of the fees collected under <cite path="44|6A|X">this subchapter</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (c)(3)(D) of this section, the money deposited into the Fund shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-506" path="§5033" codified:display="Note" app="2024-09-18" eff="2024-07-15">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-506" path="§5033">§ 5033 of Fiscal Year 2025 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-506, July 15, 2024, 71 DCR 8406)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Act 25-506" eff="2024-07-15" path="§5033" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Law 25-217" eff="2024-09-18" path="V|D" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Law 25-217" eff="2024-09-18" path="§5033" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
