<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>44-665.07</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Multi-hospital systems, closure, merger, and new hospitals.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If a hospital system owns, operates, or maintains more than one hospital licensed by the Department of Health, the hospital system shall pay the fee for each hospital separately.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding any other provision in <cite path="44|6A|IX">this subchapter</cite>, if a hospital system or person ceases to own, operate, or maintain a hospital that is subject to a fee under <cite path="§44-665.03">§ 44-665.03</cite>, as evidenced by the transfer or surrender of the hospital license, the fee for the fiscal year in which the cessation occurs shall be adjusted by multiplying the fee computed under <cite path="§44-665.03">§ 44-665.03</cite> by a fraction, the numerator of which is the number of days in the year during which the hospital system or person conducted, operated, or maintained the hospital, and the denominator of which is 365.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Within 15 days after ceasing to own, operate, or maintain a hospital, the hospital system or person shall pay the fee for the year as so adjusted, to the extent not previously paid.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-506" path="§5028" codified:display="Note" app="2024-09-18" eff="2024-07-15">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-506" path="§5028">§ 5028 of Fiscal Year 2025 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-506, July 15, 2024, 71 DCR 8406)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Act 25-506" eff="2024-07-15" path="§5028" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Law 25-217" eff="2024-09-18" path="V|C" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Law 25-217" eff="2024-09-18" path="§5028" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
