<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>44-665.03</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Inpatient hospital directed payment provider fee.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The District may charge each hospital a fee based on its inpatient net patient revenue. The fee shall be charged at a uniform rate among all hospitals.  The rate of the fee shall be established by the Department and generate an amount equal to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The non-federal share of the quarterly inpatient hospital directed payment, consistent with the applicable State directed payment preprint approved by the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The District retention.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If the Department calculates the fee under subsection (a) based in part on the inpatient net patient revenue of a new hospital that has not yet filed its first Hospital and Hospital Health Care Complex Cost Report ("Form CMS-2552-10"), the Department shall, after the hospital files its first Form CMS-2552-10:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Adjust the fee retroactively based on the inpatient net patient revenue of the new hospital using the calculation provided by <cite path="§44-665.01|(7)|(A)">§ 44-665.01(7)(A)</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Bill the new hospital for any difference in amount owed, if any; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Retroactively adjust the fees charged to all other hospitals to account for the change in the new hospital's fee obligations.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the following hospitals shall be exempt from the fee imposed under subsection (a) of this subsection:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A psychiatric hospital that is an agency or a unit of the District government;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Howard University Hospital.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If an exemption provided to a hospital by paragraph (1) of this subsection is not approved for a provider tax waiver from the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (if such waiver is determined to be necessary), the hospital shall be subject to the fee imposed under subsection (a) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-506" path="§5024" codified:display="Note" app="2024-09-18" eff="2024-07-15">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-506" path="§5024">§ 5024 of Fiscal Year 2025 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-506, July 15, 2024, 71 DCR 8406)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Act 25-506" eff="2024-07-15" path="§5024" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Law 25-217" eff="2024-09-18" path="V|C" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Law 25-217" eff="2024-09-18" path="§5024" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
