<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1461.01</num>
  <heading proof="needed">District government nonparticipation in interstate investigations and proceedings interfering with certain rights.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The District and its officers and employees acting in their official capacities shall not provide any information or expend or use time, money, facilities, property, equipment, personnel, or other resources in furtherance of any interstate investigation or proceeding seeking to impose civil or criminal liability upon any person for the following conduct, or for attempting, aiding, abetting, advising, facilitating, or intending or conspiring to achieve the following conduct, except to the extent that such conduct would be prohibited under District law:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Receiving or seeking an abortion or contraception;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Performing or inducing an abortion with the voluntary consent of the pregnant person;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Engaging in sexual conduct;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Providing contraception to an entity or to an individual with that individual's voluntary consent;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Using contraception;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Entering into or remaining in a living arrangement, marriage, domestic partnership, or civil union; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Providing, consenting to, receiving, or facilitating gender-affirming care.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A person claiming to be aggrieved by a violation of this section shall have a cause of action in any court of competent jurisdiction for damages and such other remedies as may be appropriate. An action pursuant to this subsection shall be filed in a court of competent jurisdiction within 2 years of the violation, or the discovery of the violation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Contraception" shall have the same meaning as provided in <cite path="§2-1401.02|(4A)">§ 2-1401.02(4A)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Domestic partnership" shall have the same meaning as provided in <cite path="§2-1401.02|(7B)">§ 2-1401.02(7B)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Gender-affirming care" shall have the same meaning as provided in <cite path="§2-1401.02|(12A)">§ 2-1401.02(12A)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Living arrangement" shall have the same meaning as provided in <cite path="§2-1401.02|(15A)">§ 2-1401.02(15A)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Person" shall have the same meaning as provided in <cite path="§2-1401.02|(21)">§ 2-1401.02(21)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-257" eff="2023-02-23" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-257" eff="2023-02-23" path="§101" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
