<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1461.02</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Private right of action for use of courts to interfere with exercise in the District of certain rights.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person who has had a judgment entered against him or her, in any jurisdiction, where liability is based in whole or in part on the person's alleged conduct of a type identified in <cite path="§2-1461.01|(a)">§ 2-1461.01(a)</cite>, including under any theory of vicarious, joint, several or conspiracy liability, shall have a cause of action and may recover damages from any party that brought the action leading to that judgment or that has sought to enforce that judgment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Recoverable damages under this section shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Just damages created by the action that led to that judgment, including money damages in the amount of the judgment and costs, expenses, and reasonable attorney's fees spent in defending the action that resulted in the entry of a judgment in another jurisdiction; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Costs, expenses, and reasonable attorney's fees incurred in bringing an action under this section, as may be allowed by the court.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall be interpreted to enable a court to vacate, render invalid, or otherwise disturb a judgment giving rise to an action under this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The provisions of this section shall not create a cause of action based on a judgment entered in another jurisdiction that resulted from:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An action founded in tort, contract, or statute for which a similar claim would exist under the laws of the District; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An action where no part of the acts that formed the basis for liability occurred in the District, the person subject to the earlier judgement does not reside or have its primary place of business in the District, and the injury caused by the judgement did not occur in the District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "person" shall have the same meaning as provided in <cite path="§2-1401.02|(21)">§ 2-1401.02(21)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-257" eff="2023-02-23" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-257" eff="2023-02-23" path="§102" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
