<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-1403.15</num>
  <heading>Enforcement of order.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The decision and order of the Commission shall be served on the respondent, with notice that, if the Commission determines that the respondent has not, after 30 calendar days following service of its order, corrected the unlawful discriminatory practice and complied with the order, the Commission will certify the matter to the Attorney General, and to such other agencies as may be appropriate for enforcement.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>When the Commission certifies a matter to the Attorney General for enforcement, the Attorney General shall, in the Attorney General's sole discretion, assess the matter to determine whether the order may be enforced.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the order is enforceable, the Attorney General shall institute, in the name of the District, civil proceedings, including the seeking of such restraining orders and temporary or permanent injunctions as are necessary to obtain complete compliance with the Commission's orders.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>[(3)]</num>
      <text>If civil proceedings instituted pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection do not result in securing such compliance, the Attorney General may institute criminal action.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>No enforcement action shall be instituted pending review as provided in <cite path="§2-1403.14">§ 2-1403.14</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to deprive any person of rights in the criminal justice process.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-38" type="History" path="§315">Dec. 13, 1977, D.C. Law 2-38, title III, § 315, 24 DCR 6038</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-2295.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-2555.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§2-1403.17">§ 2-1403.17</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-295" eff="2023-03-10" path="§2|(f)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-295" eff="2023-03-10" path="§2|(f)|(2)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
