<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>34-1436.01</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Triennial study of local solar policy benefits and costs.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The People's Counsel shall commission a recurring study to assess the benefits and costs of the solar requirements in <cite path="34|14A">this chapter</cite> as well as the technical and economic potential of solar energy generation in the District. The study shall address, at a minimum, the:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Benefits of locally produced solar energy to the District's electrical grid and the District's clean energy goals (including the Solar for All program);</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Need for and potential costs of system upgrades and programs by ward; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Costs to ratepayers of the Renewable Energy Portfolio Standards' solar energy requirements.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The study shall also compare the District's local solar energy policies to policies supporting the expansion of solar resources in other jurisdictions.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>By no later than October 1, 2027, the People's Counsel shall submit a complete copy of the study, and, based on the results of the study, offer recommendations regarding legislative and regulatory changes to ensure that ratepayers are not unduly impacted ("initial submission").</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The People's Counsel shall submit updated findings and recommendations every 3 years after the initial submission.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-340" type="History" path="§8a">Apr. 12, 2005, D.C. Law 15-340, § 8a</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-314" eff="2023-03-10" path="§2|(d)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-314" path="§3" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2023-03-10" eff="2023-03-10"><cite doc="D.C. Law 24-314" path="§3">Section 3 of D.C. Law 24-314</cite> provided that for 3 years after the date described in section 4, section 2(a) shall not apply to any contract entered into before the date described in subsection (a) of this section; except, that section 2(a) shall apply to an extension or renewal of such a contract.
    </annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-314" eff="2023-03-10" path="§3" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-314" path="§4" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2023-03-10" eff="2023-03-10"><cite doc="D.C. Law 24-314" path="§4">Section 4 of D.C. Law 24-314</cite> provided that this act shall apply as of March 1, 2023, or as of the effective date of this act, whichever occurs later.
    </annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-314" eff="2023-03-10" path="§4" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation path="§8002|(f)" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2023-09-06" eff="2023-09-06" doc="D.C. Law 25-50">
          For a technical correction to section 3 of D.C. Law 24-314, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-50" path="§8002|(f)">section 8002(f) of D.C. Law 25-50</cite>.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-09-06" doc="D.C. Law 25-50" eff="2023-09-06" path="§8002|(f)" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
