<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>48-652</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Restrictions on third-party meals delivery platforms.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A third-party meal delivery platform shall not arrange for the delivery of an order from a restaurant without first obtaining an agreement with the restaurant expressly authorizing the third-party meal delivery platform to collect meal orders and deliver meals prepared by the restaurant.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An agreement shall not include any provision, clause, or covenant that requires a restaurant to indemnify a third-party meal delivery platform, any independent contractor acting on behalf of the third-party meal delivery platform, or any registered agent of the third-party meal delivery service for any damages or harm that may occur after the restaurant's product leaves the restaurant.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A third-party meal delivery platform shall not advertise or otherwise market a telephone number, website, or application software featuring or marketing a restaurant without an agreement.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Upon expiration or termination of an agreement, the third-party meal delivery platform shall transfer and assign any telephone number and URL for a website used exclusively to advertise or market the restaurant to the restaurant for the restaurant's use.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A third-party meal delivery platform that does not have an agreement shall not use the name, likeness, trademark, or intellectual property of a restaurant on its platform.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Any agreement that a third-party meal delivery platform enters into with a restaurant must contain a provision allowing a food delivery worker to use the restroom facilities of the restaurant when performing a delivery or pickup service at the restaurant.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>A third-party meal delivery platform shall not exclude any restaurant with whom the third-party meal delivery platform has an agreement from the relevant search results of a customer within 4 miles of a restaurant.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>A third-party meal delivery platform shall not reduce the delivery radius of any restaurant below 4 miles based on the level or percentage of commissions paid. Nothing in this section shall prohibit a third-party meal delivery platform from offering a larger delivery radius for a fee.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>A third-party meal delivery platform shall not reduce the number of food delivery workers available to deliver online orders from a restaurant with whom the third-party meal delivery platform has an agreement based solely on the level or percentage of commission paid. Nothing in this section shall prohibit a third-party meal delivery platform from offering priority delivery services for a fee.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-591" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2023-03-10" eff="2022-10-25">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-591" path="§2">§ 2 of Fair Meals Delivery Emergency Act of 2022 (D.C. Act 24-591, Oct. 25, 2022, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Act 24-591" eff="2022-10-25" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-292" eff="2023-03-10" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-292" eff="2023-03-10" path="§3" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-108" path="§2|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2023-05-24" eff="2023-05-24">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-108" path="§2|(c)">§ 2(c) of Food Delivery Fees Transparency Emergency Amendment Act of 2023 (D.C. Act 25-108, May 24, 2023, 70 DCR 7927)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-05-24" doc="D.C. Act 25-108" eff="2023-05-24" path="§2|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-199" path="§2|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2023-07-26" eff="2023-07-26">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-199" path="§2|(c)">§ 2(c) of Food Delivery Fees Transparency Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2023 (D.C. Act 25-199, July 26, 2023, 70 DCR 10748)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-07-26" doc="D.C. Act 25-199" eff="2023-07-26" path="§2|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 25-38" path="§2|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2023-08-17" eff="2023-08-17">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-38" path="§2|(c)">§ 2(c) of Food Delivery Fees Transparency Temporary Amendment Act of 2023 (D.C. Law 25-38, Aug. 17, 2023, 70 DCR 9412)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-08-17" doc="D.C. Law 25-38" eff="2023-08-17" path="§2|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-423" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2024-03-25" eff="2024-03-25">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-423" path="§2">§ 2 of Food Delivery Fees Transparency Emergency Amendment Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-423, Mar. 25, 2024, 71 DCR 3515)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-03-25" doc="D.C. Act 25-423" eff="2024-03-25" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-05-21" doc="D.C. Law 25-162" eff="2024-05-21" path="§301|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
