<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>48-652</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Restrictions on third-party meals delivery platforms.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A third-party meal delivery platform shall not arrange for the delivery of an order from a restaurant without first obtaining an agreement with the restaurant expressly authorizing the third-party meal delivery platform to collect meal orders and deliver meals prepared by the restaurant.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An agreement shall not include any provision, clause, or covenant that requires a restaurant to indemnify a third-party meal delivery platform, any independent contractor acting on behalf of the third-party meal delivery platform, or any registered agent of the third-party meal delivery service for any damages or harm that may occur after the restaurant's product leaves the restaurant.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A third-party meal delivery platform shall not advertise or otherwise market a telephone number, website, or application software featuring or marketing a restaurant without an agreement.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Upon expiration or termination of an agreement, the third-party meal delivery platform shall transfer and assign any telephone number and URL for a website used exclusively to advertise or market the restaurant to the restaurant for the restaurant's use.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A third-party meal delivery platform that does not have an agreement shall not use the name, likeness, trademark, or intellectual property of a restaurant on its platform.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-591" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2023-03-10" eff="2022-10-25">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-591" path="§2">§ 2 of Fair Meals Delivery Emergency Act of 2022 (D.C. Act 24-591, Oct. 25, 2022, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Act 24-591" eff="2022-10-25" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-292" eff="2023-03-10" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-292" eff="2023-03-10" path="§3" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
