<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>48-855.02b</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Calculation of member's contributions for a prescription drug covered under the health benefit plan.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (b) of this section, when calculating a member's contribution to their coinsurance, copayment, cost-sharing responsibility, deductible, or out-of-pocket maximum under the member's health benefit plan, the health insurer shall  include any discount, financial assistance payment, product voucher, or any other out-of-pocket expense made by or on behalf of the member for a prescription drug covered under the member's health benefit plan that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Is without a generic drug equivalent or an interchangeable biological product preferred under the health benefit plan's formulary; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Has a generic equivalent drug or an interchangeable biological product preferred under the health benefit plan's formulary where the member has obtained access to the drug through prior authorization, a step therapy protocol, or the exception or appeal process of the health insurer or pharmacy benefits manager.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subsection (a) of this section shall not apply to a member covered by a high deductible health plan, as that term is defined under 26 U.S.C. § 223, until the member satisfies their minimum deductible; except, that subsection (a) of this section shall apply to contribution amounts made for preventative care, as that term is defined under 26 U.S.C. § 223(c)(2)(C).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>This section shall apply to health benefit plans entered into, amended, extended, or renewed on or after January 1, 2025.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-248" type="History" path="§3b">Apr. 17, 2017, D.C. Law 21-248, § 3b</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-04-07" doc="D.C. Law 21-248" eff="2017-04-07" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-07-20" doc="D.C. Law 25-26" eff="2023-07-20" path="§2|(b)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
