<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>25-131</num>
  <heading>Commercial lifestyle center license.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A CLC license may be issued to a commercial owners' association governing a commercial lifestyle center.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A CLC license shall permit a licensed restaurant, tavern, nightclub, hotel, or multipurpose facility, including a private club, that is a tenant of the commercial lifestyle center ("center facility") to sell beer, wine, or spirits for consumption on the portion of the licensed premises designated by the Board, including a plaza, seating area, concourses, walkways, and other such thoroughfares.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A holder of a CLC license shall be permitted to allow a patron to consume beer, wine, or spirits purchased from a center facility on the premises of any tenant of the commercial lifestyle center, excluding a parking lot, that is not a retail establishment licensed by the Board upon approval of the tenant.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Board shall give notice of the CLC license application pursuant to <cite path="§25-421">§ 25-421</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A holder of a CLC license shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be located in a commercial or mixed-use zone area as defined by the Board of Zoning Adjustment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Prohibit persons from consuming alcoholic beverages within the commercial lifestyle center that were not purchased from a center facility;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Require a center facility to place the beer, wine, or spirits provided to consumers in reusable containers that are distributed and recollected through a deposit-refund system, and subsequently sanitized, which may be provided through third-party reusable food service ware providers, as defined by <cite path="§8-1531|(9)">§ 8-1531(9)</cite>, for reuse;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Demonstrate in its CLC license application how the center facility plans to acquire reusable containers, sanitize the containers, and ensure the containers are reused.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Require that each tenant in the center facility has an identifying mark on their reusable containers distinguished from all other tenants as approved by and registered with ABCA.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Post appropriate signage identifying the boundaries of the licensed facility center;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Have adequate security for the licensed facility center to ensure compliance with <cite path="25">this title</cite> and Title 23 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Have adequate trash receptacles on the licensed premises and ensure the licensed premises is free of trash and other debris that may attract rats and other vermin.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If the Department of Energy and Environment determines that the licensee has failed to serve a beverage in a reusable container, the Department of Energy and Environment shall impose a penalty on the licensee.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The penalty required under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be a class 4 infraction under the Schedule of Fines in section 3201 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (16 DCMR § 3201), pursuant to <cite path="2|18">§ 2-1801.01</cite> <em>et seq.</em> ("Civil Infractions Act").  Adjudication of any infraction shall be pursuant to the <cite path="2|18">Civil Infractions Act</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>There shall be 2 classes of CLC licenses, which will be the:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Class C/L (spirits, beer, and wine); and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Class D/L (beer and wine).".</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>Within 180 days of [June 30, 2022], the Board shall issue rules clarifying the parameters of the authority of private security in carrying out their duties while working the licensed premises of a center facility.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2022-06-30" doc="D.C. Law 24-127" eff="2022-06-30" path="§2|(a)|(10)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-22" doc="D.C. Law 24-332" eff="2023-03-22" path="§5|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-22" doc="D.C. Law 24-332" eff="2023-03-22" path="§5|(b)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-22" doc="D.C. Law 24-332" eff="2023-03-22" path="§5|(c)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
