<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>25-343</num>
  <heading>Special restrictions for off-premises retailer’s license in Ward 8.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term “Ward 8” means the area defined as Ward VIII in <cite path="§1-1041.03|(a)">§ 1-1041.03(a)</cite> on [August 15, 2008].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A licensee under an off-premises retailer’s license in Ward 8, class A or B, shall not divide a manufacturer’s package of more than one container of beer, malt liquor, or ale, to sell an individual container of the package if the capacity of the individual container is 70 ounces or less.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b-1)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding subsection (b) of this section, the holder of a retailer license, class B, that meets the definition of a full-service grocery store as set forth in <cite path="§25-101|(22A)">§ 25-101(22A)</cite>, or a 25% grocery store retailer license, class A, as set forth in <cite path="§25-333|(f)">§ 25-333(f)</cite>, in Ward 8 shall be allowed to divide a manufacturer's package of more than one container of beer, malt liquor, or ale to sell an individual container of the package that is 70 ounces or less.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the election ward boundaries in effect from January 1, 2012, through December 31, 2021, apply to the ward referenced in this subsection.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A licensee under an off-premises retailer’s license in Ward 8, class A or B, shall not sell, give, offer, expose for sale, or deliver an individual container of beer, malt liquor, or ale with a capacity of 70 ounces or less.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding subsection (c) of this section, the holder of a retailer license, class B, that meets the definition of a full-service grocery store as defined in <cite path="§25-101|(22A)">§ 25-101(22A)</cite>, or a 25% grocery store retailer license, class A, as set forth in <cite path="§25-333|(f)">§ 25-333(f)</cite>, in Ward 8 shall be allowed to sell, give, offer, expose for sale, or deliver an individual container of beer, malt liquor, or ale with a capacity of 70 ounces or less.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the election ward boundaries in effect from January 1, 2012, through December 31, 2021, apply to the ward referenced in this subsection.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The restrictions set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of this section shall not apply to an off-premises retailer licensee, class A or B, that operated as a full-service grocery store or received an exception from the Board pursuant to <cite path="§25-346|(c)">§ 25-346(c)</cite> that is in Ward 8 but that was located in Ward 6 prior to [December 29, 2021], or [February 24, 2022].</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-211" type="History">Aug. 15, 2008, D.C. Law 17-211, § 2(b), 55 DCR 6984</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) additions, see § 2(b) of Mt. Pleasant, Targeted Ward 2, and Targeted Ward 6 Single Sales Moratorium Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-564, October 27, 2008,  55 DCR 12024).</annotation>
    <annotation app="2022-06-30" doc="D.C. Law 24-127" eff="2022-06-30" path="§2|(c)|(7)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2022-06-30" doc="D.C. Law 24-127" eff="2022-06-30" path="§2|(c)|(7)|(B)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-22" doc="D.C. Law 24-332" eff="2023-03-22" path="§5|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-22" doc="D.C. Law 24-332" eff="2023-03-22" path="§5|(b)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-22" doc="D.C. Law 24-332" eff="2023-03-22" path="§5|(c)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
