<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>25-767</num>
  <heading>Outdoor common seating area.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An applicant for a commercial lifestyle center license may apply to the Board to operate one or more outdoor common seating areas on private space to be utilized by patrons purchasing food and alcoholic beverages from licensed on-premises retailers for carry-out; provided, that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The outdoor common seating area is clearly defined and marked with signage;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Alcoholic beverages consumed in the outdoor common seating area are in plastic or non-glass containers of no more than 16 ounces;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Alcoholic beverages are labeled with the trade name, logo, or other labeling unique to the licensee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Patrons remain seated while consuming food and alcohol;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>There is no bar in the outdoor common seating area;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>No food or alcoholic beverage service is provided in the outdoor common seating area;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Open alcoholic beverages may not be taken from the outdoor common seating area into a licensed establishment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Only alcoholic beverages purchased from licensed establishments may be brought into the outdoor common seating area; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Any unfinished alcoholic beverage must be discarded prior to or upon leaving the licensed premises of the commercial lifestyle center.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2022-06-30" doc="D.C. Law 24-127" eff="2022-06-30" path="§2|(f)|(11)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-22" doc="D.C. Law 24-332" eff="2023-03-22" path="§5|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-22" doc="D.C. Law 24-332" eff="2023-03-22" path="§5|(b)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-22" doc="D.C. Law 24-332" eff="2023-03-22" path="§5|(c)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
