<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>23-1904a</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Right to member of a hospital-based violence intervention program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of [this section], [and §§] <cite path="§23-1904b">23-1904b</cite>[] and <cite path="§23-1904c">23-1904c</cite>, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Hospital" means a facility that provides 24-hour inpatient care, including diagnostic, therapeutic, and other health-related services, for a variety of physical or mental conditions, and may, in addition, provide outpatient services, particularly emergency care, from which a hospital-based violence intervention program operates.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Hospital-based violence intervention program" means a non-governmental program that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Provides counseling, case management, and social services to victims at, or in conjunction with, a hospital to prevent retaliatory violence; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Participates in, or is a member of, a coordinating body for similar programs, such as Project CHANGE or the Health Alliance for Violence Intervention.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"HVIP member" means an employee, contractor, or volunteer of a hospital-based violence intervention program.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Victim" means a person who has suffered an intentionally inflicted gunshot or stabbing wound.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A HVIP member shall, if the victim consents, have the right to remain physically present with a victim at any:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Forensic medical, evidentiary, or physical examination at the hospital; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Interview with law enforcement at the hospital.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A victim may at any time revoke their consent to have a HVIP member present at the setting described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2023-04-06" doc="D.C. Law 24-341" eff="2023-04-06" path="§110|(d)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
