<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>16-2333.03</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Information sharing by agencies.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the confidentiality provisions in §§ <cite path="§2-1515.06">2-1515.06</cite>, <cite path="§4-1303.03">4-1303.06</cite>, <cite path="§16-2331">16-2331</cite>, <cite path="§16-2332">16-2332</cite>, and <cite path="§16-2333">16-2333</cite>, it shall not be an offense for an agency to publicly share data derived from juvenile case records, juvenile social records, police and other law enforcement records, confidential Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services records, or confidential Child and Family Services Agency records; provided, that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The data shared does not include any information that, by itself or in combination with other publicly available information, could identify a particular person, including a person's name, Social Security number or other identifying number or code, address, phone number, email address, or birth date; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Record-level data is not shared, the data shared is aggregated, and any counts or data points with fewer than 10 observations are suppressed.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "agency" means the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, the Office of the Attorney General for the District of Columbia, the Metropolitan Police Department, the Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services, the Child and Family Services Agency, the Office of the Ombudsman for Children, the District of Columbia Auditor, and the District of Columbia Inspector General.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-410" path="§13|(h)" codified:display="Note" app="2024-06-08" eff="2024-03-11">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-410" path="§13|(h)">§ 13(h) of Secure DC Omnibus Emergency Amendment Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-410, Mar. 11, 2024, 71 DCR 2693)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-06-08" doc="D.C. Act 25-410" eff="2024-03-11" path="§13|(h)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-490" path="§13|(h)" codified:display="Note" app="2024-06-08" eff="2024-06-07">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-490" path="§13|(h)">§ 13(h) of Secure DC Omnibus Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-490, June 7, 2024, 71 DCR 7006)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-06-08" doc="D.C. Act 25-490" eff="2024-06-07" path="§13|(h)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-06-08" doc="D.C. Law 25-175" eff="2024-06-08" path="§18|(h)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
