<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>16-2399.07</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Order appointing a guardian of a vulnerable youth.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>After consideration of all the relevant, material, and competent evidence, the court, which shall be acting as a juvenile court, shall issue an order establishing a guardianship if the court finds that the guardianship is in the vulnerable youth's best interests.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>After the guardianship is established, upon request by the proposed guardian or the vulnerable youth, the court shall, if the court finds that the allegations in the petition pursuant to <cite path="§16-2399.02|(a)">§16-2399.02(a)</cite> are supported by a preponderance of the evidence, enter a guardianship order containing the following judicial determinations supported by relevant statutory citations and findings of fact:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Where the identity is known, the specific identity of the parent or parents;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>That the vulnerable youth is dependent on the court and has been placed under the care and custody of an individual or entity appointed by the court through the appointment of a guardian;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>That reunification of the vulnerable youth with one or both parents is not viable due to abuse, abandonment, neglect or similar basis under District law; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>That it is not in the best interest of the vulnerable youth to be returned to the vulnerable youth or vulnerable youth's parents' country of nationality or last habitual residence.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The court may, upon motion of a party, modify or terminate a guardianship order when the modification or termination of the guardianship order is in the vulnerable youth's best interests.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The entry of a guardianship order under <cite path="16|23|VI">this subchapter</cite> shall not impinge on the vulnerable youth's fundamental rights to make their own medical, educational, financial, or other such decisions.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A guardianship order entered under <cite path="16|23|VI">this subchapter</cite> shall automatically terminate when the youth reaches age 21.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-203" path="§3|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2024-07-19" eff="2023-08-01">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-203" path="§3|(b)|includes|VI|16-2399.07">§ 16-2399.07 of Vulnerable Youth Guardianship Protection Emergency Amendment Act of 2023 (D.C. Act 25-203, Aug. 1, 2023, 70 DCR 10758)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Act 25-203" eff="2023-08-01" path="§3|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-260" path="§3|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2024-07-19" eff="2023-10-25">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-260" path="§3|(b)|includes|VI|16-2399.07">§ 16-2399.07 of Vulnerable Youth Guardianship Protection Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2023 (D.C. Act 25-260, Oct. 25, 2023, 70 DCR 14434)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Act 25-260" eff="2023-10-25" path="§3|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 25-81" path="§3|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2024-07-19" eff="2023-11-28">For temporary (225 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-81" path="§3|(b)|includes|VI|16-2399.07">§ 16-2399.07 of Vulnerable Youth Guardianship Protection Temporary Amendment Act of 2023 (D.C. Law 25-81, Nov. 28, 2023, 70 DCR 13754)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-81" eff="2023-11-28" path="§3|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-492" path="§3|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2024-07-19" eff="2024-06-26">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-492" path="§3|(b)|includes|VI|16-2399.07">§ 16-2399.07 of Vulnerable Youth Guardianship Protection Emergency Amendment Act of 2024. (D.C. Act 25-492, June 26, 2024, 71 DCR 7595)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Act 25-492" eff="2024-06-26" path="§3|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-188" eff="2024-07-19" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-07-19" doc="D.C. Law 25-188" eff="2024-07-19" path="§3|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
