<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>16-2938</num>
  <heading>Open-market sale, sealed bids, or auction.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If the court orders a sale of real property, the sale shall be an open-market sale unless the court finds that a sale by sealed bids or an auction would be more economically advantageous and in the best interest of the cotenants as a group.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If the court orders an open-market sale and the parties, not later than 10 days after the entry of the order, agree on a real estate broker licensed in the District to offer the property for sale, the court shall appoint the broker and establish a reasonable commission.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the parties do not agree on a real estate broker, the court shall appoint a disinterested real estate broker licensed in the District to offer the real property for sale and shall establish a reasonable commission.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The real estate broker shall offer the real property for sale in a commercially reasonable manner at a price no lower than the determination of value and on the terms and conditions established by the court.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If the real estate broker appointed pursuant to subsection (b) of this section obtains, within a reasonable time, an offer to purchase the real property for at least the determination of value:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The broker shall comply with the reporting requirements in <cite path="§16-2939">§ 16-2939</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The sale may be completed in accordance with any applicable District law.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If the broker appointed pursuant to subsection (b) of this section does not obtain, within a reasonable time, an offer to purchase the real property for at least the determination of value, the court, after a hearing, may:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Approve the highest outstanding offer, if any;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Redetermine the value of the real property and order that the real property continue to be offered for an additional time; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Order that the real property be sold by sealed bids or at an auction.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If the court orders a sale by sealed bids or an auction, the court shall set terms and conditions of the sale.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the court orders an auction, the auction shall be conducted in a commercially reasonable manner that is fair to all concerned.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>If a purchaser is entitled to a share of the proceeds of the sale, the purchaser shall be entitled to a credit against the price in an amount equal to the purchaser's share of the proceeds.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-239" eff="2023-02-23" path="§2|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-239" eff="2023-02-23" path="§2|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
