<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>16-318</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Expedited adoption eligibility.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Intended parents that use assisted reproductive technology to produce a child of their union may petition the court for an expedited adoption pursuant to this section under either of the following circumstances:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>One of the intended parents gave birth to the child; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The child was born through a gestational surrogacy process brought about by one or both of the intended parents, and the parentage of only one intended parent was established pursuant to <cite path="§16-909|(e)">§ 16-909(e)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Each intended parent seeking an adoption pursuant to this section shall join in a petition for expedited adoption.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The petition for expedited adoption shall be made under oath or affirmation of the petitioners, and the title of the petition shall be: "Ex parte in the matter of the petition of . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . for expedited adoption".</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The petition shall contain:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The name, sex, date, and place of birth of the prospective adoptee;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The name, date of birth, and addresses of the petitioners;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The relationship of the prospective adoptee to the petitioners;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>A statement of how the prospective adoptee was conceived;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>The date that the prospective adoptee began residing with the petitioners;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Any change to the name of the prospective adoptee that may be desired by the petitioners;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Any change to how the prospective adoptee's birth certificate should identify the petitioners as parents of the prospective adoptee; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Language indicating consent to the expedited adoption by the intended parent who gave birth to the prospective adoptee or had parentage established pursuant to <cite path="§16-909|(e)">§ 16-909(e)</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>In a proceeding under this section, the petitioners shall file, as exhibits to the petition for expedited adoption:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A certified copy of any document that evidences the petitioners' relationship, such as a marriage certificate or registered domestic partnership certificate, or intent to parent together, such as a consent to parent form pursuant to <cite path="§16-909|(e)|(1)|(A)">§ 16-909(e)(1)(A)</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A certified copy of the prospective adoptee's birth certificate; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A sworn statement by the petitioners that a written agreement pursuant to <cite path="§16-909.01|(a)|(1)">§ 16-909.01(a)(1)</cite> has not been executed.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The court shall not require an investigation, report, and recommendation pursuant to <cite path="§16-307">§ 16-307</cite> or criminal records check pursuant to <cite path="§4-1305.02">§ 4-1305.02</cite> prior to the issuance of a final decree of adoption under this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The court shall issue a final decree of adoption under this section if it appears from the face of the pleadings that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The intended parents used assisted reproductive technology to produce a child of their union; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>No other person has a claim to parentage of the prospective adoptee.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Upon issuance of a final decree of adoption, the court shall provide 4 certified copies of the final decree of adoption to the petitioners at no additional cost.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Assisted reproductive technology" means any noncoital method of conception used with donor or nondonor eggs or sperm, including in vitro fertilization, gamete intrafallopian transfer, and zygote intrafallopian transfer.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Intended parents" means:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A married couple;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Domestic partners registered in the District pursuant to <cite path="§32-702|(a)">§ 32-702(a)</cite> or recognized by the District pursuant to <cite path="§32-702|(i)">§ 32-702(i)</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Individuals who maintain a committed relationship, as that term is defined in <cite path="§32-701|(1)">§ 32-701(1)</cite>; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Individuals who signed a consent to parent form pursuant to <cite path="§16-909|(e)|(1)">§ 16-909(e)(1)</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-237" eff="2023-02-23" path="§2|(j)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
