<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>16-5619</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Vacation or amendment by Superior Court of unconfirmed award.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>On motion of a party, the Superior Court shall vacate an unconfirmed award if the moving party establishes that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The award was procured by corruption, fraud, or other undue means;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>There was:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Evident partiality by the arbitrator;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Corruption by the arbitrator; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Misconduct by the arbitrator substantially prejudicing the rights of a party;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The arbitrator refused to postpone a hearing on showing of sufficient cause for postponement, refused to consider evidence material to the controversy, or otherwise conducted the hearing contrary to <cite path="§16-5613">§ 16-5613</cite>, so as to prejudice substantially the rights of a party;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The arbitrator exceeded the arbitrator's powers;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>No arbitration agreement exists, unless the moving party participated in the arbitration without making a motion under <cite path="§16-5607">§ 16-5607</cite> not later than the beginning of the first arbitration hearing; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The arbitration was conducted without proper notice under <cite path="§16-5606">§ 16-5606</cite> of the initiation of arbitration, so as to prejudice substantially the rights of a party.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (c) of this section, on motion of a party, the Superior Court shall vacate an unconfirmed award that determines a child-related dispute if the moving party establishes that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The award does not comply with <cite path="§16-5615">§ 16-5615</cite> or law of the District other than <cite path="16|56">this chapter</cite> governing a child-related dispute or is contrary to the best interests of the child;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The record of the hearing or the statement of reasons in the award is inadequate for the court to review the award; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A ground for vacating the award under subsection (a) of this section exists.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If an award is subject to vacation under subsection (b)(1) of this section, on motion of a party, the Superior Court may amend the award if amending rather than vacating is in the best interests of the child.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Superior Court shall determine a motion under subsection (b) or (c) of this section based on the record of the arbitration hearing and facts occurring after the hearing.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A motion under this section to vacate or amend an award shall be filed not later than 90 days:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>After an arbitrator gives the party filing the motion notice of the award or a corrected award; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For a motion under subsection (a)(1) of this section, after the ground of corruption, fraud, or other undue means is known or by the exercise of reasonable care should have been known to the party filing the motion.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>If the Superior Court under this section vacates an award for a reason other than the absence of an enforceable arbitration agreement, the court may order a rehearing before an arbitrator.  If the reason for vacating the award is that the award was procured by corruption, fraud, or other undue means or there was evident partiality, corruption, or misconduct by the arbitrator, the rehearing shall be before another arbitrator.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>If the Superior Court under this section denies a motion to vacate or amend an award, the court may confirm the award under <cite path="§16-5616">§ 16-5616</cite> unless a motion is pending under <cite path="§16-5618">§ 16-5618</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-286" eff="2023-03-10" path="§2|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-286" eff="2023-03-10" path="§2|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
