<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>ยง</prefix>
  <num>16-5613</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Powers and duties of arbitrator.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An arbitrator shall conduct an arbitration in a manner the arbitrator considers appropriate for a fair and expeditious disposition of the dispute.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An arbitrator shall provide each party a right to be heard, to present evidence material to the family law dispute, and to cross-examine witnesses.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Unless the parties otherwise agree in a record, an arbitrator's powers include the power to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Select the rules for conducting the arbitration;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Hold conferences with the parties before a hearing;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Determine the date, time, and place of a hearing;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Require a party to provide:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A copy of a relevant court order;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Information required to be disclosed in a family law proceeding under law of the District other than <cite path="16|56">this chapter</cite>; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A proposed award that addresses each issue in arbitration;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Meet with or interview a child who is the subject of a child-related dispute;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Appoint a private expert at the expense of the parties;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Administer an oath or affirmation and issue a subpoena for the attendance of a witness or the production of documents and other evidence at a hearing;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Compel discovery concerning the family law dispute and determine the date, time, and place of discovery;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Determine the admissibility and weight of evidence;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Permit deposition of a witness for use as evidence at a hearing;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>For good cause, prohibit a party from disclosing information;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>Appoint an attorney, guardian ad litem, or other representative for a child at the expense of the parties;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>Impose a procedure to protect a party or child from risk of harm, harassment, or intimidation;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(14)</num>
      <text>Allocate arbitration fees, attorney's fees, expert-witness fees, and other costs to the parties; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(15)</num>
      <text>Impose a sanction on a party for bad faith or misconduct during the arbitration according to standards governing imposition of a sanction for litigant misconduct in a family law proceeding.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>An arbitrator may not allow ex parte communication except to the extent allowed in a family law proceeding for communication with a judge.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-286" eff="2023-03-10" path="ยง2|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-286" eff="2023-03-10" path="ยง2|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
