<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>ยง</prefix>
  <num>16-5605</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Arbitration agreement.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An arbitration agreement shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be in a record signed by the parties;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Identify the arbitrator, an arbitration organization, or a method of selecting an arbitrator; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Identify the family law dispute the parties intend to arbitrate.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (c) of this section, an agreement in a record to arbitrate a family law dispute that arises between the parties before, at the time, or after the agreement is made is valid and enforceable as any other contract and irrevocable except on a ground that exists at law or in equity for the revocation of a contract.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An agreement to arbitrate a child-related dispute that arises between the parties after the agreement is made is unenforceable unless:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The parties affirm the agreement in a record after the dispute arises, or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The agreement was entered during a family law proceeding and the Superior Court approved or incorporated the agreement in an order issued in the proceeding.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If a party objects to arbitration on the ground the arbitration agreement is unenforceable or the agreement does not include a family law dispute, the Superior Court shall decide whether the agreement is enforceable or includes the family law dispute.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-286" eff="2023-03-10" path="ยง2|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-286" eff="2023-03-10" path="ยง2|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
