<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>16-5609</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Disclosure by arbitrator; disqualification.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Before agreeing to serve as an arbitrator, an individual, after making reasonable inquiry, shall disclose to all parties any known fact that a reasonable person would believe is likely to affect:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The impartiality of the arbitrator in the arbitration, including bias, a financial or personal interest in the outcome of the arbitration, or an existing or past relationship with a party, attorney representing a party, or witness; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The arbitrator's ability to make a timely award.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An arbitrator, the parties, and the attorneys representing the parties have a continuing obligation to disclose to all parties any known fact a reasonable person would believe is likely to affect the impartiality of the arbitrator or the arbitrator's ability to make a timely award.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An objection to the selection or continued service of an arbitrator and a motion for a stay of arbitration and disqualification of the arbitrator shall be made under the law and procedural rules of the District other than <cite path="16|56">this chapter</cite> governing arbitrator disqualification.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If a disclosure required by subsection (a)(1) or (b) of this section is not made, the Superior Court may:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>On motion of a party not later than 30 days after the failure to disclose is known or by the exercise of reasonable care should have been known to the party, suspend the arbitration;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>On timely motion of a party, vacate an award under <cite path="§16-5619|(a)|(2)">§ 16-5619(a)(2)</cite>; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If an award has been confirmed, grant other appropriate relief under law of the District other than <cite path="16|56">this chapter</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>If the parties agree to discharge an arbitrator or the arbitrator is disqualified, the parties by agreement may select a new arbitrator or request the Superior Court to select another arbitrator as provided in <cite path="§16-5608">§ 16-5608</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-286" eff="2023-03-10" path="§2|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-286" eff="2023-03-10" path="§2|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
