<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>ยง</prefix>
  <num>16-5602</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Definitions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of <cite path="16|56">this chapter</cite>, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Arbitration agreement" means an agreement that subjects a family law dispute to arbitration.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Arbitration organization" means an association, agency, board, commission, or other entity that is neutral and initiates, sponsors, or administers an arbitration or is involved in the selection of an arbitrator.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Arbitrator" means an individual selected, alone or with others, to make an award in a family law dispute that is subject to an arbitration agreement.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Child-related dispute" means a family law dispute regarding legal custody, physical custody, custodial responsibility, parental responsibility or authority, parenting time, right to access, visitation, or financial support regarding a child.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Family law dispute" means a contested issue arising under the domestic relations law of the District.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"Party" means an individual who signs an arbitration agreement and whose rights will be determined by an award.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>"Person" means an individual, estate, business or nonprofit entity, public corporation, government or governmental subdivision, agency, or instrumentality, or any other legal entity.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>"Record" means, when used as a noun, information that is inscribed on a tangible medium or that is stored in an electronic or other medium and is retrievable in perceivable form.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>"Sign" means, with present intent to authenticate or adopt a record:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>To execute or adopt a tangible symbol; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>To attach to or logically associate with the record an electronic symbol, sound, or process.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>"State" means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, or any territory or insular possession subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>"Superior Court" means the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-286" eff="2023-03-10" path="ยง2|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-286" eff="2023-03-10" path="ยง2|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
