<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>ยง</prefix>
  <num>16-714</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Special education attorneys for emerging adult defendants panel.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>By October 1, 2023, the Criminal Division of the Superior Court ("Court") shall designate and appoint, according to rules it establishes, a panel of special education attorneys to represent indigent emerging adult defendants with disabilities in criminal proceedings.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An attorney appointed from the panel established pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall represent the educational and disability rights and needs of the emerging adult defendant with a disability.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Court shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Maintain a register of attorneys who have expressed an interest in being appointed to serve as special education attorneys pursuant to this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Endeavor to make panel appointments from the register established in paragraph (1) of this subsection; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Only appoint attorneys to the panel after careful consideration of the qualifications of each attorney.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>For the purpose of funding the costs associated with this section, beginning in Fiscal Year 2023, and annually thereafter, the Office of Victim Services and Justice Grants shall issue a grant to a legal services and advocacy organization serving older students with special education needs who are involved in the District's juvenile and criminal legal systems.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The availability of special education attorneys for emerging adult defendants with disabilities pursuant to this section shall be contingent upon the availability of funds.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Beginning in Fiscal Year 2023, the Office of Victim Services and Justice Grants shall issue an annual grant, in the amount of $300,000, to provide special education legal representation to emerging adult defendants with disabilities by a legal services and advocacy organization serving older students with special education needs who are involved in the District's justice system.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "emerging adult defendant with a disability" means a criminal defendant under 23 years of age, or the parent, as that term is defined in 20 U.S.C. ยง 1401(23), of a criminal defendant under 18 years of age who is:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Charged as an adult; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Qualifies as a child with a disability, as that term is defined in 20 U.S.C. ยง 1401(3).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2023-04-21" doc="D.C. Law 24-344" eff="2023-04-21" path="ยง4|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
