<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-1031.12f</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Recycling of disposable plastic bags, plastic film, and plastic shipping products.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Beginning January 1, 2024, a covered retail establishment that offers disposable plastic bags to consumers shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Make available to consumers a receptacle to collect disposable plastic bags, plastic film, and plastic shipping products for recycling; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Recycle disposable plastic bags, plastic film, and plastic shipping products collected in the receptacle.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Receptables required by this section shall be located within the covered retail establishment or within 100 feet of the covered retail establishment's main entrance, in a location that is easily accessible and clearly visible to consumers and accompanied with signage stating that the receptacle is for the collection of disposable plastic bags, plastic film, and plastic shipping products for recycling.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to require a covered retail establishment to accept disposable bags, film, or shipping products made from materials other than plastic, that are not able to be recycled, or that are soiled or wet.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>On or before January 1, 2023, the Department of Public Works shall publish on its website information on where and how retail establishments may send disposable plastic bags, plastic film, and plastic shipping products to be recycled.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-154" type="History" path="ยง112f">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-154, ยง 112f</annotation>
    <annotation app="2015-02-26" doc="D.C. Law 20-154" eff="2015-02-26" path="I" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-253" eff="2023-02-23" path="ยง2|(c)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
