<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-151.09d</num>
  <heading>Commitment to greenhouse gas emission reductions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall adopt policies to reduce emissions of greenhouse gases from both public and private sources to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Not less than 45% below 2006 greenhouse gas emission levels by 2025;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Not less than 60% below 2006 greenhouse gas emission levels by 2030;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Not less than 70% below 2006 greenhouse gas emission levels by 2035;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Not less than 85% below 2006 greenhouse gas emission levels by 2040; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A level consistent with carbon neutrality by 2045, and in each year thereafter.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The District shall reduce emissions attributable to District government operations to a level consistent with carbon neutrality by 2040. In working to achieve these reductions, the District shall prioritize actions that result in additional renewable energy generation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>To achieve the reduction required by paragraph (1) of this subsection the Mayor shall establish a task force to prepare an action plan for carbon neutrality for District government operations by 2040, including the estimated funding and timeline for each action identified, which shall be submitted to the Council no later than 18 months after September 21, 2022.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The task force shall include, at a minimum, representatives from the following agencies:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The Department of General Services;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The Department of Public Works;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>The District Department of Transportation;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>The District of Columbia Housing Authority;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>The District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vi)</num>
          <text>The Office of the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vii)</num>
          <text>The Department of Energy and Environment; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(viii)</num>
          <text>The Office of Resilience and Recovery.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In working to achieve the emissions reductions required by subsections (a) and (b) of this section, the District shall seek to advance racial equity, redress past environmental and public health inequities, and use measures that have the least harmful effect on local ecosystems.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Beginning on July 1, 2025, and on July 1 of each year thereafter, DOEE shall submit an annual report to the Council which summarizes progress on achieving the emissions reductions required by subsections (a) and (b) of this section. At a minimum, the report shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An updated inventory of District-wide greenhouse gas emissions, expressed in tons of carbon dioxide equivalents, from all greenhouse gas emission sources in the District as tracked pursuant to standard greenhouse gas accounting protocols, including the relative contribution of each type of greenhouse gas and each type of source to the District-wide total, as well as an inventory of greenhouse gas emissions specifically attributable to District government operations;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A description of actions taken to achieve the emissions reductions required by subsections (a) and (b) of this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An analysis of how the actions described in paragraph (2) of this subsection advance racial equity, redress past environmental and public health inequities, and affect local ecosystems;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>If the emissions reductions required by subsections (a) and (b) of this section are not achieved, a description of any impediments encountered in achieving the emission reductions and recommendations for how to address such impediments;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>For any actions identified in the action plan required by subsection (b)(2) of this section that are not implemented according to the plan, a description of any impediments encountered in achieving the actions and recommendations for how to address such impediments; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Every 5 years, an updated projection of District-wide greenhouse gas emissions each year through 2045, as well as District government greenhouse gas emissions each year through 2040, based on policies currently in existence, as well as an analysis of whether the District is on track to meet the emissions reductions required by subsections (a) and (b) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-51" type="History" path="§109d">Feb. 15, 2006, D.C. Law 16-51, § 109d</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-51" type="History" path="§109e">Feb. 15, 2006, D.C. Law 16-51, § 109e</annotation>
    <annotation app="2022-09-21" doc="D.C. Law 24-176" eff="2022-09-21" path="§2" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
