<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>8-651.08</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by temporary legislation that will expire on February 10, 2023. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite path="§8-651.08(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
  <heading>Enforcement.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this chapter, or any regulations issued under the authority of this chapter, pursuant to <cite path="2|18">Chapter 18 of Title 2</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In addition to or instead of imposing a civil fine, penalty, or fee under subsection (a) of this section, the Mayor may issue a stop work order, which, upon service, would mandate the cessation or holding of work, if the Mayor finds that any work is being performed, or may be performed imminently, in violation of the provisions of <cite path="8|6B">this chapter</cite>. A stop work order under this subsection shall be in writing and in a form prescribed by the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A stop work order under this subsection shall contain:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The reason for the stop work order;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The conditions under which the cited work will be permitted to resume;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The address of the property;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The specific areas of the property and specific activities covered by the stop work order;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>The specific section of <cite path="8|6B">this chapter</cite> that was violated or that may be imminently violated; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>A description of the right to request review of the stop work order under paragraph (6) of this subsection, information on how to request such review, and the deadline to file such a request.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>No stop work order under this subsection shall be issued or considered valid unless it contains all of the information specified in paragraph (2) of this subsection and the signature of the issuing official.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A stop work order issued pursuant to this subsection shall be narrowly tailored to mandate only the cessation or holding of the portion of work that would violate the provisions of <cite path="8|6B">this chapter</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall effect service of a stop work order by:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Personal service on the property owner or on the property owner's agent; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Posting the stop work order in a conspicuous location on the property subject to the stop work order.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall lift the stop work order when the Mayor determines that the violation or potential violation leading to the issuance of the stop work order has been corrected or abated to the satisfaction of the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>No later than 10 business days after receiving notice of a stop work order, the property owner or the property owner's agent may request review by the Mayor and shall state, in writing, the grounds for the requested review.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Upon receipt of a request for review that complies with subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, the Mayor shall affirm, modify, or reverse the stop work order within 15 business days after receipt of the request. If the Mayor does not act upon the review request within the 15 business day period, the stop work order shall be reversed. A decision of the Mayor under this subparagraph shall be a final decision on the specific issue in the review request.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Before a stop work order under this subsection is issued, the Mayor may issue a warning notice to the property owner or the property owner's agent.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>A violation of a stop work order issued under this subsection shall constitute a violation of <cite path="8|6B">this chapter</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Whenever it appears that any person has violated, or is about to violate, a stop work order issued under this subsection, the Office of the Attorney General for the District of Columbia may bring an action in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for injunctive relief.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-309" type="History" path="§108">June 12, 2003, D.C. Law 14-309, § 108, 50 DCR 888</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-351" path="§2|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2022-03-28" eff="2022-03-28">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-351" path="§2|(a)">§ 2(a) of Urban Forest Preservation Stop Work Order Authority Emergency Amendment Act of 2022 (D.C. Act 24-351, Mar. 28, 2022, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2022-03-28" doc="D.C. Act 24-351" eff="2022-03-28" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-452" path="§2|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2022-06-28" eff="2022-06-28">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-452" path="§2|(a)">§ 2(a) of Urban Forest Preservation Stop Work Order Authority Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2022 (D.C. Act 24-452, June 28, 2022, 69 DCR 007762)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2022-06-28" doc="D.C. Act 24-452" eff="2022-06-28" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2022-06-30" doc="D.C. Law 24-133" eff="2022-06-30" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2022-06-30" doc="D.C. Law 24-133" eff="2022-06-30" path="§2|(a)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2022-06-30" doc="D.C. Law 24-133" eff="2022-06-30" path="§2|(a)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 24-133" path="§2|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2022-06-30" eff="2022-06-30">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-133" path="§2|(a)">§ 2(a) of Urban Forest Preservation Stop Work Order Authority Temporary Amendment Act of 2022 (D.C. Law 24-133, June 30, 2022, 69 DCR 004408)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
