<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>10-551.07e</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by temporary legislation that will expire on October 6, 2023. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation affecting this section, click this link: <cite path="§10-551.07e(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
  <heading>Government Space Maintenance and Repair Transparency Dashboard.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Beginning no later than October 1, 2022, the Department shall publish a dashboard referencing all open District of Columbia Public School campus facility maintenance work orders not exempted by subsection (e) of this section, updated at least weekly to reflect changes in work order status and newly opened work orders.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Beginning no later than October 1, 2023, the Department shall update the previously established dashboard to include all open Department of Parks and Recreation facility maintenance work orders not exempted by subsection (e) of this section, updated at least weekly to reflect changes in work order status and newly opened work orders.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For purposes of complying with subsections (a) and (b) of this section, the Department shall utilize existing technological resources to the greatest extent feasible.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, the term "dashboard" means a publicly accessible online data interface that shares information on all facility maintenance work orders submitted to the Department, including at least the following information for each work order:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The facility impacted;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The location of the issue;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A description of the type of issue;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The individual or entity that reported the issue, if known and authorized to be disclosed by the individual or entity;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The work order number;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Any prioritization level that the Department or client agency has assigned;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The status of the work order; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>If the work order remains open, an estimated completion date.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The following types of work order data shall be exempt from the requirements of subsections (a) and (b) of this section:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Any work order data regarding a door or lock issue that impairs ordinary operation or has the potential to impair lockdown of a campus space;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Any work order data regarding a window issue that impairs ordinary operation or has the potential to impair lockdown of a campus space; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Any work order data regarding a security camera or security alarm system if that data could be used to access a facility unlawfully.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Department of General Services ("Department") shall provide prompt written notice to the chairs of the Council committees with jurisdiction over the Department, the District of Columbia Public Schools, and the Department of Parks and Recreation regarding any work order omitted from a dashboard pursuant to paragraph (1) this subsection that remains open for 45 days or more.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Department may delay its publication pursuant to subsections (a) and (b) of this section of any work order data related to door, window, and security system issues for up to 10 business days for purposes of determining whether such data are exempt from disclosure pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History" path="§1028e">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 1028e</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-470" path="§1022" codified:display="Note" app="2022-09-21" eff="2022-07-13">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-470" path="§1022">§ 1022 of Fiscal Year 2023 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2022 (D.C. Act 24-470, July 13, 2022, 69 DCR 008707)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2022-09-21" doc="D.C. Act 24-470" eff="2022-07-13" path="§1022" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2022-09-21" doc="D.C. Law 24-167" eff="2022-09-21" path="§1022" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-650" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2022-11-21" eff="2022-11-21">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-650" path="§2">§ 2 of Protecting Security-Sensitive Dashboard Data Emergency Amendment Act of 2022 (D.C. Act 24-650, Nov. 21, 2022, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2022-11-21" doc="D.C. Act 24-650" eff="2022-11-21" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-270" eff="2023-02-23" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-270" eff="2023-02-23" path="§2|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-270" eff="2023-02-23" path="§2|(b)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-270" eff="2023-02-23" path="§2|(c)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 24-270" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2023-02-23" eff="2023-02-23">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-270" path="§2">§ 2 of Protecting Security-Sensitive Dashboard Data Temporary Amendment Act of 2022 (D.C. Law 24-270, Feb. 23, 2023, 69 DCR 14756)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-28" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2023-02-24" eff="2023-02-24">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-28" path="§2">§ 2 of Protecting Security-Sensitive Dashboard Data Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2023 (D.C. Act 25-28, Feb. 24, 2023, 70 DCR 2961)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-02-24" doc="D.C. Act 25-28" eff="2023-02-24" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
