<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>ยง</prefix>
  <num>14-508</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Introduction of records of a regularly conducted activity.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Certification" means a written declaration under oath subject to the penalty of perjury. A certification need not take the form of an affidavit.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Qualified person" means a person who would be able to establish the authenticity of a record if called as a witness at trial.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Records of a regularly conducted activity" means a record of an act, event, condition, opinion, or diagnosis, where:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The record was made at or near the time by, or from information transmitted by, someone with knowledge of the act, event, condition, opinion, or diagnosis;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The record was kept in the course of a regularly conducted activity of a business, organization, occupation, or calling, whether or not for profit;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Making the record was a regular practice of that activity; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The opponent does not show that the source of information or the method or circumstances of preparation indicate a lack of trustworthiness.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The original or copy of a domestic record of a regularly conducted activity, as shown by a certification of the custodian or another qualified person, shall be deemed authentic without further testimony as evidence in any judicial proceeding or administrative hearing.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Before the judicial proceeding or administrative hearing, the proponent shall give an adverse party reasonable written notice of the intent to offer the record of a regularly conducted activity and shall make the record of a regularly conducted activity and certification available for inspection.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-261" eff="2023-02-23" path="ยง2|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
