<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>18-902</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Definitions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of <cite path="18|9">this chapter</cite>, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Electronic" means relating to technology having electrical, digital, magnetic, wireless, optical, electromagnetic, or similar capabilities.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Electronic presence" means the relationship of two or more individuals in different locations communicating in real time to the same extent as if the individuals were physically present in the same location.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Electronic will" means a will executed electronically in compliance with <cite path="§18-905|(a)">§ 18-905(a)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Record" means information that is inscribed on a tangible medium or that is stored in an electronic or other medium and is retrievable in perceivable form.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Sign" means, with present intent to authenticate or adopt a record:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>To execute or adopt a tangible symbol; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>To affix to or logically associate with the record an electronic symbol or process.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"State" means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, or any territory or insular possession subject to the jurisdiction of the United States. The term includes a federally recognized Indian tribe.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>"Will" includes a codicil and any testamentary instrument that merely appoints an executor, revokes or revises another will, nominates a guardian, or expressly excludes or limits the right of an individual or class to succeed to property of the decedent passing by intestate succession.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-296" eff="2023-03-10" path="§2|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-296" eff="2023-03-10" path="§2|(c)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
