<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-1303.03g</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Housing for youth aging out of Agency custody.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>At least 90 days before a youth leaves foster care in accordance with a transition plan described in section 475(5)(H) of the Social Security Act, approved June 17, 1980 (94 Stat. 510; 42 U.S.C. § 675(5)(H)) ("aging-out youth"), the Agency shall develop, in consultation with the aging-out youth and the youth's guardian <em>ad litem</em>, and provide to the aging-out youth and their guardian <em>ad litem</em>, a written housing plan.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the housing plan does not contemplate the aging-out youth receiving a housing voucher, the plan shall include a thorough explanation of why the aging-out youth is not:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>At risk of homelessness as that term is defined under <cite path="§4-751.01|(5B)">§ 4-751.01(5B)</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Prepared for independent living; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Otherwise in need of a primary residence for independent living.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The housing plan shall include a description of housing options being pursued for the aging-out youth, including an explanation as to why each option is in the aging-out youth's best interest.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Agency shall collaborate with the District of Columbia Housing Authority ("DCHA") to secure for an aging-out youth who is leaving foster care within 90 days or who has left foster care within the past 5 years who is at risk of homelessness and who requires assistance securing a primary residence for independent living other than a college dormitory or military housing a Family Unification Program Housing Choice Voucher.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Agency and DCHA shall take any action required by the United Sates Department of Housing and Urban Development to administer the Foster Youth to Independence ("FYI") Initiative, which may include the Agency:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Providing or securing supportive services for participating youth for the duration of the FYI Initiative voucher;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Providing a written certification to DCHA verifying the youth's child welfare history; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Identifying youth eligible for an FYI Initiative voucher within the Agency's caseload and communicating their eligibility to the youth.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Beginning on February 28 of the year after March 10, 2023, and no later than February 28 of each year thereafter, the Mayor shall submit a report to the Council on the Agency's efforts to ensure that no aging-out youth becomes homeless, including information on:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The number of aging-out youths who left foster care in the preceding fiscal year;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The number and percentage of aging-out youths who left foster care in the preceding fiscal year who were homeless, as that term is defined under <cite path="§4-751.01|(18)">§ 4-751.01(18)</cite>, upon leaving care;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The number and percentage of aging-out youths who left foster care in the preceding 5 fiscal years who were homeless, as that term is defined under <cite path="§4-751.01|(18)">§ 4-751.01(18)</cite>, at 6 months after leaving foster care and upon the youth's 26th birthday;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Housing options available to aging-out youth and the process for accessing each housing option;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The processes by which the Agency matches aging-out youth with housing resources, including the use of matrices or other tools by any formal or informal governmental body, and a description of the considerations, qualifications, or other relevant factors that the Agency relies on when matching aging-out youth with housing resources; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Any barriers faced by the Agency in successfully matching aging-out youth with housing resources and the Agency's mitigation of those barriers.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-22" type="History" path="§303g">Sept. 23, 1977, D.C. Law 2-22, title III, § 303g</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-309" eff="2023-03-10" path="§2|(a)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
