<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-1705.01</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Client Privilege for Coordinated Intake and Referral.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There shall be no cause of action for damages arising against any association or society of attorneys or counsellors at law authorized to practice in the District of Columbia for referring any person or persons to a member of the profession for the purpose of obtaining legal services; provided, that such referral is made without charge and as a public service by said association or society, without malice, and in the reasonable belief that such referral was warranted, based upon the facts disclosed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The communications between a member or authorized agent of an association or society of attorneys or counsellors at law and any person, persons, or entity communicating with such member or authorized agent for the purpose of seeking or obtaining a professional referral shall be deemed to be privileged on the same basis as the privilege provided by law for communications between attorney and client. Such privilege may be waived only by the person, persons, or entity who has furnished information to the association or society, its members, or authorized agents.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall limit, waive, or abrogate the scope or nature of any statutory or common-law privilege, including work product, the attorney-client privilege, or the subsequent remedial measures exclusion.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-223" type="History" path="§501">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 501</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-506" path="§3042|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2024-09-18" eff="2024-07-15">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-506" path="§3042|(b)|includes|D|501">§ 501 of Fiscal Year 2025 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-506, July 15, 2024, 71 DCR 8406)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Act 25-506" eff="2024-07-15" path="§3042|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Law 25-217" eff="2024-09-18" path="§3042|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Law 25-217" eff="2024-09-18" path="§3042|(b)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
