<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-281.06</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Confidentiality.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Department shall not use or disclose information collected from or about a program participant or applicant except as provided in subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Provided that the use or disclosure is not otherwise prohibited under District or federal law, the Department may use and disclose to other District agencies, contractors, grantees, auditors, and program evaluators information in program records concerning current or former program participants or applicants without prior consent from any individual to whom the information pertains to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Establish an applicant's eligibility for, or to determine their amount and type of, support services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Coordinate for the program participant their support with other services provided by the District government, federal government, or a private individual or entity;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Conduct oversight activities, including management, financial and other audits, program evaluations, planning, investigations, examinations, inspections, quality reviews, licensure, disciplinary actions, or civil, administrative, or criminal proceedings or actions; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Conduct research related to program services, benefits, supports, assistance, or program outcomes.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-433" path="§7" codified:display="Note" app="2023-03-10" eff="2022-05-23">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-433" path="§7">§ 7 of Career Mobility Action Plan Program Establishment Emergency Act of 2022 (D.C. Act 24-433, May 23, 2022, 69 DCR 6253)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Act 24-433" eff="2022-05-23" path="§7" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-521" path="§7" codified:display="Note" app="2023-03-10" eff="2022-07-27">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-521" path="§7">§ 7 of Career Mobility Action Plan Program Establishment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2022 (D.C. Act 24-521, July 27, 2022, 69 DCR 009895)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Act 24-521" eff="2022-07-27" path="§7" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 24-161" path="§7" codified:display="Note" app="2023-03-10" eff="2022-08-27">For temporary (225 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-161" path="§7">§ 7 of Career Mobility Action Plan Program Establishment Temporary Act of 2022 (D.C. Law 24-161, Aug. 27, 2022, 69 DCR 008381)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-161" eff="2022-08-27" path="§7" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-287" eff="2023-03-10" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-287" eff="2023-03-10" path="§206" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
