<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-281.03</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on October 25, 2022.*
      </text>
  <heading>Eligibility, enrollment, and program requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>To be eligible to participate in the program, a household shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Reside in the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Be a low-income household at the time that the household's initial eligibility is determined;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Contain at least one individual who is currently participating in a housing-assistance program administered by the District or federal government at the time that the household's initial eligibility is determined; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Meet any other eligibility criteria established by the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Department may establish preference criteria and an application process, and may also conduct a randomized lottery to select eligible households to participate in the program and to aid in the evaluation of the program. Preference criteria may factor in whether a household is participating in a time-limited housing-assistance program, includes children under the age of 18, and is willing to participate in career-related and other program activities. Preference criteria may limit participation to households that are participating in one or more specific housing-assistance programs at the time their initial eligibility for the program is determined.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>No provision of <cite path="4|2D">this chapter</cite> shall be construed to create an entitlement to the program.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A program participant shall remain eligible to participate in the program for no more than 5 years after enrollment regardless of income.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To remain eligible to participate in the program, program participants shall maintain residency in the District, participate in any support services mandated as a condition of continued eligibility in the program, and meet requirements and criteria established by the Department.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Program participants must exit other housing-assistance programs upon enrollment in the program. A program participant shall cease to be eligible to participate in the program if, during the program participant's enrollment, any member of the program participant's household becomes enrolled in another District- or federal government-funded rental assistance program.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-271.01" expire="2022-07-27" codified:display="Note">For temporary (90 days) creation of § 4-281.03, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-521" path="§4">§ 4 of Career Mobility Action Plan Program Establishment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2022 (D.C. Act 24-521, July 27, 2022, 69 DCR 009895)</cite>.</codify:annotation>
  <codify:annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-281.03" applicability="2022-07-27" delay="50" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§4-281.03">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-521" path="§4">§ 4 of Career Mobility Action Plan Program Establishment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2022 (D.C. Act 24-521, July 27, 2022, 69 DCR 009895)</cite>.</codify:annotation>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-281.03" before="heading" history="false" display-template="" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§4-281.03">
    <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on October 25, 2022.*
      </text>
  </codify:insert>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-433" path="§4" codified:display="Note" app="2022-07-27" eff="2022-05-23">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-433" path="§4">§ 4 of Career Mobility Action Plan Program Establishment Emergency Act of 2022 (D.C. Act 24-433, May 23, 2022, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2022-07-27" doc="D.C. Act 24-433" eff="2022-05-23" path="§4" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2022-07-27" doc="D.C. Act 24-521" eff="2022-07-27" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2022-07-27" doc="D.C. Act 24-521" eff="2022-07-27" path="§4" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2022-07-27" doc="D.C. Act 24-521" eff="2022-07-27" path="§4" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-521" path="§4" codified:display="Note" app="2022-07-27" eff="2022-07-27">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-521" path="§4">§ 4 of Career Mobility Action Plan Program Establishment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2022 (D.C. Act 24-521, July 27, 2022, 69 DCR 009895)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
