<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-431</num>
  <heading>Diaper bank grant program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Department of Health Care Finance shall issue grant funds to a diaper bank or diaper program for the purpose of providing funds for the purchase and distribution of free diapers to eligible parents and legal guardians with infants 3 years of age and under.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>To receive funds under the program, a diaper bank or diaper program shall submit a written application to the Department and satisfy the following conditions:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Serve organizations and individuals within the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Have an approved operating budget that includes the purchase of diapers approved by the board of directors or other governing body of the diaper bank or diaper program;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Submit a detailed proposal outlining how the funds will be used to purchase and distribute free diapers to eligible parents and legal guardians with infants 3 years of age and under; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Meet any other criteria required by the Department.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Eligible parent" means the natural parent, adoptive parent, or legal guardian of an infant that is 3 years of age or under that currently resides in the District and is:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In a family that is eligible for:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>DC Healthcare Alliance;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>DC Healthy Families;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Emergency Rental Assistance Program;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>Housing Choice Program;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>Low Income Home Energy Assistance Program;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vi)</num>
          <text>Medicaid;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vii)</num>
          <text>Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(viii)</num>
          <text>Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ix)</num>
          <text>Temporary Assistance for Needy Families Program; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(x)</num>
          <text>Unemployment Insurance;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Residing in an emergency shelter, temporary shelter, permanent supportive housing, or transitional housing; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Utilizing the services of the diaper bank or diaper program, or the diaper bank's or diaper program's partner organizations.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Department" means the Department of Health Care Finance.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Diaper bank" means a nonprofit organization or a fiscally sponsored project of a nonprofit organization that collects or purchases diapers and other hygiene products for infants, children, or adults and regularly distributes diapers over an extended period through 2 or more partner agencies for eventual distribution to individuals free of charge.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Diaper program" means a program within a nonprofit organization or a fiscally sponsored project of a nonprofit organization that collects or purchases diapers for the purpose of regularly distributing the diapers directly to individuals free of charge.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-470" path="§5062" codified:display="Note" app="2022-09-21" eff="2022-07-13">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-470" path="§5062">§ 5062 of Fiscal Year 2023 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2022 (D.C. Act 24-470, July 13, 2022, 69 DCR 008707)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2022-09-21" doc="D.C. Act 24-470" eff="2022-07-13" path="§5062" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2022-09-21" doc="D.C. Law 24-167" eff="2022-09-21" path="V" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2022-09-21" doc="D.C. Law 24-167" eff="2022-09-21" path="§5062" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
