<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-516</num>
  <heading>Assessments.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In addition to and separate from punishment imposed, an assessment of $100 for each violation of the following crimes, an assessment of between $50 and $250 for other serious traffic or misdemeanor offenses, and an assessment of between $100 and $5,000 for each felony offense shall be imposed upon each person convicted of or pleading guilty or nolo contendere to the offense in the Court or any other court in which the offense charged is:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Leaving after colliding, as defined in <cite path="§50-2201.05c">§ 50-2201.05c</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Object falling or flying from vehicle, as defined in <cite path="§50-2201.05d">§ 50-2201.05d</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Driving under the influence (DUI) of alcohol or a drug, as defined in <cite path="§50-2206.11">§ 50-2206.11</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Driving under the influence of alcohol or a drug (commercial vehicle), as defined in <cite path="§50-2206.12">§ 50-2206.12</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Operating a vehicle while impaired, as defined in <cite path="§50-2206.14">§ 50-2206.14</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Operating under the influence of alcohol or a drug (horse-drawn vehicle), as defined in <cite path="§50-2206.16">§ 50-2206.16</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Operating under the influence of alcohol or a drug (watercraft), as defined in <cite path="§50-2206.31">§ 50-2206.31</cite>; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Operating a watercraft while impaired, as defined in <cite path="§50-2206.33">§ 50-2206.33</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The decision of the Court regarding assessments is final.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If an offender is indigent at the time of sentencing and is later employed for salary, receives compensation while on probation or parole, or is incarcerated in a facility of the Department of Corrections or elsewhere and receives wages or compensation therein, the amount of assessments under this section shall be paid from such salary, wages, or other compensation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The probation office of the Court shall monitor collection of assessments levied against defendants released on probation. The Department of Corrections shall monitor collection of assessments levied against incarcerated defendants. The District of Columbia Board of Parole shall consider satisfaction of assessments under this section when determining release of inmates eligible for parole. If an inmate is released on parole prior to satisfaction of an assessment, the District of Columbia Board of Parole shall monitor collection of the balance due.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Assessments under this chapter shall be collected as fines. Failure to pay assessments as ordered by the Court will subject a defendant so ordered to sanctions provided pursuant to <cite path="§16-706">§ 16-706</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-243" type="History" path="§17">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-243, § 17, 44 DCR 1142</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">See note to <cite path="§4-501">§ 4-501</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 3-436.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§4-515">§ 4-515</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-04-06" doc="D.C. Law 24-341" eff="2023-04-06" path="§102|(l)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
