<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-571.01</num>
  <heading>Office of Victim Services and Justice Grants transparency.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Beginning on September 30, 2022, and every 6 months thereafter, the Office of Victim Services and Justice Grants ("OVSJG") shall publish the following information, for the current fiscal year, on its website:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For all grants or sub-grants awarded to or received by OVSJG:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The funding source and amount received;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The date the grant or sub-grant was awarded or received;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The duration of the grant or sub-grant;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>A description of the permissible uses of, or restrictions on, the grant or sub-grant and the source of those uses or restrictions; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>The remaining balance of the grant or sub-grant.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For all grants or subgrants awarded by OVSJG:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The name of the grantee or sub-grantee to whom the grant or sub-grant was awarded;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The funding source and amount awarded;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The date the grant or sub-grant was awarded;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The duration of the grant or sub-grant; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>A description of the permissible uses of, or restrictions on, the grant or sub-grant and the source of those uses or restrictions.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall, when submitting to the Council an annual budget for the District of Columbia government as described in <cite path="§1-204.42">§ 1-204.42</cite>, publish, at a minimum, the following information regarding the proposed budget for OVSJG on a publicly accessible website:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The agency's grantmaking priorities for the proposed budget;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the Victim Services division, anticipated grant funds budgeted for each agency grantmaking priority within the division, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Implementation of the <cite path="4|5|IV">Sexual Assault Victims' Rights Act of 2014</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The housing continuum of care for victims of crime, including emergency shelters, short-term housing, and transitional housing, broken down by whether the funding or housing is tied to specific:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Categories of crime, such as domestic violence, sexual violence, human trafficking, or violent crime; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Vulnerable populations, such as LGBTQ individuals;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Hospital-based violence intervention programs; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Non-residential direct services for victims of crime, broken down by whether the funding is tied to specific:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Categories of crime, such as domestic violence, sexual violence, human trafficking, or violent crime; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Vulnerable populations, such as LGBTQ individuals;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>For the Justice Grants division, anticipated grant funds budgeted for each agency grantmaking priority within the division, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The housing continuum of care, including emergency shelters, short-term housing, and transitional housing, for returning citizens or other justice-involved populations; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Non-residential direct services for returning citizens or other justice-involved populations; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Anticipated grant funds budgeted for all other agency grantmaking priorities.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>No later than 60 days after June 8, 2024, and annually thereafter, OVSJG shall publish information regarding the work of the Victim Services Division, including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The number of victims engaged each month;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The number of victims who accepted service each month;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The services recommended to the victims each month; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A summary of collected feedback from victims and their families on their experiences with victim services and coordination efforts.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-470" path="§3022" codified:display="Note" app="2022-09-21" eff="2022-07-13">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-470" path="§3022">§ 3022 of Fiscal Year 2023 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2022 (D.C. Act 24-470, July 13, 2022, 69 DCR 008707)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2022-09-21" doc="D.C. Act 24-470" eff="2022-07-13" path="§3022" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2022-09-21" doc="D.C. Law 24-167" eff="2022-09-21" path="III" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2022-09-21" doc="D.C. Law 24-167" eff="2022-09-21" path="§3022" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-410" path="§6" codified:display="Note" app="2024-03-11" eff="2024-03-11">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-410" path="§6">§ 6 of Secure DC Omnibus Emergency Amendment Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-410, Mar. 11, 2024, 71 DCR 2693)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-03-11" doc="D.C. Act 25-410" eff="2024-03-11" path="§6" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-490" path="§6" codified:display="Note" app="2024-06-07" eff="2024-06-07">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-490" path="§6">§ 6 of Secure DC Omnibus Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-490, June 7, 2024, 71 DCR 7006)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-06-07" doc="D.C. Act 25-490" eff="2024-06-07" path="§6" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-06-08" doc="D.C. Law 25-175" eff="2024-06-08" path="§8" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
