<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>22-3212</num>
  <heading>Penalties for theft.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Theft in the first degree. – Any person convicted of theft in the first degree shall be fined no more than the amount set forth in <cite path="§22-3571.01">§ 22-3571.01</cite>, or incarcerated for no more than 10 years, or both, if:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The value of the property obtained or used is $1000 or more; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The person commits theft twice or more within a period of 6 months and the aggregate value of property obtained is $1000 or more.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>When a person commits theft twice or more within a period of 6 months pursuant to sub-subparagraph (i) of this subparagraph, the thefts may be aggregated and charged in a single count, in which event they shall constitute a single offense.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A conviction for first degree theft under paragraph (1)(C) of this subsection merges with any other conviction for robbery under <cite path="§22-2801">§ 22-2801</cite>, and malicious destruction of property under <cite path="§22-303">§ 22-303</cite>, arising from the same act or course of conduct.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>For a person found guilty of 2 or more offenses that merge under this subsection, the sentencing court shall either:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Vacate all but one of the offenses prior to sentencing according to the rule of priority in paragraph (4) of this subsection; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Enter judgment and sentence the actor for offenses that merge; provided, that:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Sentences for the offenses run concurrent to one another; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The convictions for all but, at most, one of the offenses shall be vacated after:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(I)</num>
            <text>The time for appeal has expired; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(II)</num>
            <text>The judgment that was appealed has been decided.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>When convictions are vacated under paragraph (3)(A) of this subsection, the conviction that remains shall be the conviction for:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The offense with the highest authorized maximum period of incarceration; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>If 2 or more offenses have the same highest authorized maximum period of incarceration, any offense that the sentencing court deems appropriate.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <heading>Theft in the second degree. —</heading>
    <text>Any person convicted of theft in the second degree shall be fined not more than the amount set forth in <cite path="§22-3571.01">§ 22-3571.01</cite> or imprisoned for not more than 180 days, or both, if the property obtained or used has some value.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A person convicted of theft in the first or second degree who has 2 or more prior convictions for theft, not committed on the same occasion, shall be fined not more than the amount set forth in <cite path="§22-3571.01">§ 22-3571.01</cite> or imprisoned for not more than 15 years and for a mandatory-minimum term of not less than one year, or both. A person sentenced under this subsection shall not be released from prison, granted probation, or granted suspension of sentence, prior to serving the mandatory-minimum.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, a person shall be considered as having 2 or more prior convictions for theft if he or she has been convicted on at least 2 occasions of violations of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Section 22-3211;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A statute in one or more jurisdictions prohibiting theft or larceny; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Conduct that would constitute a violation of section 22-3211 if committed in the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-164" type="History" path="§112">Dec. 1, 1982, D.C. Law 4-164, § 112, 29 DCR 3976</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-151" type="History">Aug. 20, 1994, D.C. Law 10-151, § 113(a), 41 DCR 2608</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-275" type="History">June 3, 1997, D.C. Law 11-275, § 12(b), 44 DCR 1408</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-88" type="History">Dec. 10, 2009, D.C. Law 18-88, § 214(d), 56 DCR 7413</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 205(a), 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite>: Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 205(a) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 214(d) of Omnibus Public Safety and Justice Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-227, October 21, 2009,  56 DCR 8668).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 214(d) of Omnibus Public Safety and Justice Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-181, August 6, 2009,  56 DCR 6903).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 113(a) of the Omnibus Criminal Justice Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-255, June 22, 1994,  41 DCR 4286).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> substituted “not more than the amount set forth in <cite path="§22-3571.01">§ 22-3571.01</cite>” for “not more than $5,000” in (a) and (c), and for “not more than $1,000” in (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-88">D.C. Law 18-88</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “$1,000” for “$250”; in subsec. (b), substituted “if the property obtained or used has some value” for “if the value of the property obtained or used is less than $250”; and added subsecs. (c) and (d).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 22-3812.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-11-23" doc="D.C. Law 21-166" eff="2016-11-23" path="§2|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-410" path="§18|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2024-03-11" eff="2024-03-11">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-410" path="§18|(b)">§ 18(b) of Secure DC Omnibus Emergency Amendment Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-410, Mar. 11, 2024, 71 DCR 2693)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-03-11" doc="D.C. Act 25-410" eff="2024-03-11" path="§18|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-490" path="§18|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2024-06-07" eff="2024-06-07">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-490" path="§18|(b)">§ 18(b) of Secure DC Omnibus Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-490, June 7, 2024, 71 DCR 7006)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-06-07" doc="D.C. Act 25-490" eff="2024-06-07" path="§18|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-06-08" doc="D.C. Law 25-175" eff="2024-06-08" path="§23|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
