<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>22-3603</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on May 22, 2024.*
      </text>
  <heading proof="needed">Enhanced penalty for committing certain dangerous and violent crimes against election workers and officials.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person who commits any offense listed in subsection (b) of this section against an individual whom the person knew or believed to be a Board of Elections member, employee or volunteer, while the member, employee or volunteer is engaged in the performance of his or her duties or on account of the performance of those duties, may be punished by a fine of up to 1 1/2 times the maximum fine otherwise authorized for the offense and may be imprisoned for a term of up to 1 1/2 times the maximum term of imprisonment otherwise authorized for the offense, or both.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The provisions of subsection (a) of this section shall apply to the following offenses: Abduction, arson, aggravated assault, assault with a dangerous weapon, assault with intent to kill, assault with intent to commit any other offense, threats of violence, intimidation, harassment, stalking, burglary, carjacking, armed carjacking, extortion or blackmail accompanied by threats of violence, kidnapping, malicious disfigurement, manslaughter, mayhem, murder, robbery, sexual abuse in the first, second, and third degrees, theft, fraud in the first degree, fraud in the second degree, identity theft, or an attempt or conspiracy to commit any of the foregoing offenses.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-164" type="History" path="§205 [203]" display="false">Dec. 1, 1982, D.C. Law 4-164, § 205</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-164" type="History" path="§205 [203]">Dec. 1, 1982, D.C. Law 4-164, § 205</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-02-22" doc="D.C. Act 25-404" eff="2024-02-22" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-02-22" doc="D.C. Act 25-404" eff="2024-02-22" path="§2" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-404" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2024-02-22" eff="2024-02-22">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-404" path="§2">§ 2 of Election Worker Protection Emergency Amendment Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-404, Feb. 22, 2024, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
