<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>22-4152</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Collection and use of DNA identification information from defendants.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor may collect a DNA sample from each individual who has been charged by information, complaint, or indictment for:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A crime of violence, as that term is defined in <cite path="§23-1331|(4)">§ 23-1331(4)</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A dangerous crime, as that term is defined in <cite path="§23-1331|(3)">§ 23-1331(3)</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The offenses listed in <cite path="§22-4151|(a)|(3)">§ 22-4151(a)(3)</cite> through <cite path="§22-4251|(a)|(7)">(7)</cite>; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Attempt or conspiracy to commit any of the offenses  listed in subparagraphs (A) through (C) of this paragraph.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If an individual appears in court having been charged by information, complaint, or indictment with an offense set forth in subsection (a)(1) of this section without previously having a DNA sample collected, the court may direct the collection of a DNA sample from that individual.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>DNA sample collection under this section may be limited to individuals who are fingerprinted.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Mayor, the Metropolitan Police Department, or the court, as applicable, may authorize, or enter into agreements with, other local, state, or federal governmental agencies or private entities to collect DNA samples under this section.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>An agency or entity may, but need not, collect a DNA sample from an individual if:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Another agency or entity has collected, or will collect, a DNA sample from that individual and has provided, or will provide, the sample for analysis and inclusion of the results in CODIS as provided in subsection (b) of this section; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>CODIS already contains a DNA analysis with respect to that individual.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>DNA sample collection may be repeated if the agency or entity responsible for collection is informed that a sample collected from the individual does not satisfy the requirements for analysis or for entry of the results of the analysis into CODIS.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor or other authorized agency or entity (as applicable) shall furnish an individual's DNA sample collected under this section to the Federal Bureau of Investigation Laboratory, or to another laboratory approved by the FBI, for the purpose of carrying out a DNA analysis on the DNA sample and including the results in CODIS. The requirement to furnish the DNA sample to the FBI Laboratory or to another laboratory approved by the FBI may be waived, with the permission of the FBI, if DNA samples are analyzed by means of Rapid DNA instruments and the results are included in CODIS. DNA samples may not be collected, analyzed, or included in CODIS under this section before a judicial officer has made an initial probable cause finding that the individual committed an offense set forth in subsection (a)(1) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any DNA samples collected and records of DNA analyses generated under this section shall be destroyed and expunged automatically from CODIS if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A criminal action begun against the individual does not result in a conviction of the individual for an offense set forth in subsection (a)(1) of this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The conviction for an offense set forth in subsection (a)(1) of this section is reversed or vacated and no new trial is permitted; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The individual is granted an unconditional pardon.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The authorization of DNA sample collection by this section shall not limit DNA sample collection by any agency pursuant to any other authority.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the terms "DNA sample", "DNA analysis", and "Rapid DNA instruments" shall have the same meaning as provided in 34 U.S.C. § 40703(c).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-52" type="History" path="§2a">Nov. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-52, § 2a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-52" type="History" path="§2a" display="false">Nov. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-52, § 2a</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-410" path="§22" codified:display="Note" app="2024-06-08" eff="2024-03-11">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-410" path="§22|includes|2a">§ 2a of Secure DC Omnibus Emergency Amendment Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-410, Mar. 11, 2024, 71 DCR 2693)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-06-08" doc="D.C. Act 25-410" eff="2024-03-11" path="§22" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-490" path="§22" codified:display="Note" app="2024-06-08" eff="2024-06-07">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-490" path="§22|includes|2a">§ 2a of Secure DC Omnibus Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-490, June 7, 2024, 71 DCR 7006)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-06-08" doc="D.C. Act 25-490" eff="2024-06-07" path="§22" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-06-08" doc="D.C. Law 25-175" eff="2024-06-08" path="§27" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
