<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>22-4505.01</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Off-duty law enforcement officers carrying restrictions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding <cite path="§22-4505">§ 22-4505</cite> or any other law, no off-duty law enforcement officer shall carry any firearm, openly or concealed, in the following locations or under the following circumstances:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A building or office occupied by the government of the District of Columbia, its agencies, or its instrumentalities;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A District government property or park;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any private residential property other than the officer's own residence, if:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The property displays clear and conspicuous signage indicating that firearms are prohibited; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The property owner or person in control of the premises directly communicates, orally or in writing, to the law enforcement officer in advance of entry onto the residential property that the carrying of pistols is prohibited;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Any private property that does not belong to the law enforcement officer and that is not a residence, including private property open to the public, if:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The property is posted with conspicuous signage prohibiting the carrying of a pistol; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The owner or authorized agent personally communicates to the law enforcement officer that the carrying of pistols is prohibited; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>In a church, synagogue, mosque, or other place where people regularly assemble for religious worship and that is not otherwise covered by paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection, if:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The property is posted with conspicuous signage prohibiting the carrying of a pistol; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The owner or authorized agent communicates to the law enforcement officer that carrying a pistol is prohibited.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A law enforcement officer shall be an off-duty law enforcement officer when the officer is not performing an official duty for the governmental agency that authorizes the officer to carry a firearm.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A Metropolitan Police Department officer's authorized service weapon includes the officer's authorized off-duty service weapon.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>This section shall not apply to the carrying of authorized service weapons by:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Law enforcement officers employed by the District, including members of the Metropolitan Police Department; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An officer, agent, or employee of the United States, a State, or political subdivision thereof, who is authorized by law to engage in or supervise the prevention, detection, investigation, or prosecution of any violation of law and who is engaged in the lawful performance of their official duties, including travel to or from any official activity and participation in an authorized honor guard.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 72-1-ch465" path="§5a">July 8, 1932, 47 Stat. 651, ch. 465, § 5a</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-04-21" doc="D.C. Law 24-347" eff="2023-04-21" path="§3|(e)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
