<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>22-404.04</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on October 18, 2023.*
      </text>
  <heading proof="needed">Strangulation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person commits the offense of strangulation if that person knowingly, intentionally, or recklessly restricts the normal circulation of the blood or breathing of another person, either by applying pressure on the throat, neck, or chest of another person, or by blocking the nose or mouth of another person.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except for as provided in subsection (c) of this section, a person convicted of strangulation shall be fined no more than the amount set forth in <cite path="§22-3571.01">§ 22-3571.01</cite>, or incarcerated for no more than 5 years, or both.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A person convicted of strangulation may be fined up to 1½ times the maximum fine otherwise authorized under this section and may be incarcerated for a term of up to 1½ times the maximum term of incarceration otherwise authorized under this section, or both, if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The victim sustained serious bodily injury, as that term is defined in <cite path="§22-3001|(7)">§ 22-3001(7)</cite>, as a result of the offense;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The person was, at the time of the offense, required to stay away from or have no contact with the victim as a condition of their parole or supervised release or pursuant to a court order; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The person was, within 5 years of commission of the strangulation offense, convicted of either an intrafamily offense, as defined in <cite path="§16-1001|(8)">§ 16-1001(8)</cite>, or a similar offense in the law of another jurisdiction.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-404.04" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§22-404.04" codified:display="Note"/>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-404.04" before="heading" history="false" display-template="" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§22-404.04">
    <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on October 18, 2023.*
      </text>
  </codify:insert>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 56-2-ch854" path="§806d" display="false">Mar. 3, 1901, 31 Stat. 1322, ch. 854, § 806d</annotation>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 56-2-ch854" path="§806d">Mar. 3, 1901, 31 Stat. 1322, ch. 854, § 806d</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-07-20" doc="D.C. Act 25-175" eff="2023-07-20" path="§8" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-07-20" doc="D.C. Act 25-175" eff="2023-07-20" path="§8" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-175" path="§8" codified:display="Note" app="2023-07-20" eff="2023-07-20">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-175" path="§8|includes|806d">§ 806d of Prioritizing Public Safety Emergency Amendment Act of 2023 (D.C. Act 25-175, July 20, 2023, 70 DCR 10358)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
