<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>6-1453.02</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on October 20, 2024.*
      </text>
  <heading proof="needed">Report on barriers to net zero energy ready affordable housing development.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No later than April 1, 2025, and every 6 months thereafter, the Department of Buildings ("Department") shall submit to the Council a report detailing its progress toward developing the regulations required by <cite path="§6-1453.01">§ 6-1453.01</cite>. Each report shall include a discussion of major questions that the Department needs to resolve before it can issue the regulations, plans to resolve those questions, and comments on any existing laws that pose significant challenges to successful development and implementation of the regulations. The Department may also include recommended changes to existing laws that would allow substantial affordable housing development and preservation to continue while still securing meaningful, immediate reductions in energy waste, greenhouse gas emissions, and onsite fossil fuel combustion.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In preparing each report required under this section, the Department shall hold at least one public meeting with the Department of Energy and Environment, local climate advocacy organizations, and housing development and preservation professionals with substantial experience delivering high-efficiency projects in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to establish a new cause of action to challenge the validity of any regulations issued pursuant to <cite path="§6-1453.01">§ 6-1453.01</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>This section shall expire upon the effective date of final regulations promulgated pursuant to <cite path="§6-1453.01|(b)|(1)">§ 6-1453.01(b)(1)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-177" type="History" path="§2a">Sep. 21, 2022 D.C. Law 24-177, § 2a</annotation>
    <annotation app="2022-09-21" doc="D.C. Law 24-177" eff="2022-09-21" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-07-22" doc="D.C. Act 25-518" eff="2024-07-22" path="§3" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-07-22" doc="D.C. Act 25-518" eff="2024-07-22" path="§3" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-518" path="§3" codified:display="Note" app="2024-07-22" eff="2024-07-22">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-518" path="§3">§ 3 of Green Housing Coordination Emergency Amendment Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-518, July 22, 2024, 71 DCR 9352)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
