<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>6-219</num>
  <heading>Procurement.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Until the Board promulgates procurement regulations in accordance with this section, the Authority’s existing rules governing procurement shall continue to apply. The Board shall transmit proposed procurement regulations to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the regulations, in whole or in part, by resolution within the 45-day review period, the regulations shall be deemed approved. The Board’s procurement regulations shall include rules and procedures governing public notice of invitations to bid; methods of source selection, including competitive sealed bidding and competitive sealed proposals; small purchase procurements; cost principles; delivery and performance; contract modification; and contract termination.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this subsection shall exempt the Board from compliance with <cite path="§1-204.51">§ 1-204.51</cite>; however, the Board may adopt rules governing procurements involving the expenditure of federal funds that are inconsistent with <cite path="2|3A">Chapter 3A of Title 2</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-105" type="History" path="§20">May 9, 2000, D.C. Law 13-105, § 20, 47 DCR 1325</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) addition of section, see notes following <cite path="§6-201">§ 6-201</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§6-203">§ 6-203</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-114" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2023-05-24" eff="2023-05-24">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-114" path="§2">§ 2 of District of Columbia Housing Authority Procurement Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2023 (D.C. Act 25-114, May 24, 2023, 70 DCR 7942)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-05-24" doc="D.C. Act 25-114" eff="2023-05-24" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 25-40" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2023-08-17" eff="2023-08-17">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-40" path="§2">§ 2 of District of Columbia Housing Authority Procurement Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2023 (D.C. Law 25-40, Aug. 17, 2023, 70 DCR 9040)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-08-17" doc="D.C. Law 25-40" eff="2023-08-17" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-09-06" doc="D.C. Law 25-50" eff="2023-09-06" path="§2012|(b)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-09-06" doc="D.C. Law 25-50" eff="2023-09-06" path="§2012|(b)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-09-06" doc="D.C. Law 25-50" eff="2023-09-06" path="§2012|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-09-06" doc="D.C. Law 25-50" eff="2023-09-06" path="§2012|(c)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
