<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>6-211</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on February 1, 2023. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation affecting this section, click this link: <cite path="§6-211(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on March 22, 2023. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation affecting this section, click this link: <cite path="§6-211(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
  <heading>Additional Board provisions.</heading>
  <para placeholder="Repealed">
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para placeholder="Repealed">
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para placeholder="Repealed">
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>All Commissioners, at time of appointment, shall be residents of the District of Columbia and shall remain residents throughout the term of the appointment.</text>
  </para>
  <para placeholder="Repealed">
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para placeholder="Repealed">
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para placeholder="Repealed">
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Within 60 days after a Commissioner's appointment and on an annual basis thereafter, each Commissioner shall complete training offered by or in connection with HUD covering the following topics:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The role of a public housing agency board;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Ethics for public housing agencies and board members or commissioners;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Background on major housing authority programs, including public housing, Housing Choice Voucher Program, and the rental assistance demonstration;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Fair housing and reasonable accommodations;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Public housing authority budgets, financial oversight, and financial reporting; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Federal procurement requirements.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Within 90 days after a Commissioner's appointment and on an annual basis thereafter, each Commissioner shall complete training offered by or in connection with HUD covering the following topics:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Public housing authority performance monitoring and risk management;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>HUD reporting requirements;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Public housing asset management, development, redevelopment, disposition, and repositioning;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Objectives and requirements of HUD's Moving to Work program; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Resident opportunity, including HUD's Section 3 requirements for economic and employment opportunities.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>In addition to the training required in paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection, each Commissioner shall spend at least 4 hours per quarter in training or educational seminars on corporate governance, public housing law and regulations, federal or local language access guidelines, labor and personnel, real estate and construction, or other subjects related to public housing development, operation, and management, the maximum reimbursable cost of which shall be established by the Board and paid by the Authority.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A Commissioner appointed or re-appointed before October 15, 2022, shall complete training on federal procurement requirements within 30 days after November 3, 2022 the remainder of the trainings required in paragraph (1) of this subsection within 60 days after November 3, 2022, and the trainings required in paragraph (2) of this subsection within 90 days after November 3, 2022.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The Board shall monitor Commissioners' compliance with the training requirements of this subsection and provide a Commissioner a warning notice if the Commissioner is out of compliance with the requirements.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>If a Commissioner has not completed the training requirements within 15 days after the conclusion of the timeline specified in the applicable paragraph in this subsection, he or she shall be suspended from the Board until he or she is in compliance.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Each reference to a "Commissioner" in this subsection shall be deemed to be a reference to a member of the Board.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para placeholder="Repealed">
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para placeholder="Repealed">
    <num>(j)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para placeholder="Repealed">
    <num>(k)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para placeholder="Repealed">
    <num>(l)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para placeholder="Repealed">
    <num>(m)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para placeholder="Repealed">
    <num>(n)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para placeholder="Repealed">
    <num>(o)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para placeholder="Repealed">
    <num>(p)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para placeholder="Repealed">
    <num>(q)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(r)</num>
    <text>No member of the Board may be held personally liable for any action taken in accordance with, and in furtherance of, his or her official duties and responsibilities as set forth in this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(s)</num>
    <text>Each member of the Board referred to in section 11a(a)(1)(A) through (I) shall be entitled to compensation as provided in <cite path="§1-611.08">§ 1-611.08</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(t)</num>
    <text>The Board may, by majority vote, remove any Commissioner for official misconduct, conflict of interest violations, neglect of duty, incompetence, or personal misconduct, but only after the Commissioner shall have been given a copy of the charges and an opportunity to answer those charges in accordance with a procedure established in the by-laws or other rules of the Board. The Chairperson shall suspend a Commissioner pending the Board’s consideration of the charges. If the Chairperson is the Commissioner against whom charges have been made, the Mayor shall suspend the Chairperson pending such consideration.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(u)</num>
    <text>The Board may, by majority vote, require that any member of the Board or Executive Director resolve conflict of interest violations by public disclosure of the conflict of interest and recusal from the decision-making process involving the conflict, divestiture, or any other manner that does not violate local or federal law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(v)</num>
    <text>In addition to those powers conferred elsewhere in this chapter, the Board is charged with the duty to govern all the affairs of the Authority and shall have all powers necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this chapter, including the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To review and approve all contracts for goods or services having a value of more than $250,000;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To make and implement rules, by-laws, and policies and regulations necessary or appropriate for the effective administration of the Authority and the fulfillment of the purposes of this chapter;</text>
    </para>
    <para placeholder="Repealed">
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>To evaluate the Executive Director’s job performance from time to time; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>To perform such other functions as are needed to ensure the provision of quality services to the residents of the Housing Properties.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para placeholder="Repealed">
    <num>(w)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-105" type="History" path="§12">May 9, 2000, D.C. Law 13-105, § 12, 47 DCR 1325</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-337" type="History">Apr. 12, 2005, D.C. Law 15-337, § 2(c), 52 DCR 2278</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-231" type="History">Sept. 12, 2008, D.C. Law 17-231, § 15(b), 55 DCR 6758</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-131" type="History">Mar. 23, 2010, D.C. Law 18-131, § 2, 57 DCR 1193</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-334" type="History">Mar. 31, 2011, D.C. Law 18-334, § 2, 58 DCR 30</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-271" type="History">May 2, 2015, D.C. Law 20-271, § 254(b), 62 DCR 1884</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 20-481" path="§254|(b)">§ 254(b) of the New Columbia Statehood Initiative, Omnibus Boards and Commissions, and Election Transition Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-481, Nov. 18, 2014, 61 DCR 12133, 20 STAT 4405)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 21-7" path="§254|(b)">§ 254(b) of the New Columbia Statehood Initiative, Omnibus Boards and Commissions, and Election Transition Reform Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-7, Feb. 26, 2015,  62 DCR 2646, 21 STAT 807)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) addition of section, see notes following <cite path="§6-201">§ 6-201</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-271">D.C. Law 20-271</cite> substituted “Executive Director” for “Advisory Committee” in (b)(1) and (c); and rewrote (s).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-334">D.C. Law 18-334</cite>, in subsec. (a)(2A), substituted “housing choice voucher program recipient” for “recipient”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-131">D.C. Law 18-131</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “11” for “9” in the lead in language, added pars. (2A) and (5), deleted “; and” from the end of par. (3), and substituted “; and” for a period at the end of par. (4); in subsec. (b), inserted “pursuant to subsection (a)(1) of this section”; in subsec. (m), inserted “nominated pursuant to subsection (a)(1) of this section”; and, in subsec. (l), substituted “Elected” for “Resident”, “a resident” for “an elected”, and “the resident” for “the elected”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-231">D.C. Law 17-231</cite>, in subsec. (q), substituted “spouse or domestic partner” for “spouse”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-337">D.C. Law 15-337</cite>, in subsec. (q), substituted “(including those that are purely advisory, except for Advisory Neighborhood Commissions)” for “(including those that are purely advisory)”; rewrote subsec. (s); and rewrote the first three sentences of subsec. (w) which had read: “The Board shall meet at least once each month. All meetings of the Board shall be conducted in public after publication of notice of the date, time, and location of the meeting, at least one week prior thereto, in the District of Columbia Register. Each meeting shall commence with a period for public comments, which shall not be limited in time, except that the time allowed each individual speaker may be reasonably limited.” Prior to amendment, subsec. (s) read as follows: “(s) Each Commissioner shall be entitled to compensation at the hourly rate of $25 per meeting, not to exceed $3,000 for each board member per year; provided, that each Commissioner shall be entitled to reimbursement of actual travel and other expenses reasonably related to the Commissioner’s attendance at Board meetings and fulfillment of official duties.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§1-523.01">§ 1-523.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-11-13" doc="D.C. Law 24-45" eff="2021-11-13" path="§2162|(a)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-11-13" doc="D.C. Law 24-45" eff="2021-11-13" path="§2162|(a)|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-11-13" doc="D.C. Law 24-45" eff="2021-11-13" path="§2162|(a)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-11-13" doc="D.C. Law 24-45" eff="2021-11-13" path="§2162|(a)|(4)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-11-13" doc="D.C. Law 24-45" eff="2021-11-13" path="§2162|(b)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-11-13" doc="D.C. Law 24-45" eff="2021-11-13" path="§2162|(b)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-11-13" doc="D.C. Law 24-45" eff="2021-11-13" path="§2162|(b)|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-11-13" doc="D.C. Law 24-45" eff="2021-11-13" path="§2162|(c)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-252" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2021-12-22" eff="2021-12-22">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-252" path="§2">§ 2 of District of Columbia Housing Authority Resident Commissioners Election Deadline Extension Emergency Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-252, Dec. 22, 2021, 68 DCR 014067)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-12-22" doc="D.C. Act 24-252" eff="2021-12-22" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 24-101" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2022-03-15" eff="2022-03-15">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-101" path="§2">§ 2 of District of Columbia Housing Authority Resident Commissioners Election Deadline Extension Temporary Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Law 24-101, Mar. 15, 2022, 69 DCR 000597)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2022-03-15" doc="D.C. Law 24-101" eff="2022-03-15" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2022-11-03" doc="D.C. Act 24-629" eff="2022-11-03" path="§2|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2022-11-03" doc="D.C. Act 24-629" eff="2022-11-03" path="§2|(b)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-629" path="§2|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2022-11-03" eff="2022-11-03">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-629" path="§2|(b)">§ 2(b) of Housing Authority Accountability Emergency Amendment Act of 2022 (D.C. Act 24-629, Nov. 3, 2022, 69 DCR 014026)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2022-12-22" doc="D.C. Act 24-702" eff="2022-12-22" path="§2|(d)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2022-12-22" doc="D.C. Act 24-702" eff="2022-12-22" path="§2|(d)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2022-12-22" doc="D.C. Act 24-702" eff="2022-12-22" path="§2|(d)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2022-12-22" doc="D.C. Act 24-702" eff="2022-12-22" path="§2|(d)|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2022-12-22" doc="D.C. Act 24-702" eff="2022-12-22" path="§2|(d)|(4)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2022-12-22" doc="D.C. Act 24-702" eff="2022-12-22" path="§2|(d)|(5)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2022-12-22" doc="D.C. Act 24-702" eff="2022-12-22" path="§2|(d)|(6)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-702" path="§2|(d)" codified:display="Note" app="2022-12-22" eff="2022-12-22">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-702" path="§2|(d)">§ 2(d) of District of Columba Housing Authority Stabilization and Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2022 (D.C. Act 24-702, Dec. 22, 2022, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Act 24-702" path="§4" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2022-12-22" eff="2022-12-22"><cite doc="D.C. Act 24-702" path="§4">Section 4 of D.C. Act 24-702</cite> provided that the amendments made to this section by D.C. Law 24-702 shall apply on the date that the Stabilization and Reform Board assumes authority for the governance of the Authority, as provided in <cite path="§6-210.01|(i)">§ 6-210.01|(i)</cite>.
    </annotation>
    <annotation app="2022-12-22" doc="D.C. Act 24-702" eff="2022-12-22" path="§4" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
