<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>6-210.01</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on January 9, 2024.*
      </text>
  <heading proof="needed">Stabilization and Reform Board.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Authority shall, from and after the date set forth in subsection (i) of this section, be governed by a Stabilization and Reform Board, which shall consist of the following members:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The following 9 voting members, each of whom shall be a resident of the District:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>One member with experience in housing development or operations;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>One member with experience in affordable housing development, operations, or finance;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>One member with knowledge of federal housing law and regulation;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>One member with experience in capital project financing;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>One member who is a resident of a property owned, operated, and managed by the Authority;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>One member with experience as a voucher holder;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>The current Executive Director of the Interagency Council on Homelessness;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>The Director of the District's Office of Budget and Performance Management; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(I)</num>
        <text>One member with experience in government procurement;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Chief Financial Officer, or a designee of the Chief Financial Officer who is an employee of the Office of the Chief Financial Officer, who shall serve as a non-voting member; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The President of the City-Wide Resident Advisory Board, who shall serve as a non-voting member.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection and subsections (c) and (f)(1) of this section, each member of the Stabilization and Reform Board shall be appointed by the Mayor, with the advice and consent of the Council pursuant to section 2(e) of the Confirmation Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-142; D.C. Official Code § 1-523.01(e)).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Director of the District's Office of Budget and Performance Management and the Chief Financial Officer, or the Chief Financial Officer's designee, shall serve as members of the Stabilization and Reform Board by virtue of their incumbency in the position of Director of the District's Office of Budget and Performance Management and Chief Financial Officer or being an employee of the Office of the Chief Financial Officer.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsection (b) of this section, the Mayor may appoint the following individuals to the Stabilization and Reform Board without the advice and consent of the Council pursuant to section 2(e) of the Confirmation Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-142; D.C. Official Code § 1-523.01(e)):</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Raymond A. Skinner, to fill the Board seat described in subsection (a)(1)(A) of this section and to serve as chairperson of the Stabilization and Reform Board;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>James M. Dickerson, to fill the Board seat described in subsection (a)(1)(B) of this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Christopher Murphy, to fill the Board seat described in subsection (a)(1)(C) of this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Melissa Lee, to fill the Board seat described in subsection (a)(1)(D) of this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Denise Blackson, to  fill the Board sear described in subsection (a)(1)(E) of this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Ronnie Harris, to fill the Board seat described in subsection (a)(1)(F) of this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Theresa Silla, to fill the Board seat described in subsection (a)(1)(G) of this section; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Katrina D. Jones, to fill the Board seat described in subsection (a)(1)(I) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The members of the Stabilization and Reform Board referred to in subsection (a)(1)(A) through (I) of this section shall each serve for one term of 2 years or until the Board sunsets; provided, that each such member may continue to serve until a successor board assumes the responsibilities of the Stabilization and Reform Board; provided further, that in the event of a vacancy in the seat of such a member of the Board, the Mayor may appoint a member, pursuant to subsection (b)(1) of this section, to serve the remainder of the unexpired term or until a successor board assumes the responsibilities of the Stabilization and Reform Board.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Upon a vacancy in the position of chairperson of the Stabilization and Reform Board, the Mayor shall designate a chairperson from among the members of the Stabilization and Reform Board referred to in subsection (a)(1)(A) through (I) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Upon a vacancy of any seat of the Stabilization and Reform Board, the Mayor shall nominate a replacement who meets the qualifications of the vacant seat pursuant to subsection (a)(1) of this section; provided, that this shall not apply to the seat established by subsection (a)(1)(A) of this section. If the seat established by subsection (a)(1)(A) of this section becomes vacant, the Council shall appoint a successor.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A Mayoral nomination shall be submitted to the Council pursuant to subsection (b)(1) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Stabilization and Reform Board shall meet at least 10 times per year. All meetings of the Stabilization and Reform Board shall be open to the public, except as may otherwise be authorized by the Open Meetings Act, effective March 31, 2011 (D.C. Law 18-350; D.C. Official Code § 2-571 et seq.).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>All regular meetings of the Board must be publicized through a notice, published in the District of Columbia Register one week prior to the meeting that contains the date, time, and location of the meeting.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Each regular meeting shall provide for a period of public comments, which shall not be limited in time, except that the time allowed for each individual speaker may be reasonably limited.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of taking any official action, a quorum of the Stabilization and Reform Board shall consist of 5 members.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>The Stabilization and Reform Board established by this section shall assume authority from the Board of Commissioners established by section 12, and the Board of Commissioners shall be dissolved, upon the swearing in of at least 5 members of the Stabilization and Reform Board.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(j)</num>
    <text>The Authority shall provide to the Stabilization and Reform Board at least 2 full-time employees who are qualified to provide legal and policy research as requested by members of the Board. Except as otherwise provided by law, a full-time employee provided to the Board pursuant to this subsection shall not share with employees of the Authority information about research performed for a Board member, unless the Board member authorizes the sharing of information.</text>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-210" expire="2023-10-11" codified:display="Note">For temporary (90 days) creation of § 6-210.01, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-232" path="§2|(c)|includes|11a">§ 11a of District of Columbia Housing Authority Stabilization and Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2023 (D.C. Act 25-221, Oct. 11, 2023, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</codify:annotation>
  <codify:annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-210.01" applicability="2023-10-11" delay="50" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§6-210.01">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-232" path="§2|(c)|includes|11a">§ 11a of District of Columbia Housing Authority Stabilization and Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2023 (D.C. Act 25-221, Oct. 11, 2023, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</codify:annotation>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-210.01" before="heading" history="false" display-template="" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§6-210.01">
    <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on January 9, 2024.*
      </text>
  </codify:insert>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-105" type="History" path="§11a" display="false">May 9, 2000, D.C. Law 13-105, § 11a</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-702" path="§2|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2023-10-11" eff="2022-12-22">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-702" path="§2|(c)|includes|11a">§ 11a of District of Columba Housing Authority Stabilization and Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2022 (D.C. Act 24-702, Dec. 22, 2022, 70 DCR 164)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-10-11" doc="D.C. Act 24-702" eff="2022-12-22" path="§2|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 24-329" path="§2|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2023-10-11" eff="2023-03-10">For temporary (225 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-329" path="§2|(c)|includes|11a">§ 11a of District of Columbia Housing Authority Stabilization and Reform Temporary Amendment Act of 2022 (D.C. Law 24-329, Mar. 10, 2023, 70 DCR 1029)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-10-11" doc="D.C. Law 24-329" eff="2023-03-10" path="§2|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-10-11" doc="D.C. Act 25-232" eff="2023-10-11" path="§2|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-10-11" doc="D.C. Act 25-232" eff="2023-10-11" path="§2|(c)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-232" path="§2|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2023-10-11" eff="2023-10-11">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-232" path="§2|(c)|includes|11a">§ 11a of District of Columbia Housing Authority Stabilization and Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2023 (D.C. Act 25-221, Oct. 11, 2023, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
