<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>6-210.03</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by temporary legislation that will expire on October 21, 2023.*
      </text>
  <heading proof="needed">City-Wide Resident Advisory Board.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Authority shall establish and implement a comprehensive training program for members of the City-Wide Resident Advisory Board with the goal of enabling tenant members to participate fully in the oversight of the housing authority's operation and capital planning. The Authority shall develop the training program in consultation with public housing residents and public housing industry professional organizations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The City-Wide Resident Advisory Board shall be provided access to trainings referenced in section 12(h)(1) and (2).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Additionally, the Authority shall provide training on relevant federal and District laws, leadership development, communication, and negotiations.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Authority shall provide a copy of resolutions on the agenda for consideration by the Stabilization and Reform Board to the City-Wide Resident Advisory Board at least 24 hours prior to the scheduled date and time of the Stabilization and Reform Board meeting at which the resolution will be considered.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Authority shall seek and consider the input of the City-Wide Resident Advisory Board when a policy or program change affects residents.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-702" path="§2|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2023-03-10" eff="2022-12-22">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-702" path="§2|(c)|includes|11c">§ 11c of District of Columba Housing Authority Stabilization and Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2022 (D.C. Act 24-702, Dec. 22, 2022, 70 DCR 164)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Act 24-702" eff="2022-12-22" path="§2|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-329" eff="2023-03-10" path="§2|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 24-329" eff="2023-03-10" path="§2|(c)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 24-329" path="§2|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2023-03-10" eff="2023-03-10">For temporary (225 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-329" path="§2|(c)">§ 2(c) of District of Columbia Housing Authority Stabilization and Reform Temporary Amendment Act of 2022 (D.C. Law 24-329, Mar. 10, 2023, 70 DCR 1029)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
