<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-327.56b</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on October 25, 2023.*
      </text>
  <heading proof="needed">Call data collection and posting.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>On a monthly basis, the Office shall collect and publicly post on the Office's website the number of calls eligible to be diverted and the number of calls actually diverted to the:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Department of Behavioral Health Access Help Line;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>District Department of Transportation for motor vehicle collisions that do not result in an injury;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Department of Public Works for parking enforcement; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department Nurse Triage Line.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>On a monthly basis, the Office shall publicly post the following information on the Office's website:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Descriptions of each call-taker and dispatcher error, the cause of the error, and the corrective action taken by the Office;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Number of shifts operated under minimum staffing levels;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Average and maximum call to answer times;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Average and maximum answer to dispatch times;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Number of calls in the queue for over 15 seconds;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Number of calls dropped following a queue time of over 15 seconds; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Number and type of 911 misuse calls.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205" type="History" path="§3207b">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 3207b</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-07-27" doc="D.C. Act 25-198" eff="2023-07-27" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-07-27" doc="D.C. Act 25-198" eff="2023-07-27" path="§2" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-198" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2023-07-27" eff="2023-07-27">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-198" path="§2">§ 2 of Office of Unified Communications Transparency and Accuracy Emergency Amendment Act of 2023 (D.C. Act 25-198, July 27, 2023, 70 DCR 10746)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
