<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-325.441</num>
  <heading>Opioid Abatement Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Opioid Abatement Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by the Mayor in accordance with this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Monies from the following sources shall be deposited into the Fund:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Funds received by the District, regardless of whether such funds are received as a lump sum or series of payments to be made over time, in settlement of D.C. Superior Court cases:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text><em>District of Columbia v. Johnson &amp; Johnson, et al., Case No. 2022-CA-001441-B</em>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text><em>District of Columbia v. McKesson Cop, et al., Case No. 2022-CA-001401-B</em>; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text><em>District of Columbia v. McKinsey &amp; Co., Case No. 2021-CA-00327-B</em>; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Monies otherwise appropriated to, or transferred to, the Fund in accordance with law.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Money deposited into the Fund shall not be obligated or expended until the Council of the District of Columbia passes legislation setting forth the permissible uses of the money in the Fund.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Money deposited into the Fund shall not revert to the unassigned fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of any fiscal year or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds deposited into the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2022-07-13" doc="D.C. Act 24-470" eff="2022-07-13" path="V|B" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2022-07-13" doc="D.C. Act 24-470" eff="2022-07-13" path="ยง5012" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
