<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2887.10</num>
  <heading>Notice to educational institution.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Not later than 72 hours after entering into an agency contract or before the next scheduled athletic event in which the student-athlete may participate, whichever occurs first, the athlete agent shall give notice in a record of the existence of the contract to the athletic director of the educational institution at which the student-athlete is enrolled or at which the athlete agent has reasonable grounds to believe the student-athlete intends to enroll.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Not later than 72 hours after entering into an agency contract or before the next scheduled athletic event in which the student-athlete may participate, whichever occurs first, the student-athlete shall inform the athletic director of the educational institution at which the student-athlete is enrolled that the student-athlete has entered into an agency contract and the name and contact information of the athlete agent.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If an athlete agent enters into an agency contract with a student-athlete and the student-athlete subsequently enrolls at an educational institution, the agent shall notify the athletic director of the institution of the existence of the contract not later than 72 hours after the agent knew or should have known that the student-athlete enrolled in the educational institution.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If an athlete agent has a relationship with a student-athlete before the student-athlete enrolls in an educational institution and receives an athletic scholarship from the institution, the agent shall notify the institution of the relationship not later than 10 days after the enrollment if the agent knows or should have known of the enrollment and:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The relationship was motivated in whole or part by the intention of the agent to recruit or solicit the student-athlete to enter an agency contract in the future; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The agent directly or indirectly recruited or solicited the student-athlete to enter an agency contract before the enrollment.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>An athlete agent shall give notice in a record to the athletic director of any educational institution at which a student-athlete is enrolled before the agent communicates or attempts to communicate with:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The student-athlete or, if the student-athlete is a minor, a parent or guardian of the student-athlete, to influence the student-athlete or parent or guardian of the student-athlete to enter into an agency contract; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Another individual to have that individual influence the student-athlete or, if the student-athlete is a minor, the parent or guardian of the student-athlete, to enter into an agency contract.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>If a communication or attempt to communicate with an athlete agent is initiated by a student-athlete or another individual on behalf of the student-athlete, the agent shall notify, in a record, the athletic director of any educational institution at which the student-athlete is enrolled. The notification must be made not later than 10 days after the communication or attempt.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>An educational institution that becomes aware of a violation of <cite path="47|28|IV|E">this part</cite> by an athlete agent shall notify the following entities of the violation:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any professional league or players association with which the athlete agent is licensed or registered, to the extent the educational institution is aware of such affiliations.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "communicates or attempts to communicate" means contacting or attempting to contact by an in-person meeting, a record, or any other method that conveys or attempts to convey a message.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-107" type="History">Apr. 13, 2002, D.C. Law 14-107, § 3, 49 DCR 1193)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 11 of the Uniform Athlete Agents Act.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-245" eff="2023-02-23" path="§102|(g)|(1)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-245" eff="2023-02-23" path="§102|(g)|(1)|(B)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-245" eff="2023-02-23" path="§102|(g)|(2)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-245" eff="2023-02-23" path="§102|(g)|(2)|(B)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-245" eff="2023-02-23" path="§102|(g)|(2)|(C)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-245" eff="2023-02-23" path="§102|(g)|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-09-06" doc="D.C. Law 25-50" eff="2023-09-06" path="§8002|(g)|(2)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
