<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>47-2887.15</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Civil remedies.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An educational institution or student-athlete may bring an action for damages against an athlete agent if the institution or student-athlete is adversely affected by an act or omission of the athlete agent in violation of <cite path="47|28|IV|E">this part</cite>. An educational institution or student-athlete is adversely affected by an act or omission of the agent only if, because of the act or omission, the institution or an individual who was a student-athlete at the time of the act or omission and enrolled in the institution:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Is suspended or disqualified from participation in an interscholastic or intercollegiate sports event by or under the rules of a State or national federation or association that promotes or regulates interscholastic or intercollegiate sports; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Suffers financial damage.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A plaintiff that prevails in an action under this section may recover actual damages, costs, and reasonable attorney's fees.  An athlete agent found liable under this section forfeits any right of payment for anything of benefit or value provided to the student-athlete and shall refund any consideration paid to the agent by or on behalf of the student-athlete.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-107" type="History">Apr. 13, 2002, D.C. Law 14-107, § 3, 49 DCR 1193)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 16 of the Uniform Athlete Agents Act.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-245" eff="2023-02-23" path="§102|(j)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
