<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2887.09</num>
  <heading>Required form of agency contract.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An agency contract must be in a record signed by the parties.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An agency contract must state or contain:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The amount and method of calculating the consideration to be paid by the student-athlete for services to be provided by the athlete agent under the contract and any other consideration the athlete agent has received or will receive from any other source for entering into the contract or for providing the services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(1A)</num>
      <text>A statement that the athlete agent is registered as an athlete agent in the District and a list of any other States in which the person is registered as an athlete agent;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The name of any person not listed in the application for registration or renewal of registration who will be compensated because the student-athlete signed the agency contract;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A description of any expenses that the student-athlete agrees to reimburse;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A description of the services to be provided to the student-athlete;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The duration of the contract; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The date of execution.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (f) of this section, an agency contract must contain a conspicuous notice in boldface type and in substantially the following form:</text>
    <text>"WARNING TO STUDENT-ATHLETE.</text>
    <text>"IF YOU SIGN THIS CONTRACT:</text>
    <text>"(1) YOU MAY LOSE YOUR ELIGIBILITY TO COMPETE AS A STUDENT- ATHLETE IN YOUR SPORT;</text>
    <text>"(2) IF YOU HAVE AN ATHLETIC DIRECTOR, WITHIN 72 HOURS AFTER SIGNING THIS CONTRACT OR BEFORE THE NEXT SCHEDULED ATHLETIC EVENT IN WHICH YOU PARTICIPATE, WHICHEVER OCCURS FIRST, BOTH YOU AND YOUR ATHLETE AGENT MUST NOTIFY YOUR ATHLETIC DIRECTOR THAT YOU HAVE ENTERED INTO THIS CONTRACT AND PROVIDE THE NAME AND CONTACT INFORMATION OF THE ATHLETE AGENT; AND</text>
    <text>"(3) YOU MAY CANCEL THIS CONTRACT WITHIN 14 DAYS AFTER SIGNING IT.  CANCELLATION OF THIS CONTRACT MAY NOT REINSTATE YOUR ELIGIBILITY AS A STUDENT-ATHLETE IN YOUR SPORT."</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c-1)</num>
    <text>An agency contract must be accompanied by a separate record signed by the student-athlete or, if the student-athlete is a minor, the parent or guardian of the student-athlete, acknowledging that signing the contract may result in the loss of the student-athlete's eligibility to participate in the student-athlete's sport.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A student-athlete or, if the student-athlete is a minor, the parent or guardian of the student-athlete may void an agency contract that does not conform to this section.  If the contract is voided, any consideration received from the athlete agent under the contract to induce entering into the contract is not required to be returned.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>At the time an agency contract is executed, the athlete agent shall give the student-athlete or, if the student-athlete is a minor, the parent or guardian of the student-athlete a copy in a record of the contract and the separate acknowledgement required by subsection (c-1) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>If a student-athlete is a minor, an agency contract must be signed by the parent or guardian of the minor and the notice required by subsection (c) of this section must be revised  accordingly.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-107" type="History">Apr. 13, 2002, D.C. Law 14-107, § 3, 49 DCR 1193)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 10 of the Uniform Athlete Agents Act.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-245" eff="2023-02-23" path="§102|(f)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-245" eff="2023-02-23" path="§102|(f)|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-245" eff="2023-02-23" path="§102|(f)|(4)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-245" eff="2023-02-23" path="§102|(f)|(5)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-245" eff="2023-02-23" path="§102|(f)|(6)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-245" eff="2023-02-23" path="§102|(a)|(2)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-245" eff="2023-02-23" path="§102|(f)|(7)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
