<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>ยง</prefix>
  <num>47-4675</num>
  <heading>DC Habitat 900 55th Street N.E. and 2327 through 2341 Skyland Terrace S.E.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The real property located at 900 55th Street, N.E., designated for tax purposes as Square 5204, Lot 0022, and 2327 through 2341 Skyland Terrace S.E., designated for tax purposes as Square 5740, Lots 341, 350, 351, 352, 353, 354, 355, and 356 (collectively "Property") shall be exempt from the tax imposed by Chapter 8 of this title for the period beginning January 1, 2018, and ending June 31, 2025 ("exemption period") so long as the Property is owned by Habitat for Humanity of Washington D.C. ("DC Habitat") and used to produce 25 homes for sale that are affordable to households earning no more than 60% of the area median income (adjusted for household size), as determined by the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In each year of the exemption period, the Mayor shall certify to the Office of Tax Revenue the Property's eligibility for the exemption provided pursuant to subsection (a) of this section.  The Mayor's certification shall include:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The Property's owner and the use of the Property;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The amount of the tax exemption given to the owner;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A description of the eligible Property by street address, square, and lot; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Any other information that the Mayor considers necessary or appropriate.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If at any time the Mayor determines that the owner has becomes ineligible for the exemption provided pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, the Mayor shall notify the Office of Tax and Revenue and shall specify the date that the Property became ineligible.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2022-09-09" doc="D.C. Law 24-165" eff="2022-09-09" path="ยง2|(b)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-09-06" doc="D.C. Law 25-50" eff="2023-09-06" path="ยง8002|(g)|(4)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
