<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-1621</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Definitions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>In <cite path="42|16A">this chapter</cite>:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Amendment" means a document that removes an unlawful restriction.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Document" means a record recorded or eligible to be recorded in land records.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Governing instrument" means a document recorded in land records that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Establishes a governing body responsible for management of common areas or facilities used by more than one owner of a property interest affected by the document; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Requires contribution, enforceable by a lien on a separate property interest, of a share of taxes, insurance premiums, maintenance, or improvement of, or services or other expenses for the common benefit of, the real property described in the document.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Index" means a system that enables a search for a document in land records.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Land records" means documents and indexes maintained by a recorder.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"Owner" means a person that has a fee interest in real property.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>"Person" means an individual, estate, business or nonprofit entity, government or governmental subdivision, agency, or instrumentality, or other legal entity.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>"Record" when used as a noun means information:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Inscribed on a tangible medium; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Stored in an electronic or other medium and retrievable in perceivable form.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>"Recorder" means the District of Columbia Recorder of Deeds.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>"Remove" means to eliminate any apparent or purportedly continuing effect on title to real property.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>"Unlawful restriction" means a prohibition, restriction, covenant, or condition in a document that purports to interfere with or restrict the transfer, use, or occupancy of real property:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>On the basis of race, color, religion, national origin, sex, familial status, disability, or other personal characteristics; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>In violation of other law of the District or federal law.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-476" path="§102" codified:display="Note" app="2024-08-14" eff="2024-05-29">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-476" path="§102">§ 102 of Unlawful Restrictions in Land Records Emergency Amendment Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-476, May 29, 2024, 71 DCR 6682)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-08-14" doc="D.C. Act 25-476" eff="2024-05-29" path="§102" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-08-14" doc="D.C. Law 25-201" eff="2024-08-14" path="I" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-08-14" doc="D.C. Law 25-201" eff="2024-08-14" path="§102" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
