<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-2081</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of <cite path="42|20C">this chapter</cite>, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>"ADU" means affordable dwelling unit, which is a for-sale or for-rent housing unit that is locally restricted, but not federally restricted, for occupancy to a household with an income that falls within a certain range and that is generally produced in exchange for zoning relief, tax incentives, public financing, the right to purchase or lease District-owned land, or other relief, as described in Mayor's Order 2009-112, issued June 18, 2009 (56 DCR 6859).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>"CA" means the River East at Grandview Condominium Association.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>"DHCD" means the District of Columbia Department of Housing and Community Development.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>"HPAP" means Home Purchase Assistance Program.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>"HUD" means the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>"Inclusionary Development" shall have the same meaning as provided in <cite path="§6-1041.01|(2)">§ 6-1041.01(2)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>"Inclusionary unit" shall have the same meaning as provided in <cite path="§6-1041.01|(3)">§ 6-1041.01(3)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>"IZ" means the Inclusionary Zoning Program.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>"NACA" means the Neighborhood Assistance Corporation of America and its subsidiaries and affiliates, including the Neighborhood Stabilization Corporation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(j)</num>
    <text>"OCFO" means the Office of the Chief Financial Officer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(k)</num>
    <text>"Property" means the River East at Grandview Condominiums located at 1262 Talbert Street, SE, Washington, DC, 20020, known for tax and assessment purposes as Lots 2047 through 2092 in Square 5807, which may also be known as River East at Grandview, Grandview Estate, Grandview Estates, Grandview Estates II, Gardenview, River East, RiverEast, River East at Anacostia, River East at Anacostia Metro Station, River East at Grandview, and Talbert Street.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(l)</num>
    <text>"Property Owner" means an individual who owns one of the 46 condominium units at the Property.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Law 25-217" eff="2024-09-18" path="II|N" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Law 25-217" eff="2024-09-18" path="§2132" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
