<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-2805</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on October 20, 2024.*
      </text>
  <heading proof="needed">Net zero energy requirements for subsidized projects.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Beginning no later than October 1, 2025, any request for housing proposals involving the Fund shall include a requirement that proposals for new construction of 50,000 square feet or more receiving Fund support must satisfy EGCC element 5.4, "Achieving Zero Energy," or an equivalent standard as determined by the Department in consultation with the Department of Buildings.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Department may accept proposals that satisfy EGCC element 5.2b, "Moving to Zero Energy: Near Zero Certification," or an equivalent standard as determined by the Department in consultation with the Department of Buildings, if the Director of the Department issues a written finding that this lesser standard is necessary to ensure affordable housing development in the immediate term and includes the basis for this finding.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Beginning no later than October 1, 2025, any request for housing proposals involving the Fund shall include a requirement that proposals for new construction of 50,000 square feet or more receiving Fund support must satisfy EGCC element 5.5b, "Moving to Zero Carbon: All Electric," or an equivalent standard as determined by the Department in consultation with the Department of Buildings.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the applicability of any other environmental standards, including <cite path="6|14A">Chapter 14A of Title 6</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>This section shall expire upon the effective date of final regulations promulgated pursuant to <cite path="§6-1453.01|(b)|(1)">§ 6-1453.01(b)(1)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "EGCC" means the 2020 Enterprise Green Communities Criteria issued by Enterprise Community Partners.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-202" type="History" path="§6">Mar. 16, 1989, D.C. Law 7-202, § 6</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-07-22" doc="D.C. Act 25-518" eff="2024-07-22" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-07-22" doc="D.C. Act 25-518" eff="2024-07-22" path="§2" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-518" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2024-07-22" eff="2024-07-22">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-518" path="§2">§ 2 of Green Housing Coordination Emergency Amendment Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-518, July 22, 2024, 71 DCR 9352)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
