<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-2082</num>
  <heading proof="needed">DHCD grant authority.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding <cite path="1|3|XII-A|B">part B of subchapter XII-A of Chapter 3 of Title 1</cite>, or its implementing rules under Chapter 50 of Title 1 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (1 DCMR ยง 5000 <em>et seq.</em>), DHCD is authorized to enter into a grant agreement with NACA to provide financial relief for Property Owners seeking to obtain permanent housing.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The grant agreement may include that NACA:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Provide housing counseling services to Property Owners, including assessing Property Owners' permanent housing options and working with Property Owners to meet NACA's mortgage eligibility criteria;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Provide recommendations to the Mayor about the financial need for gap financing based on the assessments of the Property Owners;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Alongside the Mayor, seek relief for Property Owners' existing mortgages on the Property;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Provide affordable mortgage options to eligible Property Owners;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Waive any requirements against a Property Owner having an existing mortgage; provided, that the existing mortgage is on the Property; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Not use credit score as the deciding factor for approving a Property Owner's mortgage.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Law 25-217" eff="2024-09-18" path="II|N" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Law 25-217" eff="2024-09-18" path="ยง2133" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
