<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>ยง</prefix>
  <num>28:12-104</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Rights in controllable account, controllable electronic record, and controllable payment intangible.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>This section applies to the acquisition and purchase of rights in a controllable account or controllable payment intangible, including the rights and benefits under subsections (c), (d), (e), (g), and (h) of this section, of a purchaser and qualifying purchaser, in the same manner this section applies to a controllable electronic record.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>To determine whether a purchaser of a controllable account or a controllable payment intangible is a qualifying purchaser, the purchaser obtains control of the account or payment intangible if it obtains control of the controllable electronic record that evidences the account or payment intangible.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in this section, law other than <cite path="28|I|12">this article</cite> determines whether a person acquires a right in a controllable electronic record and the right the person acquires.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A purchaser of a controllable electronic record acquires all rights in the controllable electronic record that the transferor had or had power to transfer, except that a purchaser of a limited interest in a controllable electronic record acquires rights only to the extent of the interest purchased.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A qualifying purchaser acquires its rights in the controllable electronic record free of a claim of a property right in the controllable electronic record.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsections (a) and (e) of this section for a controllable account and a controllable payment intangible or law other than <cite path="28|I|12">this article</cite>, a qualifying purchaser takes a right to payment, right to performance, or other interest in property evidenced by the controllable electronic record subject to a claim of a property right in the right to payment, right to performance, or other interest in property.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>An action may not be asserted against a qualifying purchaser based on both a purchase by the qualifying purchaser of a controllable electronic record and a claim of a property right in another controllable electronic record, whether the action is framed in conversion, replevin, constructive trust, equitable lien, or other theory.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>Filing of a financing statement under <cite path="28|I|9">Article 9</cite> is not notice of a claim of a property right in a controllable electronic record.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2024-04-20" doc="D.C. Law 25-158" eff="2024-04-20" path="ยง2|(k)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-04-20" doc="D.C. Law 25-158" eff="2024-04-20" path="ยง2|(k)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
