<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>28:2-102</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Scope; certain security and other transactions excluded from this article.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Unless the context otherwise requires, and except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, <cite path="28|I|2">this article</cite> applies to transactions in goods and, in the case of a hybrid transaction, it applies to the extent provided in subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In a hybrid transaction:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If the sale-of-goods aspects do not predominate, only the provisions of <cite path="28|I|2">this article</cite> that relate primarily to the sale-of-goods aspects of the transaction apply, and the provisions that relate primarily to the transaction as a whole do not apply.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the sale-of-goods aspects predominate, <cite path="28|I|2">this article</cite> applies to the transaction but does not preclude application in appropriate circumstances of other law to aspects of the transaction which do not relate to the sale of goods.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text><cite path="28|I|2">This article</cite> does not:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Apply to a transaction that, even though in the form of an unconditional contract to sell or present sale, operates only to create a security interest; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Impair or repeal a statute regulating sales to consumers, farmers, or other specified classes of buyers.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 639, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:2-102.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:2-102.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-04-20" doc="D.C. Law 25-158" eff="2024-04-20" path="§2|(c)|(1)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
