<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>5-1109</num>
  <heading>Referral of complaint to the United States Attorney.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>When, in the determination of the Executive Director, there is reason to believe that the misconduct alleged in a complaint or disclosed by an investigation of the complaint may be criminal in nature, the Executive Director shall refer the matter to the United States Attorney for the District of Columbia for possible criminal prosecution. The referral shall be accompanied by a copy of all of the Office’s files relevant to the matter being referred.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Executive Director shall give written notification of such referral to the Police Chief, the complainant, and the subject officer or officers. The receipt of notification by the Police Chief that a matter has been referred to the United States Attorney for the District of Columbia shall not constitute knowledge or cause to know of acts, occurrences, or allegations contained in such referral for purposes of <cite path="§1-616.01">§ 1-616.01</cite> [repealed].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Executive Director shall maintain a record of each referral, and ascertain and record the disposition of each matter referred to the United States Attorney.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If the United States Attorney declines in writing to prosecute, the Office shall resume its processing of the complaint, and thereafter the Executive Director may dismiss the complaint in accordance with §§ <cite path="§5-1107">5-1107</cite> and <cite path="§5-1108">5-1108</cite>, conciliate the complaint, refer the complaint to mediation, or refer the complaint for investigation, as appropriate.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-208" type="History" path="§10">Mar. 26, 1999, D.C. Law 12-208, § 10, 45 DCR 8107</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 4-919.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-04-21" doc="D.C. Law 24-345" eff="2023-04-21" path="§301|(a)|(1)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="notfunded" doc="D.C. Law 24-345" eff="2023-04-21" path="§105|(h)" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 24-345" path="§105|(h)" codified:display="Note" app="2023-04-21" eff="2023-04-21">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-345" path="">D.C. Law 24-345</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-345" path="§301">§ 301 of D.C. Law 24-345</cite> provided that the change made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-345" path="§105|(h)">§ 105(h) of D.C. Law 24-345</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-04-21" doc="D.C. Law 24-345" eff="2023-04-21" path="§105|(h)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-09-06" doc="D.C. Law 25-50" eff="2023-09-06" path="§7097" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-50" path="§7097" type="Applicability" history="false" display-template="" app="2023-09-06" eff="2023-09-06"><cite doc="D.C.Law 25-50" path="§7097">Section 7097 of D.C. Law 25-50</cite> amended <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-345" path="§301|(a)|(1)">section 301(a)(1) of D.C. Law 24-345</cite> retaining the applicability provision impacting this section.  Therefore the amendment of this section by section 105(h) of Law 24-345 still has not been implemented.
        </annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
